<?xml version="1.0"?>
<gameList>
	<game>
		<path>./1943mii.zip</path>
		<name>1943: The Battle of Midway Mark II</name>
		<desc>Unofficial US version of 1943 Kai, which is a Japanese only release that introduced some modifications to sprites and game play to the original 1943. Probably a hack where airplane sprites are from 1943 Kai but backgrounds are from the original 1943.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/1943mii-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19870601T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Capcom</developer>
		<publisher>Unknown</publisher>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
		<players>2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./aliensyn.zip</path>
		<name>Alien Syndrome</name>
		<desc>Two players control two soldiers named Ricky and Mary, who must fight their way through large eight-way scrolling levels rescuing their comrades who are being held by aliens. After they have rescued a certain number of hostages the exit opens and they can pass through it in order to fight the end-of-level guardian. If this monstrosity is defeated, they move onto the next stage. As well as two player simultaneous gameplay, Alien Syndrome features pick-ups which assist the player including better weapons and maps of the current level.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/aliensyn-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19860101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Sega</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<genre>Action, Shooter</genre>
		<players>2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./robokid.zip</path>
		<name>Atomic Robo-Kid</name>
		<desc>As the half-human half-cyborg flying machine of the title, you are faced with 28 levels to clear of enemies. The gameplay is horizontally scrolling. Your unit is able to fly and then hold at a certain level in space. Defeated enemies often release gems, which can be collected towards power-ups. These include more powerful or multi-directional firing.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/robokid-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19880101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>UPL Co., Ltd</developer>
		<publisher>Activision</publisher>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./bionicc.zip</path>
		<name>Bionic Commando</name>
		<desc>The original arcade game was advertised in the United States as a sequel to Commando, going as far to refer to the game's main character as Super Joe (the protagonist of Commando) in the promotional brochure, who was originally an unnamed member of a "special commando unit" in the Japanese and World versions.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/bionicc-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Capcom</developer>
		<publisher>Capcom</publisher>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
		<players>2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./eswat.zip</path>
		<name>E-SWAT: Cyber Police</name>
		<desc>Players control Duke Oda, a member of the Cyber Police force in the city of Liberty who tries to clear the streets of crime, terminate the most wanted criminals and put them behind bars. There are 15 stages to complete, which takes the player through Liberty streets, car yards, stadiums, restaurants, the CBD, and boat docks. There are bosses on some stages. During each stage, the player picks up ammunition with varying amounts. For example, on some levels, ammo may be worth 10 bullets, while in others, there may be 60 bullets.

Bosses attack in several ways. Note that the bosses are not just people. The player also battles an ape, a tiger, a monster truck in "Eagles Stadium", and cyborgs. Once these first three bosses are defeated, the player's rank rises to captain, followed by assistant chief, and finally to chief.

Once the chief rank has been achieved, the player is given a cyber suit, which is described by the game as a "long-range supersonic powered suit" which contains two Turbo-Booster Thrusters, and provides extra ammunition and protection. This suit is used for the rest of the game. At this point, the player will have to arrest criminal masterminds.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/eswat-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19890323T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Sega</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<genre>Fighting</genre>
		<players>2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./eightman.zip</path>
		<name>EightMan</name>
		<desc>Murdered by criminals, Detective Yokoda's body is retrieved by Professor Tani and taken to his laboratory. There, Tani performs an experiment that has failed seven times; Yokoda is the latest subject to have his life force transferred into an android body. For the first time, the experiment succeeds. Yokoda is reborn as the armor-skinned android 8 Man, able to dash at impossible speeds, as well as shape-shift into other people. He shifts himself into Yokoda, this time christening himself as "Hachiro Azuma". He keeps this identity a secret, known only to Tani and his police boss Chief Tanaka. Even his girlfriend Sachiko and friend Ichiro do not know he is an android. As 8-Man, Hachiro fights crime (even bringing his murderers to justice). He smoked "energy" cigarettes, to rejuvenate his powers, that he carried in a cigarette case on his belt.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/eightman-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19911101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>SNK</developer>
		<publisher>SNK</publisher>
		<genre>Action, Platform</genre>
		<players>2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./mslug3.zip</path>
		<name>Metal Slug 3</name>
		<desc>The rebellion orchestrated by General Morden to bring about a new global regime is now ancient history, and order and peace has begun to return to the world. Morden, brought back into power, was attempting another coup d'état, but government forces got wind of the plot beforehand and pre-empted the impending assault.
Instrumental in squashing Morden's rebel forces, Marco and Tarma of the Peregrine Falcon Strike Force are ordered to lead the team after their earlier requests for resignation were denied. Although General Morden has been written off as "missing" by his followers, they have hidden themselves throughout the world, and Marco and Tarma's abilities and experience are seen as a necessity to destroy remaining rebel strongholds, one by one. Throughout the furious fighting against the holdouts, Marco and Tarma cannot help but suspect Morden's involvement in this new evil plan for world domination.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/mslug3-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>20000601T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>SNK</developer>
		<publisher>SNK</publisher>
		<genre>Action, Adventure, Shooter</genre>
		<players>2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./mslug4.zip</path>
		<name>Metal Slug 4</name>
		<desc>One year after the events of Metal Slug 3, the world is trembling under the new threat of a mysterious but deadly cyber virus that threatens to attack and destroy any nation's military computer system. With Tarma and Eri unable to help due to their own assignments in the matter, Marco and Fio are called in to investigate the situation and are joined by two newcomers, Nadia and Trevor. In their investigation, the group discovers that a terrorist organization known as Amadeus is behind the nefarious plot and that they head into battle against Amadeus' forces, hoping to destroy the cyber virus before it gets the chance to wipe out the entire world's military computer system</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/mslug4-image.png</image>
		<releasedate>20020719T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Mega Enterprise</developer>
		<publisher>MEGA Enterprise Co., Ltd.</publisher>
		<genre>Action, Adventure, Shooter</genre>
		<players>2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./mslug5.zip</path>
		<name>Metal Slug 5</name>
		<desc>A special disc that contains deep and intricate secrets about the Metal Slug project is stolen by a mysterious group called the Ptolemaic Army, whose specialty lies from within archaeological excavation and espionage. Marco and Tarma of the Peregrine Falcon Strike Force follow in hot pursuit against the group and in the process are joined by Eri and Fio of SPARROWS. Together once more, the quartet investigate the shrouded objective of the Ptolemaic Army.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/mslug5-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>20031101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Noise Factory</developer>
		<publisher>SNK</publisher>
		<genre>Action, Adventure, Shooter</genre>
		<players>2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./mslug6.zip</path>
		<name>Metal Slug 6</name>
		<desc>Metal Slug 6 returns to the Rebel-Martian alliance featured in Metal Slugs 2, X, and 3, but on a much broader scale. Rather than repeating the previous games' events of the Martians breaking the alliance and the Rebels assisting the player in turn, the player now teams up with the Rebels and Martians to combat an even greater threat.

Metal Slug 6 introduces a new play mechanic dubbed the 'Weapon Stock System'. Two gun power-ups can now be carried at the same time. Players can switch between the two weapons, or simply put them both away in favor of the default weapon. When obtaining a new weapon power-up, it will automatically occupy the inactive slot, or, if both are holstered, replace the less recent weapon of the two.
The score is now multiplied by powers of 2. The faster the speed at which enemies are killed, the higher the power, as a meter at the bottom of the screen shows. When it says "Max" enemies and destructible objects will drop coins for an extra high score.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/mslug6-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>20060224T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>SNK</developer>
		<publisher>SNK</publisher>
		<genre>Action, Adventure, Shooter</genre>
		<players>2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./mpatrol.zip</path>
		<name>Moon Patrol</name>
		<desc>Moon Patrol is an arcade game originally released in 1982 by Irem and later licensed for release in North America by Williams (Midway). It is a side-scrolling shooter that puts players at the controls of a six-wheeled moon rover that can jump and shoot. The goal is to move through the entire course as quickly as possible while shooting enemies for additional points. Cannons are mounted on the front and top of the vehicle, and both fire simultaneously when the fire button is pressed. Rocks, mines, and pits in the course prevent you from just holding to the right for maximum speed. Rocks and mines can be shot, but pits must be jumped. Some enemies fire shots that create new pits in the course, forcing players to react quickly.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/mpatrol-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19820101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Irem Corp.</developer>
		<publisher>Irem Corp.</publisher>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
		<players>2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./nam1975.zip</path>
		<name>NAM-1975</name>
		<desc>"The roar of the helicopters overhead snaps us back into reality. We will never forget the nightmare of that summer..."

The game is set in a very fictional account of the final months of the Vietnam War. The story begins with the two soldiers, Silver (P1) and Brown (P2), entering the war to rescue Dr. R. Muckly, an ex-scientist of the American Army, who has been kidnapped by Northside Terrorists. Nancy Muckly, Dr. Muckly's daughter has also been kidnapped and is presumed imprisoned in the NAM interior.

However, as the game progresses, the armies learn that Dr. R. Muckly is a madman who is building a gigantic laser cannon to take over the world himself (the final boss battle was infamous for disallowing continues ). Despite the intense firepower of the laser cannon, the troops defeat Dr. Muckly and save the world, though the war continues in Vietnam.

There are many references to many famous Vietnam War films in the game, such as Apocalypse Now and Full Metal Jacket: the attract sequence showing one of the characters firing off an M60 machine gun is clearly ported from the shot of Animal Mother firing on the VC sniper in the latter film.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/nam1975-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19910701T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>SNK</developer>
		<publisher>SNK</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./paperboy.zip</path>
		<name>Paperboy</name>
		<desc>Paperboy is a 1985 arcade game developed and published by Atari Games. The player takes the role of a paperboy who delivers a fictional newspaper called "The Daily Sun" along a suburban street on his bicycle. The game was ported to a wide range of video game consoles and personal computers.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/paperboy-image.png</image>
		<releasedate>19840101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Atari Games</developer>
		<publisher>Atari Games</publisher>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
		<players>2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./pulstar.zip</path>
		<name>Pulstar</name>
		<desc>In the year 2248, the first recorded sign of extraterrestrial life was discovered coming from Mars. The signal emanated from the planet and from it an object travelled through space at light speed out of the Solar System. Earth scientists read the signal, but not knowing the nature of it, warned the world's defenses in case aliens traced the signal and followed it to Earth with the intent to destroy.

Eight years later, aliens followed the signal to the Solar System and began attacking the human space craft awaiting them along Neptune’s orbit. The battle between the humans and aliens spread throughout the Solar System; within two years of combat Neptune was disintegrated, Jupiter was turned into a star and more than half of Earth's continents sank from rising ocean levels and the planet's changing axis as a result. Kaoru Yamazaki, lone fighter pilot of the Dino246, is one of the few survivors left of the Pulstar attack force founded to save the Solar System from the alien invaders; it is through her that mankind may have a chance to survive the alien menace.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/pulstar-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19950929T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Aicom</developer>
		<publisher>SNK</publisher>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
		<players>2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./pbobble.zip</path>
		<name>Puzzle Bobble</name>
		<desc>Puzzle Bobble  is a real-time puzzle game in which the player controls a device called "pointer" at the bottom of the screen, aiming and releasing randomly colored bubbles upwards. Depending on the aiming, the bubbles may float up directly or bounce off the walls, changing their trajectory. The goal is to aim the bubbles in such a way that they will touch identically colored ones. When such bubbles form a group of three or more, they pop and disappear from the screen.

If the ceiling of the area is covered by too many bubbles, it will gradually descend; the game is over when it nearly reaches the player-controlled pointer. Should the player fail to release the bubbles within a specific time limit, they will be released automatically, unaffected by the pointer's aiming.

A two-player mode is included as well. Each player competes on an area occupying half of the screen, dealing with identically generated bubbles. Whenever a player successfully disposes of a bubble group, a part of it is transferred onto the opponent's part of the screen.

The game features the two dinosaur protagonists (Bob and Bub) as well as other characters from Bubble Bobble, even though the two games have distinctly different gameplay.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/pbobble-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19940601T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Taito Corporation</developer>
		<publisher>Taito Corporation</publisher>
		<genre>Puzzle</genre>
		<players>2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./pbobble2.zip</path>
		<name>Puzzle Bobble 2</name>
		<desc>Bub and Bob are back! Like in Tetris in reverse, you shoot bubbles at an array of different-colored bubbles stuck in an ever descending ceiling, attempting to match them up three by three to make them disappear.

This edition contains both puzzle challenges, multiplayer and normal progressive stages.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/pbobble2-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19950701T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Taito Corporation</developer>
		<publisher>Taito Corporation</publisher>
		<genre>Puzzle</genre>
		<players>2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./pbobble3.zip</path>
		<name>Puzzle Bobble 3</name>
		<desc>Puzzle Bobble 3 (also known as Bust-A-Move 3) is the second sequel to Puzzle Bobble. It was released into arcades in September 1996 and later ported to the Sega Saturn, Sony PlayStation, Game Boy, Nintendo 64 and Microsoft Windows. It would be the final appearance of Puzzle Bobble on the Sega Saturn. Like its predecessors, the player is tasked with shooting balls at groups of balls, creating groups of 3 or more, which are then removed from play. A European remake is entitled Bust-a-Move 3 DX. released in America as Bust-a-Move '99.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/pbobble3-image.png</image>
		<releasedate>19960901T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Taito Corporation</developer>
		<publisher>Taito Corporation</publisher>
		<genre>Puzzle</genre>
		<players>2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./pbobble4.zip</path>
		<name>Puzzle Bobble 4</name>
		<desc>Puzzle Bobble 4 (also known as Bust-a-Move 4 in North America and Europe) is the third sequel to the video game Puzzle Bobble and is the final appearance of the series on the Arcade, PlayStation and Dreamcast. The game is also the final title to be recognizably similar in presentation to the original.

Building upon the success of Puzzle Bobble 3, the game adds a pulley system that requires two sets of bubbles, attached to either side of a rope hanging across two pulleys. The game contains a story mode for single player play.

In total, the game features 640 levels. The console version features a level editor to either create and save a level, set a succession of levels, or to create an unlimited amount of extra levels and stages. It also has an alternative "story mode".</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/pbobble4-image.png</image>
		<releasedate>19980101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Taito Corporation</developer>
		<publisher>Taito Corporation</publisher>
		<genre>Puzzle</genre>
		<players>2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./rtype.zip</path>
		<name>R-Type</name>
		<desc>R-Type is a side scrolling shoot-em-up arcade game produced by Irem in 1987. The player controls a space fighter named the R-9 to defend humanity against a mysterious powerful alien life-form known as the "Bydo".

The game is composed of several sequential levels, with a boss enemy at the end of each. The player must navigate terrain and fight enemies using various weapons. The player's spacecraft has, by default, a weak but rapid-firing main gun; and a more powerful gun called a wave cannon, which requires the player to hold the fire button to build up power for the cannon.

During the game, the player can obtain an auxiliary device called a Force. This resembles a glowing orange ball. The Force can be attached to the front or back of the player's spacecraft, or detached to fly freely. When attached, the Force provides one of three different powerful weapons, in addition to the main gun and the wave cannon. When detached, these weapons cannot be used, but the Force will instead resort to a secondary set of guns, which can be fired by the player even if the Force is at a distance from the spacecraft. The Force has a secondary use as a shield; it is completely indestructible and can block most things fired at it, as well as damage or destroy enemies on contact.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/rtype-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19870701T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Irem Corp.</developer>
		<publisher>Irem Corp.</publisher>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
		<players>2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./rtype2.zip</path>
		<name>R-Type II</name>
		<desc>R-Type II is a horizontal scrolling shooter arcade game developed and published by Irem in 1989. It is the second game in the R-Type series.

The player controls a ship called the R-9C (or R-9 Custom), which is an improved version of its predecessor game's ship; the R-9. The ship's design was changed slightly, and the wave cannon was given a new charge level. Two new types of weapons (the Search Laser and Shotgun Laser) were added, bringing the total number of weapon types up to five. A new anti-ground unit bomb was also added to the missile inventory.

Though the number of levels was decreased from the prequel, the number of enemies, their durability, and the number of bullets they shoot were greatly increased. Enemy movements and terrain were also made trickier, bringing the game's difficulty up considerably. The same revival system is used as in the prequel, where the player is brought back to a checkpoint whenever their ship is destroyed.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/rtype2-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19890102T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Irem Corp.</developer>
		<publisher>Capcom</publisher>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
		<players>2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./raiden.zip</path>
		<name>Raiden</name>
		<desc>In the year 2090, Earth has suddenly become the target of deranged aliens. Following the invasion, a new cutting-edge weapon, the Raiden Supersonic Attack Figther, based on the destroyed alien craft, is created for humanity's hope for survival.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/raiden-image.jpg</image>
		<developer>Seibu Kaihatsu Inc.</developer>
		<publisher>Fabtek</publisher>
		<genre>Action, Shooter</genre>
		<players>2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./raidendx.zip</path>
		<name>Raiden DX</name>
		<desc>Vertical scrolling shoot-em-up that adds new features to its prequel Raiden II. Choose from three separate missions: Training special stage, Alpha levels 1-5 and Bravo levels 1-9. Collect various power-ups to increase your weaponry. Lots of secrets and bonuses including ratings based upon player performance</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/raidendx-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19940101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Seibu Kaihatsu Inc.</developer>
		<publisher>Fabtek</publisher>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
		<players>2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./raiden2.zip</path>
		<name>Raiden II</name>
		<desc>Excellent sequel to the classic original "Raiden".  As in the original, players control a fighter jet/spaceship through various levels while shooting down other planes and bombing tanks on the ground.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/raiden2-image.jpg</image>
		<developer>Seibu Kaihatsu Inc.</developer>
		<publisher>Fabtek</publisher>
		<genre>Action, Shooter</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./rbisland.zip</path>
		<name>Rainbow Islands</name>
		<desc>Rainbow Islands is a 1987 arcade game developed and published by Taito. The game is subtitled "The Story of Bubble Bobble 2" and is the sequel to Taito's hit game Bubble Bobble from the previous year. It is the second of four arcade games in the Bubble Bobble series (followed by Bubble Symphony and Bubble Memories, but itself has two direct sequels: Parasol Stars and Bubble Bobble Part 2). The game was ported for numerous home computers and game consoles.

Rainbow Islands - The Story of Bubble Bobble 2 est un jeu video de plates-formes developpe par Taito, initialement sorti en 1987 sur borne d'arcade. Il s'agit du second episode de la serie Bubble Bobble. Dans cette nouvelle aventure, le joueur incarne Bub ou Bob, qui ont repris leur forme humaine apres avoir ete transforme en « Bubble Dragon » dans le 1er episode. Les habitants de sept îles ont ete enleves par « Boss of Dark Shadow ». Le but du jeu est de rejoindre le sommet de chaque niveau avant que la montee des eaux ne submerge le heros. Bub a le pouvoir de lancer des arcs-en-ciel magiques qui font office d'armes et de plates-formes temporaires.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/rbisland-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Taito Corporation</developer>
		<publisher>Taito Corporation</publisher>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
		<players>2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./robocop.zip</path>
		<name>RoboCop</name>
		<desc>RoboCop is a side-scrolling platform shoot 'em up arcade game developed and published by Data East. The player controls RoboCop who advances through various stages that are taken from the 1987 movie. RoboCop was licensed to Data East by UK-based Ocean Software who in turn had obtained the rights straight from Orion Pictures at the script stage.

RoboCop features nine levels of action, with two of the game's nine stages being first-person target shooting ranges, in which players can try to accrue bonus points and earn extra health. Marked crates can be smashed to reveal one of three Weapon power-ups; Three-way Gun, Dual Laser and the incredibly powerful Cobra Gun. The film's incidental music plays throughout the game and RoboCop's speech is sampled directly from the original film.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/robocop-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19880301T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Data East Corporation</developer>
		<publisher>Data East Corporation</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./robocop2.zip</path>
		<name>RoboCop 2</name>
		<desc>RoboCop 2 is an arcade game developed and published in 1991 by Data East, which allows up to two players at once (one controlling the original RoboCop, the other controlling a slightly purple-hued clone). The game is based on the movie sequel with the same name. It is mostly a side-scrolling shoot 'em up, with some levels viewed from behind RoboCop and providing a targeting reticle with which to kill generic criminals.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/robocop2-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19910501T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Data East Corporation</developer>
		<publisher>Data East Corporation</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./robotron.zip</path>
		<name>Robotron: 2084</name>
		<desc>Robotron: 2084 is an arcade video game developed by Eugene Jarvis and Larry DeMar of Vid Kidz and released by Williams Electronics (part of WMS Industries) in 1982. It is a shoot 'em up with two-dimensional graphics. The game is set in the year 2084 in a fictional world where robots have turned against humans in a cybernetic revolt. The aim is to defeat endless waves of robots, rescue surviving humans, and earn as many points as possible.

The game uses a two-joystick control scheme; the left joystick controls the on-screen character's movement, while the right controls the direction the character's weapon fires. Both joysticks allow for an input direction in one of eight ways. Each level, referred to as a "wave", is a single screen populated with a large number of various enemy robots and obstacles; types include invincible giants to robots that continually manufacture other robots that shoot the protagonist. Coming into contact with an enemy, projectile, or obstacle costs the player one life, but extra lives can be earned at certain point totals. Waves also include human family members who can be rescued to score additional points, but certain robots can either kill them or turn them into enemies. Destroying all vulnerable robots allows the player to progress to the next wave; the cycle continues until all reserve lives are lost.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/robotron-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19821201T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Vid Kidz</developer>
		<publisher>Williams Electronic Games, Inc.</publisher>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./rygar.zip</path>
		<name>Rygar</name>
		<desc>An evil being known as Ligar is about to conquer the land of Argool. Such is his power that no living creature dares to cross paths with him. But the legendary warrior Rygar rises from his grave to restore peace and justice. Armed with his famed weapon Diskarmor, Rygar begins to traverse the vast lands that lead to the lair of the demon, as his minions are trying in vain to stop him...</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/rygar-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19861001T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Tecmo</developer>
		<publisher>Tecmo</publisher>
		<genre>Fighting</genre>
		<players>2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./salamand.zip</path>
		<name>Salamander</name>
		<desc>In a distant part of the universe, an alien creature called Zelos was born. As he grew so did his appetite, and soon he began devouring galaxies, planets, and stars by the hundreds. Now your planet has appeared in Zelos' path, and it is up to you and a partner to fly into battle to save your world. Life Force is an action packed shooter based on the arcade game. There are six levels which alternate between side and vertical scrolling, each of them ending with a powerful guardian. Throughout the game, destroying certain enemies will release power ups which can be used to equip your ship with more powerful weapons, extra speed, and shields.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/salamand-image.jpg</image>
		<developer>Konami</developer>
		<publisher>Konami</publisher>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./shocktr2.zip</path>
		<name>Shock Troopers - 2nd Squad</name>
		<desc>DIO, a terrorist organization led by a man called Nakatomi, has threatened the world's leaders to submit to their will. After DIO completely eradicates a city, a squad of Shock Troopers are sent to deal with the threat.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/shocktr2-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19990402T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>SNK</developer>
		<publisher>SNK</publisher>
		<genre>Fighting</genre>
		<players>2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./sharrier.zip</path>
		<name>Space Harrier</name>
		<desc>Space Harrier is set in the "Fantasy Zone", a surreal world composed of bright colors and a checkerboard-styled ground. The enemies are also unique, featuring prehistoric animals, Chinese dragons, and alien pods. The player is forced along the levels, running or flying around enemy fire, while shooting back with fireballs via the character's under-arm cannon (which doubles as a rocket-esque device allowing the character to fly).</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/sharrier-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19851001T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Sega</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./starwars.zip</path>
		<name>Star Wars</name>
		<desc>Strap on your helmet, climb aboard your X-Wing Fighter, and prepare to take on the Empire! The first scene is the Space Attack, with waves of hostile space-craft attacking your lonely but powerful ship. You battle to the Death Star, and once there fly close to the ground in a daring attempt to blast the space towers and flying stars, steering your way through the barrage. Finally, you emerge in the trench, jumping and ducking the stretch barriers and shooting the missile emplacements fastened to each side of the death-defying walls. There are many levels to the game with stirring music and speech synthesis - fast and furious action is guaranteed throughout!</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/starwars-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19830617T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Midway</developer>
		<publisher>Atari, Inc.</publisher>
		<genre>Shooter, Flight Simulator</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./s1945ii.zip</path>
		<name>Strikers 1945 II</name>
		<desc>Continuing where the last game ended, the forces of CANY had been demolished by the previous Strikers' line-up. However, a small group known as the FGR stole the sources and technology responsible for the last events and planned to continue CANYs work by initiating world-warfare with massive mech technology. Once again, the Strikers are called into action.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/s1945ii-image.jpg</image>
		<developer>Psikyo</developer>
		<publisher>Psikyo</publisher>
		<genre>Action, Shooter</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./s1945p.zip</path>
		<name>Strikers 1945 Plus</name>
		<desc>Strikers 1945 Plus (ストライカーズ1945PLUS) is a shoot 'em up video game for the Neo Geo created by Psikyo. This game is a remake of Strikers 1945 II for different hardware, featuring a horizontal screen.

The player chooses one of six planes or can opt for a random choice. The first four stages are in random order, while the last four are sequential. Players collect weapon powerups, bombs, and gold bars for points. Each plane has a unique "supershot" which is charged by damaging enemies and fired by holding then releasing the fire button. Supershots can be stored, although the number varies from plane to plane. Using a bomb results in a large friendly fighter swooping onto the screen and blocking shots while returning fire for a few seconds.

After the player beats the final boss, the game starts again from the beginning, albeit at a much higher difficulty level. All level are similar to the ones in Strikers 1945 II. Only one of the four bosses that are randomly chosen and the sixth boss is changed.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/s1945p-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19990901T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Psikyo</developer>
		<publisher>Psikyo</publisher>
		<genre>Action, Shooter</genre>
		<players>2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./ssriders.zip</path>
		<name>Sunset Riders</name>
		<desc>Sunset Riders is a side-scrolling run and gun video game developed and released by Konami as a coin-operated video game on the JAMMA arcade platform in 1991.

The game, which is set in a fanciful version of the American Old West, revolves around four bounty hunters named Steve, Billy, Bob, and Cormano who are out to claim rewards given for eliminating the most wanted outlaws in the West.

Sunset Riders can be played by up to two or four players, depending on the version of the game. In the two-player version each player can choose which of the four bounty hunters to play as at the start of the game, while in the four-player version each character is assigned to a different control panel. Steve and Billy wield revolvers, while Bob uses a rifle and Cormano uses a shotgun.

The objective of the game is to reach the end of each stage and defeat the outlaw awaiting at the end. While most of the game has the player moving on foot, Stages 2 and 7 both begin with a segment where the player fights against bandits on a horseback. In addition, there's a bonus minigame at the end of Stages 2 and 5 where the player must shoot at enemies from a first-person perspective coming from eight different positions before time runs out. There are a total of eight stages in the game.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/ssriders-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19910920T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Konami</developer>
		<publisher>Konami</publisher>
		<genre>Action, Shooter</genre>
		<players>4</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./shangon.zip</path>
		<name>Super Hang-On</name>
		<desc>Super Hang-On is a 1987 motorcycle racing arcade game from Sega, and the sequel to the acclaimed Hang-On.

The arcade mode in Super Hang-On is similar to the original Hang-On. However, there is a choice of four tracks to race on which are based on continents, each containing a different amount of stages. Also, should the player reach the normal maximum speed of 280 km/h, a turbo button is enabled. Using this button allows the player to reach an even higher top speed of 324 km/h. Each stage is roughly half the length of a stage in the original Hang-On. Africa is the easiest and shortest out of the four courses (six stages). Asia is the second easiest and is similar in length to the course from the original Hang-On at ten stages long. The Americas is the second to toughest course, containing 14 stages and Europe is the hardest course, being 18 stages long.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/shangon-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Sega</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<genre>Racing</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./tmnt2.zip</path>
		<name>Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles: Turtles In Time</name>
		<desc>Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles: Turtles in Time is an arcade video game produced by Konami. A sequel to the original Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles arcade game, it is a scrolling beat 'em up based mainly on the 1987 animated series.

Like its predecessor, Turtles in Time was available for the arcades in two and four-player versions. Each playable character has his own strengths and weaknesses. New features in this game include the ability to execute a power attack by hitting an enemy several times in a row, and the ability to slam Foot Soldiers into surrounding enemies.

Players guide the turtles through a series of levels. The first takes place in the streets of New York City. Later levels transport the turtles to representations of various historical eras. In each level, players face enemies from both the 1987 cartoon and the feature film Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles II: The Secret of the Ooze, including Foot Soldiers and Stone Warriors. Bosses include the fly form of Baxter Stockman, Metalhead, Tokka, Rahzar and Leatherhead.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/tmnt2-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19910918T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Konami</developer>
		<publisher>Konami</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>4</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./tempest.zip</path>
		<name>Tempest</name>
		<desc>Tempest is an arcade game by Atari Inc., originally designed and programmed by Dave Theurer. Released in October 1981 it was fairly popular and had several ports and sequels. The game is also notable for being the first video game with a selectable level of difficulty (determined by the initial starting level). The game is a tube shooter, a type of shoot 'em up where the environment is fixed and viewed from a three-dimensional perspective.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/tempest-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19811001T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Atari</developer>
		<publisher>Atari, Inc.</publisher>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
		<players>2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./tetris.zip</path>
		<name>Tetris</name>
		<desc>Tetris (In Russian: Тетрис) is a puzzle video game originally designed and programmed by Alexey Pajitnov in the Soviet Union. It was released on June 6, 1984, while he was working for the Dorodnicyn Computing Centre of the Academy of Science of the USSR in Moscow, Russian Soviet Federative Socialist Republic. He derived its name from the Greek numerical prefix tetra- (all of the game's pieces contain four segments) and tennis, Pajitnov's favorite sport.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/tetris-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19880101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Atari Games</developer>
		<publisher>Atari Games</publisher>
		<genre>Puzzle</genre>
		<players>2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./tophuntr.zip</path>
		<name>Top Hunter: Roddy &amp; Cathy</name>
		<desc>Top Hunter: Roddy &amp; Cathy is a side scrolling arcade platform game developed by SNK in 1994. The player must navigate through the stages, collecting items, killing enemies, and defeating a boss at the end of each area.

The game is split into four planets: Forest, Ice, Wind and Fire. Depending on what stage is picked first, the layout of the stage will change. For example, if the player picks the Ice world before the Forest world, the Forest world's starting layout will be different. After completing all four worlds, the player is taken to the final stage, where they must rematch with the four bosses and battle the game's antagonist, Captain Klapton.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/tophuntr-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19940601T000000</releasedate>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./toutrun.zip</path>
		<name>Turbo OutRun</name>
		<desc>Turbo OutRun is a 1989 arcade racing game released by Sega. A follow-up to 1986's Out Run, it was released as a dedicated game, as well as an upgrade kit for the original Out Run board.

Like its predecessor, Turbo OutRun has players driving a Ferrari, this time a Ferrari F40. Players now traverse a set route across the entire continental United States from New York City to Los Angeles instead of the branching paths of the first game. In addition to a time limit, Turbo OutRun also adds a computer-controlled opponent driving a Porsche 959. The "Turbo" in the title also plays a factor as players can now press a button to receive a brief turbo boost of speed. Various power-ups which increase the vehicle's attributes can now be chosen at various stages of the game.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/toutrun-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19891201T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Sega</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<genre>Racing</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./zaxxon.zip</path>
		<name>Zaxxon</name>
		<desc>Zaxxon is a 1982 arcade game developed and released by Sega. Some sources claim that Japanese electronics company Ikegami Tsushinki also worked on the development of Zaxxon. The game gives the player the experience of flying a fighter craft through a fortress while shooting at enemy entities (missiles, enemy gunfire, etc.) The object of the game is to hit as many targets as possible without being shot down or running out of fuel—which can be replenished, paradoxically, by blowing up fuel drums.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/zaxxon-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19820801T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Ikegami Tsushinki</developer>
		<publisher>Sega, Gremlin Interactive Ltd.</publisher>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
		<players>2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./timecris.zip</path>
		<name>Time Crisis</name>
		<desc>The game is a first person rail shooter that is played with a light gun and a foot pedal. The foot pedal is used to move out from behind cover to begin shooting. While the pedal is released the player is moved behind cover so that he can reload without being hit. The light gun that this arcade game used had a blowback function where the top of the gun would slide back to simulate a real gun. The game is moved along by a constantly decreasing timer that is only increased by completing a stage.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/timecris-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19951201T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Namco</developer>
		<publisher>Sony</publisher>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
		<playcount>2</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20190630T194626</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./timecrs3.zip</path>
		<name>Time Crisis 3 (TST1)</name>
		<playcount>1</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20190630T194420</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./timecrs4.zip</path>
		<name>Time Crisis 4</name>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19691231T160000</releasedate>
		<playcount>1</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20190630T194430</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./timecrs2.zip</path>
		<name>Time Crisis II</name>
		<desc>Christy Ryan, the agent responsible for uncovering the corporation's hidden agenda, attempts to escape NDI captivity and report the details of the plot to V.S.S.E. HQ, but is captured by Jakov Kinisky and his bodyguards. V.S.S.E. sends agents Keith Martin and Robert Baxter to shut down the Starline Network and rescue Ryan.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/timecrs2-image.jpg</image>
		<developer>Namco</developer>
		<publisher>Namco</publisher>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
		<players>2</players>
		<playcount>1</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20190630T194649</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./zedblade.zip</path>
		<name>Zed Blade</name>
		<desc>Operation Ragnarok is a sideways scrolling shoot-em-up for one or two players. Players can chose from three different ships, each with varying speeds.

As well as ship choices, there are three different selectable weapon systems available; one each for the front and rear firing weapons and one for projectile weapons (such as Homing Missiles).

Some enemies and waves drop bonuses and weapon power-up items when destroyed. Hyper-Bombs (very powerful 'Smart Bombs') can also be picked up.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/zedblade-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19940901T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>NMK Co. Ltd.</developer>
		<publisher>NMK Co. Ltd.</publisher>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
		<players>2</players>
		<playcount>2</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20190630T194830</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./spaceinv.zip</path>
		<name>Space Invaders</name>
		<desc>Space Invaders is a two-dimensional fixed shooter game in which the player controls a laser cannon by moving it horizontally across the bottom of the screen and firing at descending aliens. The aim is to defeat five rows of eleven aliens—some versions feature different numbers—that move horizontally back and forth across the screen as they advance towards the bottom of the screen. The player defeats an alien, and earns points, by shooting it with the laser cannon. As more aliens are defeated, the aliens' movement and the game's music both speed up. Defeating the aliens brings another wave that is more difficult, a loop which can continue indefinitely.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/spaceinv-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19780601T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Taito Corporation</developer>
		<publisher>Midway Games</publisher>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
		<players>2</players>
		<playcount>3</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20190630T200223</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./sinvasnb.zip</path>
		<name>Space Invasion (bootleg)</name>
		<playcount>1</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20190630T200551</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./sinvasn.zip</path>
		<name>Space Invasion (Europe)</name>
		<playcount>1</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20190630T200542</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./sicv.zip</path>
		<name>Space Invaders (CV Version)</name>
		<playcount>2</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20190630T202022</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./splatter.zip</path>
		<name>Splatterhouse</name>
		<desc>Splatterhouse is a sidescrolling beat 'em up video game in which the player controls Rick, a parapsychology student who is trapped inside West Mansion. After his resurrection by the Terror Mask, Rick makes his way through the mansion, fighting off hordes of creatures in a vain attempt to save his girlfriend Jennifer from a grisly fate. Players of this game will also recognize a number of western horror film influences, such as Friday the 13th and Evil Dead II.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/splatter-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19880101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Namco Splatter Team</developer>
		<publisher>Namco</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<playcount>1</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20190630T215124</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./s1945.zip</path>
		<name>Strikers 1945</name>
		<desc>In 1945, the second world war ended. Soon, there was peace, but an organization of high-ranking military officers from all over the world form a global army known as CANY. Their mission was to conquer the world. CANY activity was found in areas like the Soviet Union, America, Japan, and even Germany. It is revealed that CANY had weapons never seen before from rockets to mechanical walkers. The world quickly formed a group of pilots and planes called the Strikers whose mission is to rid of CANY from the world.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/s1945-image.png</image>
		<releasedate>19950904T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Psikyo</developer>
		<publisher>Psikyo</publisher>
		<genre>Action, Shooter</genre>
		<players>2</players>
		<playcount>1</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20190630T230824</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./strider2.zip</path>
		<name>Strider 2</name>
		<desc>Strider 2, released in Japan as Strider Hiryū 2 (ストライダー飛竜２ Sutoraidā Hiryū Tsū?), is Capcom's 1999 sequel to the original Strider. The game is actually the second sequel to Strider produced, following the U.S. Gold-produced Strider II released in 1990, a game with which Capcom was not directly involved. The Capcom-produced Strider 2 makes no references to the western-only Strider Returns. The game was released in arcades in December 1999 and was ported to the PlayStation in 2000.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/strider2-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19991213T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Capcom</developer>
		<publisher>Capcom</publisher>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
		<playcount>3</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20190701T190608</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./invaders.zip</path>
		<name>Space Invaders</name>
		<desc>Space Invaders is a two-dimensional fixed shooter game in which the player controls a laser cannon by moving it horizontally across the bottom of the screen and firing at descending aliens. The aim is to defeat five rows of eleven aliens—some versions feature different numbers—that move horizontally back and forth across the screen as they advance towards the bottom of the screen. The player defeats an alien, and earns points, by shooting it with the laser cannon. As more aliens are defeated, the aliens' movement and the game's music both speed up. Defeating the aliens brings another wave that is more difficult, a loop which can continue indefinitely.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/invaders-image.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19780601T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Taito Corporation</developer>
		<publisher>Midway Games</publisher>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
		<players>2</players>
		<playcount>12</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20190701T195141</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./term2.zip</path>
		<name>Terminator 2: Judgment Day</name>
		<desc>Terminator 2: Judgment Day is a gun shooting video game based on the film of the same name produced by Midway Manufacturing Company for the arcades in 1991.[1] Home conversions were released by Acclaim Entertainment for various platforms under the title of T2: The Arcade Game in order to avoid confusion with the numerous tie-in games also based on the movie.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/term2-image.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19911031T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Midway</developer>
		<publisher>Midway Games</publisher>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
		<players>2</players>
		<playcount>6</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20190701T204038</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./ddp2.zip</path>
		<name>DoDonPachi II - Bee Storm</name>
		<desc>Bee Storm was released in May 2001 in the Japanese arcades.
Developed by Cave and published by IGS under license from the developer.
It was the first shoot'em up game made on the PGM hardware.
Scitron Digital Content released a limited-edition soundtrack album for this game (Dodonpachi II / Dodonpachi Sound Trax - SCDC-00126) on 19/09/2001.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/ddp2-image.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19691231T160000</releasedate>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
		<players>2</players>
		<playcount>9</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20190705T231923</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./salmndr2.zip</path>
		<name>Salamander 2</name>
		<desc>Like the original Salamander, and as opposed to the Life Force releases, Salamander 2 abandons the selection-bar based power-up system, in favor for a simplified system that focuses on powering weapons up based on specific icons. For example, the player cannot increase his ship speed until a speed icon is picked up; additional speed icons further increase the ship velocity.

Several weapons, when additionally upgraded, turn into a 'super' weapon for approximately ten seconds. If the player has the ripple laser, and then gets another icon for it, the player will receive the high-powered Buster ripple for a short period of time. Options have been slightly changed with the arrival of 'option seeds', which are small options that orbit the ship firing only the basic initial shot. Two option seeds can combine into one full option. Moreover, options can also be sacrificed to utilize a short-term homing beam weapon.

Several enemy bosses typical to Gradius games return, including the Brain Golem (the first level boss) and the Tetran (the second level boss). There are a total of six levels. Since the game is similar to its prequel, Salamander 2 does not use the Revival Start feature from Gradius (which pushes the player back to a pre-determined checkpoint if a life is lost), many people consider this title to be easier than other titles in the Gradius series due to this. Once the game has been completed, it starts its second-loop at a much higher difficulty. The music is also changed to remixed versions of Salamander's music in some stages. The first player's ship is called Vic Viper while the second player's ship is Super Cobra.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/salmndr2-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19960126T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Konami</developer>
		<publisher>Konami</publisher>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
		<playcount>1</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20190706T144514</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./bouldash.zip</path>
		<name>Boulder Dash</name>
		<desc>Boulder Dash, originally released in 1984 for Atari 8-bit computers, is a series of computer games released for the Apple II, MSX, ZX Spectrum, Commodore 64, and ColecoVision home computers, and later ported to the NES, BBC Micro and Acorn Electron, PC, Amstrad CPC, Amiga, Intellivision and many other platforms. It was created by Peter Liepa and Chris Gray, and on October 28, 1983, acquired and later published by First Star Software, which still owns the rights to the game. Boulder Dash inherits numerous gameplay features from the earlier 1982 arcade game The Pit, by Japanese developer Taito.

The game's protagonist is called "Rockford". He must dig through caves collecting gems and diamonds and reach the exit within a time limit, while avoiding various types of dangerous creatures as well as obstacles like falling rocks and the constant danger of being crushed or trapped by an avalanche, or killed by an underground explosion.

The Commodore 64 version of the first game was also re-released on the Virtual Console in Europe on September 19, 2008, and in North America on June 1, 2009, but was removed from the service in 2013.

On January 21, 2014, FirstStar Software and TapStar Interactive announced Boulder Dash - 30th Anniversary Edition, a freemium mobile title developed by SoMa Play Inc. for Android and iOS.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/bouldash-image.png</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19850101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Exidy, Inc.</developer>
		<publisher>Data East Corporation</publisher>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./pbobblen.zip</path>
		<name>Puzzle Bobble (NeoGeo)</name>
		<desc>Puzzle Bobble  is a real-time puzzle game in which the player controls a device called "pointer" at the bottom of the screen, aiming and releasing randomly colored bubbles upwards. Depending on the aiming, the bubbles may float up directly or bounce off the walls, changing their trajectory. The goal is to aim the bubbles in such a way that they will touch identically colored ones. When such bubbles form a group of three or more, they pop and disappear from the screen.

If the ceiling of the area is covered by too many bubbles, it will gradually descend; the game is over when it nearly reaches the player-controlled pointer. Should the player fail to release the bubbles within a specific time limit, they will be released automatically, unaffected by the pointer's aiming.

A two-player mode is included as well. Each player competes on an area occupying half of the screen, dealing with identically generated bubbles. Whenever a player successfully disposes of a bubble group, a part of it is transferred onto the opponent's part of the screen.

The game features the two dinosaur protagonists (Bob and Bub) as well as other characters from Bubble Bobble, even though the two games have distinctly different gameplay.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/pbobblen-image.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19940601T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Taito Corporation</developer>
		<publisher>Taito Corporation</publisher>
		<genre>Puzzle</genre>
		<players>2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./pbobbl2n.zip</path>
		<name>Puzzle Bobble 2 (NeoGeo)</name>
		<desc>Bub and Bob are back! Like in Tetris in reverse, you shoot bubbles at an array of different-colored bubbles stuck in an ever descending ceiling, attempting to match them up three by three to make them disappear.

This edition contains both puzzle challenges, multiplayer and normal progressive stages.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/pbobbl2n-image.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19950701T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Taito Corporation</developer>
		<publisher>Taito Corporation</publisher>
		<genre>Puzzle</genre>
		<players>2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./spcinv95.zip</path>
		<name>Space Invaders 95</name>
		<desc>Space Invaders '95: The Attack of the Lunar Loonies is an Action game, developed and published by Taito Corporation, which was released in 1995.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/spcinv95-image.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19950904T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Taito Corporation</developer>
		<publisher>Taito Corporation</publisher>
		<genre>Action, Shooter</genre>
		<players>2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./spacedx.zip</path>
		<name>Space Invaders DX</name>
		<desc>A remake of the original with several new options and gameplay elements, including a competitive two-player mode.

Introduced a "parody mode" that replaces the traditional sprites by those from other Taito games including Arkanoid, Bubble Bobble, The NewZealand Story, and Darius.

Early versions use Taito's B system hardware, while later ones use Taito's F3 system hardware.

The home versions were released as Space Invaders - The Original Game. Other names include: Space Invaders XL on the Nuon, Space Invaders  '​94 on the Game Boy and Super Nintendo Entertainment System, and Space Invaders 2000 and Space Invaders 1500 on two PlayStation re-releases.

The home releases feature variants of the two-player mode.

The Game Boy release was an update to the 1990 version of Space Invaders Part II. Extra options similar to Space Invaders DX are available when played via Nintendo's Super Game Boy.

The first PlayStation release lacked the two-player mode. Subsequent PlayStation re-releases in 1998 and 2001 restored it. The 2001 release, known as The Invaders and Space Invaders 1500, includes a 3D version, and was part of D3 Publisher's Simple series of budget games that sell for ¥1500.

The Super Nintendo Entertainment System version was also released on Nintendo's Virtual Console.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/spacedx-image.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19931001T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Taito Corporation</developer>
		<publisher>Taito Corporation</publisher>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
		<players>2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./invadpt2.zip</path>
		<name>Space Invaders Part II</name>
		<desc>This game was released in America by Midway in 1980 as Space Invaders Deluxe. "Deluxe" uses a color overlay, however, instead of a color monitor. The only difference in gameplay between the two is the point value of the blinking saucer: 500 in Space Invaders Part II, but only 200 in Space Invaders Deluxe. Oddly enough, Midway's Space Invaders Deluxe displays the name Space Invaders Part II during the attract mode. All other references to the game (promotional material, manual, service bulletins, labels on the motherboard, serial number tags inside the cabinet, monitor glass, etc.) say Space Invaders Deluxe. This is most likely because the licensing agreement between Taito and Midway only allowed certain minor changes to the program code.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/invadpt2-image.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19801225T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Taito Corporation</developer>
		<publisher>Midway Games</publisher>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
		<players>2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./s1945iii.zip</path>
		<name>Strikers 1945 III</name>
		<desc>Year 1999, fall. The countless super minimum machine group 'nano-machine', which came flying, invaded the principal weapon and military terminals of each country from outer space and began multiplication. This weapon group which is automated with the 'nano-machines' repeated attack with non discrimination and the metropoles of each country were in a devastating state. A fear of the extensive nuclear warfare with the strategy nuclear missile error morphism hit the world!!! Barely the unit of each country which prevents the invasion of the 'nano- machine' is summoned because of the unmanned weapon eradication maneuvers. So, fighting with the weapons of the entire world was not enough. The Strikers start the attack on the enemy center! By the way of the time of half a century, new legend of special force STRIKERS now starts!</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/s1945iii-image.png</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19691231T160000</releasedate>
		<developer>Psikyo</developer>
		<publisher>Psikyo</publisher>
		<genre>Action, Shooter</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./bjourney.zip</path>
		<name>Blue's Journey</name>
		<desc>The planet Raguy was once a beautiful place, until the evil Daruma tribe invaded, bringing pollution that corrupted the land. You, as Blue, are a specialist of the Leaf Dump, and you love Princess Fa of the Raguy family. Unfortunately, Princess Fa has fallen sick from the pollution. It's your job to save your princess in Blue's Journey, a 2D side-scrolling platformer with RPG elements. Go through stages jumping on platforms and avoiding traps, while dealing with a multitude of bad guys, with a special bad guy boss at the end of every level to defeat with special means. To help with this, Blue can use a leaf attack and shrink. The leaf attack, only used when Blue is full sized, lets Blue slam a leaf that stuns any enemies he hits. Blue can also pick up power-ups for a more devastating leaf attack, or change his attack entirely. When the enemies are stunned, Blue can pick them up and throw them across the screen to dispose of more baddies. Shrunken down Blue can't use his attacking power, but he can fit into small crevasses and crannies not normally accessible. Of course, Blue can also dispatch enemies by jumping on them. Since Raguy's economy is flower based, Blue can collect flowers to buy things at special huts. But Blue must take care not to fall into traps or bottomless pits, which cause instant death. Being hit by bad guys or their shots is just as bad. Blue starts the game with two hearts, losing one when he gets whacked by a bad guy. When his heart count goes to zero, Blue dies. Play the game alone (as Blue), or with your friend (as a green Blue) for two-player simultaneous fun.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/bjourney-image.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19910606T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Alpha Denshi Co., Ltd.</developer>
		<publisher>SNK</publisher>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
		<players>2</players>
		<playcount>2</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20190706T230233</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./ssi.zip</path>
		<name>Super Space Invaders 91</name>
		<desc>Super Space Invaders '91 was produced by Taito in 1990.  The gameplay adheres much to the original, making it very easy to play. The object in most cases is to simply clear the screen of invaders before they reach bottom. Every so often, however, a boss invader appears that must be hit multiple times to be destroyed.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/ssi-image.png</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19900903T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Taito Corporation</developer>
		<publisher>Taito Corporation</publisher>
		<genre>Action, Shooter</genre>
		<players>2</players>
		<playcount>1</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20190707T093218</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./vulcan.zip</path>
		<name>Vulcan Venture</name>
		<desc>The player returns as the role of the pilot of the Vic Viper spaceship to battle the second onslaughts of the Bacterion Empire, under the new leadership of Gofer, the giant head. Gradius II has kept the gameplay from the original game, but infused it with enhancements brought from the spin-off, Salamander (Life Force). This is primarily evident in two of the weapons configurations that are selectable. Another first in the series was the inclusion of the "boss rush" (also known as "boss parade" or "boss alley"), a level designed entirely with only boss confrontations.

Gradius II retains the selection bar from Gradius, but now the player can choose between four different weapon configurations and progressions. All schemes have speed-up and multiples (Options), but have differing 'Missile', 'Double' (laser), and 'Laser' weapons. The player can have at most four multiples. Additionally, there are also two types of shielding to choose from: shield and forcefield. The shield option adds more durability, but only for the front of the Vic Viper, while the forcefield adds protection for the entire spacecraft, albeit only against three hits. In the Famicom version, choosing another multiple after four will make the four multiples to move around the spacecraft for 16 seconds; force field is the only shielding available for protection of the entire spacecraft, withstanding three hits and it is included in four different weapon configurations and progressions; and 'Double' and 'Laser' have to be activated twice to achieve full performance.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/vulcan-image.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19691231T160000</releasedate>
		<developer>Konami</developer>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
		<players>2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./gyruss.zip</path>
		<name>Gyruss</name>
		<desc>Gyruss is a shoot 'em up video arcade game developed by Konami, and released in 1983. 

It was designed by Yoshiki Okamoto, who had earlier created Time Pilot for Konami. Gyruss was licensed to Centuri in the United States, and was ported to numerous games consoles and home computers. It follows in the tradition of space war games such as Space Invaders and Galaga.

Gyruss was the second and last game Yoshiki Okamoto designed for Konami, after Time Pilot. Due to pay disputes, he was fired after the release of this game, and soon joined Capcom, where he would write 1942 and the first Street Fighter game.

The game's background music is an electronic, fast-paced arrangement of J. S. Bach's Toccata and Fugue in D minor, BWV 565; this particular arrangement is similar in sound to "Toccata", a rock arrangement by the UK-based instrumentalist group Sky.

Gyruss is notable for using stereo sound, which according to the bonus material for Konami Arcade Classics, was achieved by utilizing discrete audio circuits. The game used three microprocessors: two Z80 microprocessors and one 6809, as well as an 8039 microcontroller. For the sound, five AY-3-8910 PSG sound chips and a DAC.

Gyruss was released in both upright and cocktail cabinets.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/gyruss-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19830129T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Konami</developer>
		<publisher>Centuri, Inc.</publisher>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
		<players>2</players>
		<playcount>2</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20190707T113254</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./trackfld.zip</path>
		<name>Track &amp; Field</name>
		<desc>Track &amp; Field, known in Japan as Hyper Olympic (ハイパーオリンピック?), is a 1983 Olympic-themed arcade game developed and published by Konami.

The arcade version was released in 1983. The simple gameplay, based on quick repeating button presses, set the basics for sequels and similar games in the genre for the next decades. There were several home versions of the original; the ZX Spectrum and Amstrad CPC versions were only released as part of the Game, Set and Match II compilation in 1988, and are poorly regarded by fans.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/trackfld-image.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19831001T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Konami</developer>
		<publisher>Konami</publisher>
		<genre>Sports</genre>
		<players>4</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./gaxeduel.zip</path>
		<name>Golden Axe: The Duel</name>
		<desc>Many years have passed since the last war with Death Adder. But, as memories of those dark times begin to fade, another war is beginning. Out of the mists of time, a magical axe is discovered. The legend of the axe is well known throughout the land, for it is told that this axe is the very one which Gillius Thunderhead used to slay Death Adder.

Over time, the powers of the axe have grown. It is said that the artifact can grant its owner anything his or her heart desires. Young and old, good and evil, many are drawn towards the power of the weapon. Thus begins the war of the Golden Axe.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/gaxeduel-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19941001T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Sega</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<genre>Fighting</genre>
		<players>2</players>
		<playcount>6</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20190710T161240</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./gradius4.zip</path>
		<name>Gradius IV</name>
		<desc>The fourth game in the "Gradius" series brings a considerable graphical upgrade, particularly with the use of colored lighting but the core gameplay remains relatively unchanged. In addition, there are several additions and removals to the vaulted weapons system; specifically, the edit mode has been removed.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/gradius4-image.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19980101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Konami</developer>
		<publisher>Konami</publisher>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
		<playcount>14</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20190710T212932</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./unplayable/gaxeduel.zip</path>
		<name>Golden Axe - The Duel (JUETL 950117 V1.000)</name>
		<playcount>1</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20190714T004552</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./puckman.zip</path>
		<name>Puck-Man</name>
		<desc>The original Japanese Version of Pac-Man. The player controls Puck-Man through a maze, eating Puck-dots (also called pellets). When all Puck-dots are eaten, Puck-Man is taken to the next stage. Between some stages one of three intermission animations plays. Four enemies (Akabei, Pinky, Aosuke and Guzuta) roam the maze, trying to catch Puck-Man. If an enemy touches Puck-Man, a life is lost and the Puck-Man itself withers and dies. When all lives have been lost, the game ends. Puck-Man is awarded a single bonus life at 10,000 points by default.

Near the corners of the maze are four larger, flashing dots known as power pellets that provide Puck-Man with the temporary ability to eat the enemies. The enemies turn deep blue, reverse direction and usually move more slowly. When an enemy is eaten, its eyes remain and return to the center box where it is regenerated in its normal color. Blue enemies flash white to signal that they are about to become dangerous again and the length of time for which the enemies remain vulnerable varies from one stage to the next, generally becoming shorter as the game progresses. In later stages, the enemies go straight to flashing, bypassing blue, which means that they can only be eaten for a short amount of time, although they still reverse direction when a power pellet is eaten; in even later stages, the ghosts do not become edible (i.e., they do not change color and still make Puckman lose a life on contact), but they still reverse direction.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/puckman-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19800522T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Namco</developer>
		<publisher>Namco</publisher>
		<genre>Action, Strategy</genre>
		<players>2</players>
		<playcount>4</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20190717T233448</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./parodius.zip</path>
		<name>Parodius</name>
		<desc>Created as a parody of Konami's own superb and challenging "Gradius" series of shoot-em-ups, Parodius acquired its own identity and would spawn sequels of its own. It maintained the same intuitive power-up system of "Nemesis" and "Salamander" but adopted a graphical style that was entirely its own; something that becomes evident at the very start of the game when players can chose to pilot either a penguin or an octopus rather than the traditional Gradius ship. Parodius' eccentricity and unique humour is further demonstrated soon after the game begins, as players face such enemies as a sumo-wrestling pig and a half-cat/half-boat creature.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/parodius-image.png</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19900430T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Konami</developer>
		<publisher>Konami</publisher>
		<genre>Action, Shooter</genre>
		<players>2</players>
		<playcount>8</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20190720T215605</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./rastan.zip</path>
		<name>Rastan</name>
		<desc>Rastan Saga (ラスタンサーガ?), known in North America simply as Rastan, is a 1987 hack and slash platform arcade game developed and published by Taito.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/rastan-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Taito Corporation</developer>
		<publisher>Taito Corporation</publisher>
		<genre>Fighting</genre>
		<players>2</players>
		<favorite>true</favorite>
		<playcount>2</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20190720T221255</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./shocktro.zip</path>
		<name>Shock Troopers</name>
		<desc>Shock Troopers is an arcade game developed by Saurus. Gameplay involves taking command of one or three commandos in an 8-way shooter through 6 stages of opposing forces, weaponry, and power-ups.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/shocktro-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19970101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Saurus</developer>
		<publisher>SNK</publisher>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
		<players>2</players>
		<playcount>1</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20190720T224526</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./mslug2.zip</path>
		<name>Metal Slug 2</name>
		<desc>As Marco, Eri, Tarma, or Fio, you must defeat the evil General Morden and his henchman. To do this, you must defeat various enemies that get in your way. Throughout the game, you can collect new weapons including the Heavy Machine Gun, Shot Gun, Rocket Launcher, Flame Shot, Laser Shot, Flame Bottles, and Armor Piercer. Also scattered throughout the game, you can ride in four different vehicles (aka: Slugs) such as the Metal Slug, Slug Flyer, Camel Slug, and SlugNoid. By using these vehicles, you can cause awesome destruction against Morden's evil army. Other items such as energy, extra ammunition, and food (eat too much and your player will gain weight) are also found throughout the game.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/mslug2-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19980101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>SNK</developer>
		<publisher>SNK</publisher>
		<genre>Action, Adventure, Shooter</genre>
		<players>2</players>
		<playcount>1</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20190808T012835</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./mslugx.zip</path>
		<name>Metal Slug X</name>
		<desc>Metal Slug X is a modified version of Metal Slug 2 released in 1999 for the Neo-Geo console/arcade platform by SNK. It introduces some new features like new weapons, rearranged enemy replacement and greater difficulty.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/mslugx-image.png</image>
		<releasedate>19960101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nazca</developer>
		<publisher>SNK</publisher>
		<genre>Action, Adventure, Shooter</genre>
		<players>2</players>
		<playcount>1</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20190808T013145</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./mspacman.zip</path>
		<name>Ms. Pac-Man</name>
		<desc>The gameplay of Ms. Pac-Man is identical to the original Pac-Man. The player earns points by eating pellets and avoiding ghosts (contact with one causes Ms. Pac-Man to lose a life). Eating an energizer (or "power pellet") causes the ghosts to turn blue, allowing them to be eaten for extra points. Bonus fruits can be eaten for increasing point values, twice per round. As the rounds increase, the speed increases, and energizers generally lessen the extent of the ghosts' vulnerability, eventually stopping altogether.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/mspacman-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19810101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Midway</developer>
		<publisher>Midway Games</publisher>
		<genre>Action, Puzzle</genre>
		<players>2</players>
		<playcount>3</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20190812T231152</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./tmnt.zip</path>
		<name>Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles</name>
		<desc>Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles is a side-scrolling beat 'em up released by Konami in 1989. It is based on the first Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles animated series which began airing in the winter of 1987.

The player chooses from one of the four Ninja Turtles: Leonardo, Michelangelo, Donatello, and Raphael. After Shredder kidnaps the Turtles' friend April O'Neil and their mentor Splinter, they must give chase, save their comrades, and defeat the evil Shredder. Up to four players (two in some versions) can take control of any of the Turtles. Donatello has slower attacks but a longer range, Michelangelo and Raphael have faster attacks but a shorter range, and Leonardo is a well-rounded Turtle with average range and speed.

Most of the enemies the Turtles face are the Foot Soldiers, all color-coded to indicate their attack patterns and weapon of choices. Some enemies, such as the standard purple-clad Foot Soldiers and Roadkill Rodney robots, have the ability to restrain the Turtles' mobility and drain their health, leaving the player open to attack for other enemies. The bosses in the game include Rocksteady and Bebop (individually at first in that order, and later the two of them together), Baxter Stockman, Granitor, General Traag, Krang, and Shredder himself.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/tmnt-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19890601T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Konami</developer>
		<publisher>Konami</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>4</players>
		<playcount>1</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20191104T211119</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./captcomm.zip</path>
		<name>Captain Commando</name>
		<desc>Captain Commando is set in a crime-ridden future in the year 2026, where a superhero named Captain Commando, assisted by his three faithful Commando Companions rise up to protect the Earth and all the Galaxy from a gang of super-powered criminals.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/captcomm-image.png</image>
		<releasedate>19911101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Capcom</developer>
		<publisher>Capcom</publisher>
		<genre>Action, Platform</genre>
		<players>4</players>
		<playcount>2</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20200105T010836</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./mslug.zip</path>
		<name>Metal Slug</name>
		<desc>Players control Marco and Tarma, both members of the special-ops force Team Peregrine Falcon (commonly known as Team PF), and battle their way through stage after stage of intense action. The goal is to try to overthrow General Morden and win back the stolen weapon, the Metal Slug. Players must blast through waves of enemies and machines (while also jumping over any obstacles in the way) to advance through the stages. It's not as hopeless as it might sound, though - weapons such as heavy machine guns, shotguns, rocket launchers and flamethrowers, as well as the Metal Slug itself (which appears frequently in the game), will make the battle easier.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/mslug-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19960418T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nazca</developer>
		<publisher>SNK</publisher>
		<genre>Action, Shooter</genre>
		<players>2</players>
		<playcount>2</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20200105T004914</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./strider.zip</path>
		<name>Strider</name>
		<desc>Strider is a 1989 side-scrolling platform game developed and released for the CP System arcade hardware by Capcom. The game is set in a dystopian future in the year 2048 and features a wide range of settings that dramatically affect gameplay. It became one of Capcom's early big hits prior to Street Fighter II, hailed for its innovative gameplay, diverse and unique music, and multilingual voice samples.

The player controls the protagonist Strider Hiryu, whose main weapon is a tonfa-like plasma sword. He can perform numerous acrobatic feats depending on the joystick/button combination used. 

The game has five stages: the Kazakh Soviet Socialist Republic, the Siberian Wilderness, the Aerial Battleship Balrog, the Amazonian Jungle, and the Grandmaster's lair itself, the Third Moon.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/strider-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19890101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Capcom</developer>
		<publisher>Capcom</publisher>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
		<players>2</players>
		<playcount>19</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20200105T013058</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./tigeroad.zip</path>
		<name>Tiger Road</name>
		<desc>'Ryu Ken Oh' raided villages and kidnapped small children to brainwash them and make them into soldiers. Master of 'Oh Rin' temple ordered his best student 'Lee Wong' to destroy 'Ryu Ken Oh' and save the children. To meet with 'Ryu Ken Oh', 'Lee Wong' must clear 4 stages and destroy big enemy at the end of each stage. 'Lee Wong' was given a magical jacket to jump and fly around, and weapons from the master to destroy 'Ryu Ken Oh'.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/tigeroad-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Capcom</developer>
		<publisher>Capcom</publisher>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
		<players>2</players>
		<playcount>1</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20200105T013230</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./stdragon.zip</path>
		<name>Saint Dragon</name>
		<desc>A side scrolling shooter.  Much like R-Type in feel of play. There is no randomness to the levels yet it is very challenging. The game has rather colorful and attractive graphics and a rather catchy musical track. You can collide with (and die from) the terrain. One very unique feature of the game is the dragon is multi segmented. The tail follows the heads movements in a "Snap the Whip" type of motion. Only the head is vulnerable so if you are to do a tight circle then put your head in the center your are mostly invulnerable.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/stdragon-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19891001T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Jaleco Ltd.</developer>
		<publisher>Jaleco Ltd.</publisher>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
		<players>2</players>
		<playcount>1</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20200112T042446</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./blazstar.zip</path>
		<name>Blazing Star</name>
		<desc>Sometime in their past, the planets Remuria and Mutras started an interplanetary war that showed no sign of ending. The endless fight between the human-like inhabitants of the two planets had gone so long that weapon development moved into dangerous territory: Organic Weapon Production combined with alien technology. Soon, a sentient weapon - Brawshella - was born. Brawshella gathered all animal life on both planets and forced them to do its bidding and attack the humans. In a week, the humans were assimilated by Brawshella.
Yet, once they were assimilated, they found no other purpose in life but to continue fighting each other. After a while, four of the assimilated fighter pilots regained their consciousness and remembered their pasts. Upon discovering their humanity, the pilots were conflicted with following Brawshella's orders or fighting it to fully regain their independence. The pilots finally turn against the machine in a battle to rediscover themselves and reclaim their planets.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/blazstar-image.png</image>
		<releasedate>19980219T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Yumekobo Co., Ltd.</developer>
		<publisher>SNK</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>2</players>
		<playcount>36</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20200112T163254</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./avsp.zip</path>
		<name>Alien vs. Predator</name>
		<desc>San Drad, California, has been overrun by the Aliens, and the cybernetically-enhanced Major Dutch Schaefer and Lieutenant Linn Kurosawa have been abandoned by their superiors and are cornered by a swarm of the Alien drones. Before they can be killed, a pair of the Predators appear and destroy the Aliens. The Predators offer an alliance with the two humans in order to stop the Alien infestation.

The players take control of up to three of four characters: Dutch, Linn, a Predator hunter, and a Predator warrior, and battle the Aliens through several environments. In the process, the characters discover that the Alien presence on Earth is the result of an experiment headed by a renegade General Bush of the U.S. Colonial Marines in conjunction with the Weyland-Yutani corporation. They destroy the Alien hive by crashing a military ship into San Drad, causing a huge explosion. The Predator warrior then gives his wrist blades to Dutch and Linn in recognition of their skills as warriors, before the Predators depart back into space.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/avsp-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19940520T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Capcom</developer>
		<publisher>Capcom</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>2</players>
		<playcount>2</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20200121T015307</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./alexkidd.zip</path>
		<name>Alex Kidd: The Lost Stars</name>
		<desc>Alex Kidd: The Lost Stars has similar gameplay like in the other Alex Kidd games, but this one's easier and designed for kids. Once again you play Alex, whose mission is to run through each location, knocking down enemies, and obtain the six miracle balls. These balls are hidden inside the strangest places like golden eggs, the Fantasy Zone ship out of action, clamshells, Christmas presents, pumpkins, and desk bells.

Alex must then venture in outer space to defeat the evil Ziggurat. Locations include Toy World, Machine World, the World of Make Believe, Water World, and Monster World. You will even tour through the giant's body. Once you obtained the six miracle balls, you have to run through all the locations again, but these repeated locations introduce new enemies.

With all the locations, you're under a time limit, and as usual, if the time expires, you lose a life. Alex starts the game with nothing, but during the game, he can collect power-ups that give him extra time, and allow him to shoot enemies or jump higher.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/alexkidd-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19860101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Sega</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
		<players>2</players>
		<playcount>3</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20200126T204713</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./bangbead.zip</path>
		<name>Bang Bead</name>
		<desc>Bang Bead is a pong-esq arcade game released in 2000 by Visco Corp. It was released for the SNK Neo-Geo MVS hardware chip set. It is the sequel to 1998's Battle Flip Shot.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/bangbead-image.png</image>
		<releasedate>20000101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Visco Corporation</developer>
		<publisher>SNK</publisher>
		<genre>Sports</genre>
		<players>2</players>
		<playcount>1</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20200126T204931</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./88games.zip</path>
		<name>'88 Games</name>
		<desc>Konami '88 (also known as '88 Games or Hyper Sports Special) is the third in the Track &amp; Field game series by Konami, where you test your Olympic skills against other world-class athletes. As the name implies, it is loosely based on (and not licensed by) the 1988 Summer Olympics in Seoul, South Korea. Bronze or silver medals are not good enough - you have to go for the gold to get to the next event. However, you must at least qualify in each event in order to compete in the next event.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/88games-image.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19880101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Konami</developer>
		<publisher>Konami</publisher>
		<genre>Sports</genre>
		<players>2</players>
		<playcount>3</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20200229T185141</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./1942.zip</path>
		<name>1942</name>
		<desc>1942 is set in the Pacific theater of World War II. The goal is to reach Tokyo and destroy the entire Japanese air fleet. The player pilots a plane dubbed the "Super Ace" (but its appearance is clearly that of a Lockheed P-38 Lightning). The player has to shoot down enemy planes; to avoid enemy fire, the player can perform a roll or "loop-the-loop".</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/1942-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19841201T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Capcom</developer>
		<publisher>Capcom</publisher>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
		<players>2</players>
		<playcount>5</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20200229T205656</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./1943kai.zip</path>
		<name>1943 Kai: Midway Kaisen</name>
		<desc>This updated version was released exactly one year after the original game's debut. 1943 Kai is an enhanced, "wild" version of 1943 that was made only available in Japan under the name 1943 Kai: Midway Kaisen (or 1943改: ミッドウェイ海戦). Most of the graphics and sounds have been reworked, the weapons have been made more extreme and some fairly strange things (laser-firing WWII planes and ships that run on ground) have been added. The trademark P-38 has been replaced with a biplane, the Boeing-Stearman Model 75.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/1943kai-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19880601T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Capcom</developer>
		<publisher>Capcom</publisher>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
		<players>2</players>
		<playcount>3</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20200229T205918</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./1943.zip</path>
		<name>1943: The Battle of Midway</name>
		<desc>The game is set in the Pacific theater of World War II, off the coast of the Midway Atoll. The goal is to attack the Japanese Air Fleet that bombed the players' American Aircraft Carrier, pursue all Japanese Air and Sea forces, fly through the 16 levels of play, make their way to the Japanese battleship Yamato and destroy her. 11 Levels consist of an Air-to-Sea battle (with a huge battleship or an aircraft carrier as an End-Level Boss), while 5 levels consist of an all-aerial battle against a squadron of Japanese Bombers and a Mother Bomber that needs to be destroyed.
As in 1942, players pilot a P-38. Two buttons are used: one for regular attacks (with several weapons) and one for special actions that executes either a loop like in 1942 or one of three special attacks that damage the plane. Unlike 1942, the player only has one life, with one refillable energy meter. Destroying a complete formation of red enemy planes will result in a power-up, such as a health boost or a temporary special weapons which replaces the default twin gun.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/1943-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19870601T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Capcom</developer>
		<publisher>Capcom</publisher>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
		<players>2</players>
		<playcount>5</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20200229T185317</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./1944.zip</path>
		<name>1944: The Loop Master</name>
		<desc>The game takes place in the heated battles of 1944 during the Second World War as a super ace pilot attempts to defeat an entire army. The game operates and plays like most standard shooters. The objective of every level is to shoot enemy planes, tanks, trains, turrets, battleships, and defeat the boss after each level. Unlike its predecessor, 19XX: The War Against Destiny, the game plays more like the early games in the series.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/1944-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>20000620T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Capcom</developer>
		<publisher>8ing/Raizing</publisher>
		<genre>Action, Shooter</genre>
		<players>2</players>
		<playcount>3</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20200229T185335</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./1945kiii.zip</path>
		<name>1945k III</name>
		<desc>1945kIII is a scrolling shooter arcade video game. It was developed and published by the Korean developer Oriental Software in 2000.

In this game, the player controls a fighter and has to shoot as many enemy fighters as possible while the stage is moving forward. There are many bonuses and new weapons available. The gameplay is reminiscent of several 1980s scrolling shooter arcade video games, and is therefore considered a retro game.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/1945kiii-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>20000101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Promat</developer>
		<publisher>Oriental Soft</publisher>
		<genre>Action, Shooter</genre>
		<players>2</players>
		<playcount>3</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20200229T185348</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./19xx.zip</path>
		<name>19XX: The War Against Destiny</name>
		<desc>19XX: The War Against Destiny is a vertical scrolling shooter arcade game made by Capcom in 1995 (copyrighted in 1996). The game is the 4th of a series of World War II vertical shooters made by Capcom. The story takes place before a fictional war (Hence, the 19XX) as a lone pilot tries to defeat an entire army/evil organization from starting another World War, which soon escalates to a nuclear apocalypse.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/19xx-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19951207T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Capcom</developer>
		<publisher>Capcom</publisher>
		<genre>Action, Shooter</genre>
		<players>2</players>
		<playcount>3</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20200229T185423</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./sonicwi3.zip</path>
		<name>Aero Fighters 3</name>
		<desc>The world seems to be free from the menace of the evil alien forces. However, they are not willing to give up and launch a surprise attack against the Aero Fighters' base, effectively destroying their aircraft. Unable to counter the attack, they must use old WWII-era warplanes with strange modifications, in a desperate scramble for victory.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/sonicwi3-image.png</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19950101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Video System Co., Ltd.</developer>
		<publisher>Video System Co., Ltd.</publisher>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
		<players>2</players>
		<playcount>2</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20200229T185457</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./cadash.zip</path>
		<name>Cadash</name>
		<desc>Cadash is a platform action role-playing game. The player chooses one of the four character classes in the beginning of the game: fighter, priestess, mage, or ninja. The protagonist fights his or her way through dungeons, attacking physically or casting spells (as priestess or mage). Like in regular platform games, there are places where the player character is required to jump, duck, or climb. The protagonist gains experience for defeating monsters, and their level rises in a true RPG fashion.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/cadash-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19890601T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Taito Corporation</developer>
		<publisher>Taito Corporation</publisher>
		<genre>Action, Adventure, Role-Playing</genre>
		<players>2</players>
		<playcount>1</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20200229T185611</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./centiped.zip</path>
		<name>Centipede</name>
		<desc>Centipede is a vertically oriented shoot 'em up arcade game produced by Atari, Inc. in 1980. The game was designed by Ed Logg and Dona Bailey. The player defends against centipedes, spiders, scorpions and fleas, completing a round after eliminating the centipede that winds down the playing field.

The centipede starts at the top of the screen, traveling either left or right. When it hits a mushroom or the edge of the screen, it drops one level and switches direction. Thus, more mushrooms on the screen cause the centipede to descend more rapidly. The player can destroy mushrooms by shooting them, but each takes four hits to destroy.

If the centipede reaches the bottom of the screen, it moves back and forth within the player area and one-segment "head" centipedes are periodically added. This continues until the player has eliminated both the original centipede and all heads. When all the centipede's segments are destroyed, a new centipede forms at the top of the screen. Every time a centipede is eliminated, however, the next one is one segment shorter and is accompanied by one additional, fast-moving "head" centipede.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/centiped-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19800101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Atari</developer>
		<publisher>Atari, Inc.</publisher>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
		<players>2</players>
		<playcount>1</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20200229T185630</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./fantjour.zip</path>
		<name>Fantastic Journey</name>
		<desc>Fantastic Parodius - Pursue the Glory of the Past, known outside Japan as Fantastic Journey, is a scrolling shooter arcade game and the third title in the Parodius series produced by Konami. Like the rest of the series, it is a parody of the Gradius series and other Konami games.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/fantjour-image.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19940426T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Konami</developer>
		<publisher>Konami</publisher>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
		<players>2</players>
		<playcount>2</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20200229T185713</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./fantzone.zip</path>
		<name>Fantasy Zone</name>
		<desc>Imagine the wildest, wackiest place in the Universe and you've got Fantasy Zone! As Opa-Opa, a living spaceship, you'll marvel at the incredible landscapes filled with the strangest creatures. Watch out! They may look cute and innocent, but they're Menons, nasty aliens that have overrun the eight planets that make up Fantasy Zone. Your job is to clear each world of Menons. Every time you zap one, it turns into a coin. Collect enough coins and you can buy power-up items like deadlier weapons and mightier engines. At the end of every planet lurks a super-powerful boss. Find a way to blast past these monsters in order to continue your exciting journey in the Fantasy Zone!</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/fantzone-image.png</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19860101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Sega</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<genre>Action, Shooter</genre>
		<players>2</players>
		<playcount>1</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20200229T185727</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./fantzn2.zip</path>
		<name>Fantasy Zone II: The Tears of Opa-Opa</name>
		<desc>Opa-Opa is at it again in this zany return to his original homeland some ten years later. Welcome to Fantasy Zone II where perils are great and rewards even greater. During your visit you'll discover that peace is at stake once again and those who threaten it are more cunning and wicked than before. So beware, the evil Blackhearts are near and they're not alone. Scores of unusual and seemingly innocent creatures will enthusiastically approach you. But don't be fooled. They're not here to help. They're henchmen for the dark powers of the Blackhearts. And they'll sabotage every chance you've got to protect the warp gates from total ruin. So fight valiantly, because just when you think you've made it, the Blackhearts will be waiting.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/fantzn2-image.png</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19880101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Sunsoft</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<genre>Action, Shooter</genre>
		<players>2</players>
		<playcount>2</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20200229T185753</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./ffight.zip</path>
		<name>Final Fight</name>
		<desc>Final Fight can be played by up to two players simultaneously, with each player controlling a different character. Before the game begins, the player chooses between the three main characters, Guy, Cody, and Haggar, each with his own fighting style and attributes. Guy is the weakest but has faster attacks, Haggar is the strongest but also the slowest, and Cody has all-round attributes.

Final Fight consists of six stages or "rounds", as well as two bonus rounds. Each round takes place in a different section of Metro City such as the Slums and the Subway, with most rounds featuring more than one level. At the end of each round the player will face a boss character unique to that round.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/ffight-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19891201T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Capcom</developer>
		<publisher>Capcom</publisher>
		<genre>Action, Fighting, Platform</genre>
		<players>2</players>
		<playcount>4</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20200229T192929</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./galaga.zip</path>
		<name>Galaga</name>
		<desc>Galaga is a fixed shooter arcade game developed and published by Namco in Japan and published by Midway in North America in 1981. It is the sequel to Galaxian, released in 1979. The gameplay of Galaga puts the player in control of a space ship which is situated on the bottom of the screen. At the beginning of each stage, the area is empty, but over time, enemy aliens fly in formation, and once all of the enemies arrive on screen, they will come down at the player's ship in formations of one or more and may either shoot it or collide with it. During the entire stage, the player may fire upon the enemies, and once all enemies are vanquished, the player moves onto the next stage.

Galaga has proven very successful. The arcade version of it has been ported to many consoles, and it has had several sequels, most recently Galaga Legions for the PlayStation Network and Xbox Live Arcade services.

The objective of Galaga is to score as many points as possible by destroying insect-like enemies. The player controls a starfighter that can move left and right along the bottom of the playfield. Enemies swarm in groups in a formation near the top of the screen, and then begin flying down toward the player, firing bombs at the fighter. The game ends when the player's last fighter is lost, either by colliding with an enemy or one of its bullets, or by being captured.

Galaga introduces a number of new features over its predecessor, Galaxian. Among these is the ability to fire more than one bullet at a time, a count of the player's "hit/miss ratio" at the end of the game, and a bonus "Challenging Stage" that occurs every few levels, in which a series of enemies fly onto and out of the screen in set patterns without firing at the player's ship or trying to crash into it.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/galaga-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19810801T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Namco</developer>
		<publisher>Midway Games</publisher>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
		<players>2</players>
		<favorite>true</favorite>
		<playcount>5</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20200229T190717</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./galaga88.zip</path>
		<name>Galaga '88</name>
		<desc>The gameplay in Galaga '88 is built on the same premise as that of the original Galaga game, but is in many ways more complex and more difficult. The game is divided into a series of 29 Stages distributed through eight Worlds. The starship Galaga accelerates between Stages and Worlds and even to higher dimensions (go to the section on Dimensional Travel below to find out more).

With the exception of the third and eighth, each World culminates in a Challenging Stage. There are six such stages to engage in any full game, and each begins with the on-screen announcement "That's Galactic Dancin'!" and has its own YM2151-generated song to which the enemy formations dance. In any given Challenging Stage, both the design of the enemies and their dancing formations shall vary according to the player's current Dimension. As in Galaga, the objective is to destroy all forty enemies before they fly away off the screen. However, refraining completely from touching any controls for the duration of a Challenging Stage awards a "secret bonus" ranging in value from 10000 to 25000 points, and equal to the "special bonus" which would have been awarded for destroying all forty enemy aliens instead.

Galaga '88 introduces a variety of new enemies and behaviors. Most of these special enemies are worth varying amounts of bonus points when destroyed. Some enemies can combine into larger enemies which take multiple hits to destroy, while others arrive in eggs, explode in a shower of fireworks, grow with multiple hits, or sport armor which makes them invincible while in formation. Certain enemies drop small formations of tiny creatures that wiggle their way down the screen, and still others can act as escorts to incoming groups of enemies and then quickly dive at the player before leaving the game. Most stages also include various obstacles which appear once the enemy formation has been assembled. These can be destroyed with either one or several shots, and the first one on each stage will leave a "Warp Capsule".

At the start of the game, the player can select how many Galaga starships to start with (one or two), affecting their number of remaining lives. The game ends after the final boss is defeated (or when the player's last ship is destroyed or captured) - in the latter case, the player can continue the game for an additional credit. The Game Over screen shows the player's hit-miss ratio and a visual representation of their progress. If the player reaches Stage 27, the game also shows a picture of the final boss (damaged if defeated, but silhouetted if not). If the arcade operator has set the "continue" option to "on", the player also cannot continue if he is defeated on Stages 27-29.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/galaga88-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19871201T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Namco</developer>
		<publisher>Namco</publisher>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
		<players>2</players>
		<playcount>3</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20200229T190741</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./gauntlet.zip</path>
		<name>Gauntlet</name>
		<desc>Gauntlet is a fantasy-themed hack and slash 1985 arcade game by Atari Games. It is noted as the first class-based multiplayer game. Released during the emergence of popularity of other role-playing games like Dungeons &amp; Dragons, the game was a sensation, being one of the first true dungeon crawl arcade games.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/gauntlet-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19851001T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Atari Games</developer>
		<publisher>Atari Games</publisher>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
		<players>4</players>
		<playcount>1</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20200229T190806</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./gpilots.zip</path>
		<name>Ghost Pilots</name>
		<desc>Ghost Pilots is a vertical-scrolling shoot 'em up arcade game released in 1991 by SNK.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/gpilots-image.png</image>
		<releasedate>19910601T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>SNK</developer>
		<publisher>SNK</publisher>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
		<players>2</players>
		<playcount>2</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20200229T204054</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./goldnaxe.zip</path>
		<name>Golden Axe</name>
		<desc>An evil entity known as Death Adder has captured the King and his daughter, and holds them captive in their castle. He also finds the Golden Axe, the magical emblem of Yuria, and threatens to destroy both the axe and the royal family unless the people of Yuria accept him as their ruler. Three Warriors set out on a quest to rescue Yuria and avenge their losses at the hands of Death Adder. The first is a battle axe-wielding dwarf, Gilius Thunderhead, from the mines of Wolud, whose twin brother was killed by the soldiers of Death Adder. Another is a male barbarian, Ax Battler, wielding a two handed broadsword looking for revenge for the murder of his mother. The last is a long-sword-wielding Tyris Flare, an amazon, whose parents were both killed by Death Adder.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/goldnaxe-image.png</image>
		<releasedate>19890501T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Sega</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>2</players>
		<playcount>1</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20200229T190834</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./gradius.zip</path>
		<name>Gradius</name>
		<desc>One of the defining characteristics of the Gradius series is the use of a "power meter." The power meter is powered by a power-up item, whose purpose, when collected, is to move a highlight to the next power-up on the power meter. When a power-up that the player wants becomes highlighted, he or she may activate it, also causing the highlight to reset.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/gradius-image.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19850529T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Konami</developer>
		<publisher>Konami</publisher>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
		<players>2</players>
		<playcount>14</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20200229T190847</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./gradius2.zip</path>
		<name>Gradius II: Gofer no Yabou</name>
		<desc>The player returns as the role of the pilot of the Vic Viper spaceship to battle the second onslaughts of the Bacterion Empire, under the new leadership of Gofer, the giant head.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/gradius2-image.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19880324T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Konami</developer>
		<publisher>Konami</publisher>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
		<players>2</players>
		<playcount>11</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20200229T190900</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./gradius3.zip</path>
		<name>Gradius III</name>
		<desc>In the darkest reaches of infinite space, pure evil lies in wait ... The Dark Forces led by the god of destruction, Bacterian, prepare to launch a massive onslaught against the planet Gradius. Possessing unstoppable power, the Dark Forces threaten to plunge the Universe into total war and complete annihilation.

Their invasion force smashes the Gradius defenses, and the surrounding planets soon fall like dominoes. Now Bacterian's evil grasp reaches for the heart of the resistance...planet Gradius itself...

To counter the oncoming threat the United Gradius World Forces gather all their fighter craft. Half of them form a defensive net - the other half a strike team. But they are badly outnumbered and The Dark Forces easily tear through their thin frontline. No fighters survive the slaughter....

In a last gasp move, the United Gradius World Forces send out two fighters, previously considered too dangerous for combat missions: The InterDimensional VIC VIPER fighters.

The Fighters take off for the heart of darkness to join the fray that will decide the fate of the Universe...</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/gradius3-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19891211T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Konami</developer>
		<publisher>Konami</publisher>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
		<players>2</players>
		<playcount>5</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20200229T190917</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./hypsptsp.zip</path>
		<name>Hyper Sports Special (Japan)</name>
		<playcount>1</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20200229T190952</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./joust.zip</path>
		<name>Joust</name>
		<desc>Joust is an arcade game developed by Williams Electronics and released in 1982. It is a platform game that features two-dimensional (2D) graphics. The player uses a button and joystick to control a knight riding a flying ostrich. The object is to progress through levels by defeating groups of enemy knights riding buzzards.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/joust-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19820101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Williams</developer>
		<publisher>Williams Electronic Games, Inc.</publisher>
		<genre>Action, Fighting</genre>
		<players>2</players>
		<playcount>2</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20200229T191013</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./joust2.zip</path>
		<name>Joust 2: Survival Of The Fittest</name>
		<desc>Joust 2: Survival of the Fittest is an arcade game developed by Williams Electronics and released in 1986. It is a sequel to Williams' 1982 game Joust. Like its predecessor, Joust 2 is a platform game that features two-dimensional (2D) graphics. The player uses a button and joystick to control a knight riding a flying ostrich. The object is to progress through levels by defeating groups of enemy knights riding buzzards. Joust 2 features improved audio-visuals and gameplay elements absent from the original.

The game uses more advanced hardware than the original Joust, allowing for the new elements. John Newcomer led development again, which began to create a conversion kit that allowed arcade owners to convert the cabinet into another game. Williams chose a vertically oriented screen for the kit as a result of the design's popularity at the time. Released during the waning days of the golden age of arcade games, Joust 2 did not achieve the success that Joust reached. The game was later released on home consoles as part of arcade compilations.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/joust2-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19861201T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Wiliams Electronics</developer>
		<publisher>Williams Electronic Games, Inc.</publisher>
		<genre>Action, Platform</genre>
		<players>2</players>
		<playcount>1</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20200229T191026</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./jrpacman.zip</path>
		<name>Jr. Pac-Man</name>
		<desc>The gameplay of Jr. Pac-Man is very similar to that of its predecessors: The player controls the eponymous Jr. Pac-Man (who wears an animated propeller beanie), and scores points by eating all of the Pac-Dots in the maze, while four ghosts chase him around the maze and attempt to kill him. The player can eat an energizer to turn the ghosts blue, making them vulnerable for a short period of time, and allowing the player to eat them for extra points. Once the maze is cleared, a new maze will be presented and the gameplay will continue.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/jrpacman-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19830101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Midway, Bally</developer>
		<publisher>Bally Mfg. Corp.</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<playcount>45</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20200229T193117</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./knights.zip</path>
		<name>Knights of the Round</name>
		<desc>Knights of the Round is an arcade game released by Capcom in 1991. A side-scrolling beat 'em up based loosely on the legend of King Arthur and the Knights of the Round Table, the game features an role-playing video game-like level advancement system, with fighters getting new weapons and armour as they advance through the game, however the player can not choose how to upgrade his/her character - the level up system is static.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/knights-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19910101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Capcom</developer>
		<publisher>Capcom</publisher>
		<genre>Action, Adventure, Fighting, Platform</genre>
		<players>2</players>
		<playcount>1</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20200229T191052</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./konami88.zip</path>
		<name>Konami 88</name>
		<desc>Konami '88 (also known as '88 Games or Hyper Sports Special) is the third in the Track &amp; Field game series by Konami, where you test your Olympic skills against other world-class athletes. As the name implies, it is loosely based on (and not licensed by) the 1988 Summer Olympics in Seoul, South Korea. Bronze or silver medals are not good enough - you have to go for the gold to get to the next event. However, you must at least qualify in each event in order to compete in the next event:</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/konami88-image.png</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19880201T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Konami</developer>
		<publisher>Konami</publisher>
		<genre>Sports</genre>
		<players>4</players>
		<playcount>5</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20200229T191112</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./legend.zip</path>
		<name>Legend</name>
		<desc>A top-down action-adventure game somewhat similar to The Legend of Zelda.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/legend-image.png</image>
		<releasedate>19860501T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Sega</developer>
		<genre>Role-Playing</genre>
		<playcount>2</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20200229T191138</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./lifefrce.zip</path>
		<name>Life Force</name>
		<desc>Life Force is the 1986 North American release of a Japanese game from Konami called Salamander.

More Info:
Salamander (沙羅曼蛇 / サラマンダ Saramanda?), retitled Life Force (ライフフォース Raifu Fōsu?) in North America and in the Japanese arcade re-release, is a scrolling shooter arcade game by Konami. Released in 1986 as a spin-off of Gradius, Salamander introduced a simplified power-up system, two-player cooperative gameplay and both horizontally and vertically scrolling stages. Some of these later became the norm for future Gradius games.

Gameplay:
The first player controls Vic Viper and the second player takes the reins of debuting spacecraft Lord British, which is sometimes referred to as "Road British" due to the ambiguity of Japanese-to-English romanization. The game features six stages which alter between horizontal and vertical scrolling.

Players are allowed to continue from where they leave upon death instead of being returned to a predefined checkpoint as per Gradius tradition. There are no continues in Salamander's single player mode; however, in the two-player mode, players are given two continues. The number of continues can be changed through DIP switches. The player gains power-ups by picking up capsules left behind by certain enemies, as opposed to the selection bar used in other Gradius titles. However, the Japanese version of Life Force keeps the selection bar.

Many of the power-ups can be combined. For example, an option fires a second (or third) salvo of missiles or ripple/plutonic lasers if these power-ups have been option. The ripple and laser, however, are mutually exclusive. The only power-up that can survive the ship's destruction are the options. Upon the ship's destruction, the options float in space for a brief time before disappearing; the new ship can grab and retain them if they get to them first.

Description from https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Salamander_(video_game)</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/lifefrce-image.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19860704T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Konami</developer>
		<publisher>Konami</publisher>
		<genre>Action, Shooter</genre>
		<players>2</players>
		<playcount>2</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20200229T191305</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./msword.zip</path>
		<name>Magic Sword: Heroic Fantasy</name>
		<desc>Magic Sword fully titled as Magic Sword: Heroic Fantasy, is a side-scrolling fantasy arcade game released by Capcom in 1990. The game casts the player as a hero who must fight his way through a mystical tower in order to save the world. The player can use a sword, axe or magic, and can also rescue and recruit potential allies of various character classes, each of which has his or her own special abilities. Three years earlier, Capcom had released the similar Black Tiger in 1987.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/msword-image.png</image>
		<releasedate>19900701T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Capcom</developer>
		<publisher>Capcom</publisher>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
		<players>2</players>
		<playcount>2</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20200229T191328</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./magdrop2.zip</path>
		<name>Magical Drop II</name>
		<desc>Magical Drop is played in a style and gameplay similar to Compile's (now Sega's) Puyo Puyo and Taito's Puzzle Bobble franchises; a "stack" of random colored bubbles descend from the top, and a player is defeated when a bubble hits the bottom. Bubbles can be picked up and dropped by the player's "clown" at the bottom, and are destroyed when three or more of the same color are put together on a single column. "Chains" are formed either when a single drop caused a chain reaction, or when more than one group of bubbles is destroyed in quick succession. The game is normally played with two players (one may be a computer opponent), and chains cause the opponent's stack to descend faster.

There are 24 characters, all but the Black Pierrot being named after a tarot card (although the Strength card has been represented by two characters throughout the series). Different characters have different attack patterns. The columns of the opponent's stack will descend at different rates relative to each other depending on the character chosen. This causes a disjunction of colors that may make it more difficult for the other player to clear their stack. For example, with the character Devil, all the columns will descend at the same rate, whereas with Sun, the middle columns will descend faster than the others.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/magdrop2-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19950101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Data East Corporation</developer>
		<publisher>Data East Corporation</publisher>
		<genre>Puzzle</genre>
		<players>2</players>
		<playcount>1</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20200229T191343</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./magdrop3.zip</path>
		<name>Magical Drop III</name>
		<desc>Control a clown to pull in and throw back balloons hurled from the top of the screen. If you line up three or more balloons of the same color in a vertical row, they will burst. If you're not quick enough, the balloons will squash the clown and the game is over. Once you've got the hang of bursting balloons, you'll need to master combos and chains.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/magdrop3-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19971231T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Data East Corporation</developer>
		<publisher>Data East Corporation</publisher>
		<genre>Puzzle</genre>
		<players>2</players>
		<playcount>1</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20200229T191358</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./milliped.zip</path>
		<name>Millipede</name>
		<desc>Millipede is a 1982 arcade game by Atari, Inc. and is the sequel to the arcade hit, Centipede. The objective of the game is to score as many points as possible by destroying all segments of the millipede as it moves toward the bottom of the screen, as well as destroying and avoiding other enemies. The game is played with a trackball and a single fire button, which can be held down for rapid-fire. The game is over when the player's last life is lost.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/milliped-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19820101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Atari</developer>
		<publisher>Atari, Inc.</publisher>
		<genre>Action, Shooter</genre>
		<players>2</players>
		<playcount>1</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20200229T191418</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./nbajamte.zip</path>
		<name>NBA Jam Tournament Edition</name>
		<desc>NBA JAM Tournament Edition brings you more senses-shattering slam dunking excitement than ever! More than twice as many NBA superstars, more than double the secret characters, Hot Spots, Super Jam Power-Ups, battery back-up and - OH MY - nine all-new rim-rattling slam dunks plus all the original jams! NBA JAM Tournament Edition... it's on FIRE!</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/nbajamte-image.png</image>
		<developer>Midway</developer>
		<publisher>Midway Games</publisher>
		<genre>Sports</genre>
		<players>4</players>
		<playcount>2</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20200229T203534</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./lresort.zip</path>
		<name>Last Resort</name>
		<desc>The player must guide their spacecraft across horizontally scrolling cityscapes and wastelands, disposing of hordes of enemy spacecraft (some metallic, some organic) including huge mid- and end-level guardians. Power-up pods provide the craft with a moveable drone which can be charged up and fired or locked into position and used as an extra gun or 'battering ram'/shield.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/lresort-image.png</image>
		<releasedate>19920701T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>SNK</developer>
		<publisher>SNK</publisher>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
		<players>2</players>
		<playcount>5</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20200301T160745</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./neobombe.zip</path>
		<name>Neo Bomberman</name>
		<desc>The gameplay consists of walking through maze-like areas filled with monsters with a goal of opening the gate leading to the next area. Playing as a bomberman, the player can lay bombs to destroy all of the monsters, which will subsequently open the gate. Destroying blocks in the maze may uncover useful items including remote control bombs, accelerators, hearts, and increased firing range. Neo Bomberman includes Bosses that appear after each zone. Each zone is harder than the last, some featuring new traps and level obstacles such as conveyor belts.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/neobombe-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19970101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Hudson Entertainment, Inc.</developer>
		<publisher>Hudson Entertainment, Inc.</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>2</players>
		<playcount>5</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20200301T163605</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./outrun.zip</path>
		<name>Out Run</name>
		<desc>Out Run is an arcade game released by Sega in 1986. It was designed by Yu Suzuki and developed by Sega AM2. The game was a critical and commercial success, becoming one of the best-selling video games of its time. It is notable for its pioneering hardware, graphics and music, and innovative features such as a selectable soundtrack and nonlinear gameplay.

The object of the game is to reach one of a variety of destinations against a timer. If the timer reaches zero, the game ends. The player periodically encounters checkpoints near junctions, which add time to the clock. At each junction, the player must choose one of two directions, each of which lead to different environments.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/outrun-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19860920T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>SEGA AM-2</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<genre>Racing</genre>
		<playcount>14</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20200301T191848</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./lasthope.zip</path>
		<name>Last Hope</name>
		<desc>The evil empire is rushing at light-speed across the galaxies, heading towards Mother Earth. Barely 24 hours ago, they penetrated the last defence line of our galaxy, the Arsion Laser Belt. Millions of innocent people perished in outer space colonies. 70% of our fleet was destroyed during first contact. Our intelligence has now extrapolated their arrival within six days. Conventional weapons cannot stop them. Our last hope is in your hands: The Z-42 Warpstar. Warp into their territories and destroy their leader before they reach Earth.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/lasthope-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>20110201T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>NG:DEV.TEAM</developer>
		<publisher>NG:DEV.TEAM</publisher>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
		<players>2</players>
		<playcount>18</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20200315T004711</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./nemesis.zip</path>
		<name>Nemesis</name>
		<desc>In territories outside Japan, the arcade version of Gradius was released under the title of Nemesis. The Gradius (Guradiusu, pronounced: Gra-dee-us) games, first introduced in 1985, make up a series of scrolling shooter video games published by Konami. 
     The first true Gradius game introduced the concept of the 'weapon bar'. During the game, many enemy craft leave behind icons or 'pick ups' when destroyed. Collecting one of these will shift the section cursor along the weapon bar at the bottom of the screen. The player can then select the weapon highlighted if they want it. The cursor then resets. In general, the more useful 'power ups' are towards the right hand side of the bar, so the player may decide to stock up on pickups until the better item is available. This innovation allowed for deeper tactics on the part of the player and for greater freedom of weapon choice rather than relying on the pre-determined power ups common in other games in the genre.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/nemesis-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19850501T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Konami</developer>
		<publisher>Konami</publisher>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
		<players>2</players>
		<playcount>13</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20200315T004750</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./samsho.zip</path>
		<name>Samurai Shodown</name>
		<desc>In early Japan, a man named Shiro Tokisada Amakusa preaches a heretic religion. Little does anyone know that Amakusa is really a servant of the evil Ambrosia, who took over Amakusa's body. Ambrosia wishes to shroud the world in darkness. Now, choose between 12 warriors (and 3 bonus characters) to fight for the honor of destroying Amakusa, and fulfilling a mission.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/samsho-image.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19930811T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>SNK</developer>
		<publisher>SNK</publisher>
		<genre>Fighting</genre>
		<players>2</players>
		<playcount>22</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20200506T230149</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./aburner2.zip</path>
		<name>After Burner II</name>
		<desc>The game is played from behind your Navy F-14 Tomcat as you blast oncoming fighter planes trying to bring you down.

Perform complete barrel rolls by holding left or right as your machine guns continuously fire at anything in their path. Speed up by activating your afterburners or slow down to get a lock on your target.

You also have a limited number of AIM-54 Phoenix missiles on board to use as you see fit, which can be replenished after completing a series of stages (a plane will fly overhead and automatically load them onto your F-14 Tomcat).</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/aburner2-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19871103T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Sega</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
		<playcount>7</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20200507T002702</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./alpham2.zip</path>
		<name>Alpha Mission II</name>
		<desc>Alpha Mission II (also known as ASO II: Last Guardian, its Japanese title) is a vertically scrolling full screen shoot 'em up released by SNK in 1991 for the Neo Geo arcade and home systems. It was later released for the Neo Geo CD in 1994 and for the PlayStation Portable in 2010.

The player controls a fighter spacecraft (Armored Scrum Object) and can shoot enemies in the air, bomb enemies on the ground, collect power-ups, and defeat bosses to advance levels.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/alpham2-image.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19910101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>SNK</developer>
		<publisher>SNK</publisher>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
		<players>2</players>
		<playcount>1</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20200507T001809</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./altbeast.zip</path>
		<name>Altered Beast</name>
		<desc>Altered Beast is a side scrolling, platform, beat 'em up game that puts the player in control of a centurion who had died in battle. The centurion has been raised from the dead to rescue Zeus' daughter Athena from the demon Neff. The player battles undead and demonic hordes, controlling the shapeshifting hero. He must fight through several levels in order to save the kidnapped goddess.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/altbeast-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19880801T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Sega</developer>
		<publisher>Sega</publisher>
		<genre>Action, Shooter</genre>
		<players>2</players>
		<playcount>2</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20200507T001850</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./sonicwi2.zip</path>
		<name>Aero Fighters 2</name>
		<desc>The game is played with two buttons, with the A button firing bullets from the plane and the B button launching a special bomb attack which uses a bomb from a limited stock of bombs. Power bullets can be obtained by destroying buildings and armored enemy planes. There are 2 types of Power bullets: "P" Power bullets, that increases the plane's firepower by one level, and "F" Power bullets, that increases the plane's firepower to the maximum level instantly. The maximum level only lasts for a limited amount of shots.

When certain ground enemies and buildings are destroyed, money bonuses appear which give a random amount of points each. When the player reaches the end of the stage, the player has to face a boss ship.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/sonicwi2-image.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19940101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Video System Co., Ltd.</developer>
		<publisher>Video System Co., Ltd.</publisher>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
		<players>2</players>
		<playcount>9</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20200507T013953</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./1941.zip</path>
		<name>1941: Counter Attack</name>
		<desc>The goal is to shoot down enemy airplanes and collect weapon power-ups (POW). One is only able to perform three loops per level and a bonus is awarded at the end of the level for unused loops. Player 1 uses a P-38 Lightning and Player 2 uses a Mosquito Mk IV. The game shifts from the original Pacific Front setting with that of the Western Front.

The game consists of six levels.

It was the first shoot 'em up to add +1 to the score when a continue is used.[1]</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/1941-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19900201T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Capcom</developer>
		<publisher>Capcom</publisher>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
		<players>2</players>
		<playcount>21</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20200513T205212</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./nslasher.zip</path>
		<name>Night Slashers</name>
		<desc>The dead have risen from their graves, and monsters and mutants prey upon what's left of the living. Three monster hunters have joined together, using their knowledge of the occult to slay the undead scourge.

During the course of the game, players fight through hordes of attacking zombies and mutants, as well as other enemies such as werewolves and elementals. Bosses also include monsters such as a mummy, a golem and a mad scientist. Players fight these enemies and bosses to stop the evil plans of King Zarutz from turning our planet into a worldwide kingdom for the dead.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/nslasher-image.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19931001T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Data East Corporation</developer>
		<publisher>Data East Corporation</publisher>
		<genre>Action, Fighting</genre>
		<players>3</players>
		<playcount>2</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20200513T210341</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./ssf2t.zip</path>
		<name>Super Street Fighter II Turbo</name>
		<desc>Super Street Fighter II Turbo, released in Japan as Super Street Fighter II X: Grand Master Challenge, is a competitive fighting game released for the arcades by Capcom in 1994. It is the fifth arcade installment in the Street Fighter II sub-series of Street Fighter games, following Super Street Fighter II. Like its predecessor, it ran on the CP System II hardware.

Super Turbo introduced several new play mechanics to the game system from the previous Street Fighter II installments, including the addition of powered-up Special Moves called Super Combos. It also introduced the hidden character of Akuma, who would go on to become a recurring character in later Street Fighter installments and other Capcom fighting games.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/ssf2t-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19940223T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Capcom</developer>
		<publisher>Capcom</publisher>
		<genre>Fighting</genre>
		<players>2</players>
		<playcount>1</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20200515T172143</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./maglord.zip</path>
		<name>Magician Lord</name>
		<desc>Magician Lord (マジシャンロード Majishan Roodo?), is a side-scrolling platform game developed by ADK that was released on April 26, 1990. It was a launch title for both the Neo-Geo MVS (arcade) and AES (home) systems, and was one of the pack-in games for the Neo-Geo AES. The game was re-released through the Virtual Console download service in Europe and Australia on October 26, 2007, and in North America on October 29, 2007. It was later released for the PlayStation 3 and PlayStation Portable through the PlayStation Store. It was previously included in SNK Arcade Classics Vol. 1, released for the Wii, PlayStation 2 and PlayStation Portable in North America on May 1, 2008.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/arcade/maglord-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19901001T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>SNK</developer>
		<publisher>SNK</publisher>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
		<players>2</players>
		<playcount>19</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20200515T231458</lastplayed>
	</game>
</gameList>
