<?xml version="1.0"?>
<gameList>
  <game>
    <path>/home/pi/RetroPie/roms/tg16/Blazing Lazers (U).zip</path>
    <name>Blazing Lazers</name>
    <desc>Blazing Lazers is a top-down shooter featuring 9 levels of varied and fast-paced action. The story here is the usual save-the-world variety. You must pilot your ship against 8 super-weapons and ultimately destroy the menace once and for all.

The power-up system in Blazing Lazers deserves special mention. There are four main types of weapons, and each type of weapon can be upgraded several times to produce an incredible amount of firepower. In addition, there are secondary weapons systems that provide you with shields, homing missiles, multi-fire units, or super weapon power.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Blazing Lazers (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>1</rating>
    <releasedate>19890101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Compile</developer>
    <publisher>NEC</publisher>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <players/>
    <playcount>2</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T021132</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>/home/pi/RetroPie/roms/tg16/Aero Blasters (U).zip</path>
    <name>Aero Blasters</name>
    <desc>The player controls a small craft through different levels with many enemies. Every level ends with a boss and some section speed up the gameplay, offering fast obstacle courses both horizontally and vertically scrolling. Flying orange pods release many power-ups at once, enhancing the ships with new or more powerful lasers, wing men and shields. The player can also hold the fire key to charge a blast that removes all enemy bullets from the screen and deals damage to all enemies. With an unforgiving difficulty, every hit is fatal, but the game can be continued from any points as long as there are lives and credits left. The game can be played with two players cooperatively.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Aero Blasters (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19900101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Hudson Soft</developer>
    <publisher>Kaneko</publisher>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <players>2</players>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T073751</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Panza Kick Boxing (U).zip</path>
    <name>Andre Panza Kick Boxing</name>
    <desc>Forget the movies. Forget the make-believe. This is the master, 3 time World Kick Boxing Champion Andr&#xE9; Panza, and the reality will stun you! His every move was filmed and digitized over 2 years for a devastating arsenal of kick boxing combat. Train until you're good enough. Then go to war against a friend or battle through the ranks of 8 international champions! Over 50 whirlwind punches and kicks let you customize your attack. Master new techniques during hundreds of ever-changing battles. Then put your body on the line against Panza himself for the ultimate Kick Boxing Championship!</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Panza Kick Boxing (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0.6</rating>
    <releasedate>19910101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Loriciel</developer>
    <publisher>NEC</publisher>
    <genre>Fighting</genre>
    <players>2</players>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T073926</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>/home/pi/RetroPie/roms/tg16/Ballistix (U).zip</path>
    <name>Ballistix</name>
    <desc>It's chaos in the Ballistix Stadium! You're a techno-gladiator in the wildest ballgame in the galaxy. The alien claw drops the puck. You fire balls at warp-speed, blasting it towards the enemy goal. Ricochet it off walls and bumpers. Hit a splitter and balls explode in a swarming barrage! The field changes to make each level more intense. Acid pools swallow the puck. Pitch arrows propel it. Your enemy cannons it into a tunnel and it shoots out towards your goal! Get a shield to save it! Score big to enter your name in the Hall of Fame in a nonstop Ballistix frenzy.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Ballistix (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19920101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Psygnosis</developer>
    <publisher>NEC</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <players>2</players>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T074004</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>/home/pi/RetroPie/roms/tg16/Battle Royale (U).zip</path>
    <name>Battle Royale</name>
    <desc>It's wrestling mayhem out of control! Five maniacs hit the mat in a no-holds-barred, free-for-all brawl with no rules, no refs and absolutely no mercy! Team up with friends to nail opponents. Now look out! They're coming after you! Smash 'em, bash 'em and throw 'em over the ropes! The sound is so intense you'll feel every crushing hit, every cracking bone. It's furious, non-stop action for up to five players ... a winner-take-all gang fight for survival!</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Battle Royale (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19900913T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Incredible Technologies</developer>
    <publisher>NEC</publisher>
    <genre>Sports</genre>
    <players>4+</players>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T074030</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>/home/pi/RetroPie/roms/tg16/Bloody Wolf (U).zip</path>
    <name>Bloody Wolf</name>
    <desc>Snake and Eagle, two commandos of the Bloody Wolf special forces, receive instructions from their commander to destroy the enemy's heavily armed base to rescue the President and any allies who have been reported as MIA.

Based off the 1988 arcade game, this single-player, top-down, run and gun shooter takes a nod to Contra-style gameplay, allowing one of the two mercenaries to blast their way through eight levels of enemy opposition armed with only a knife and a machine gun. 

Along the way, new weapons such as shotguns, bazookas, flash bombs and grenades grenades can be added to the arsenal, as well as health and defensive power-ups. Players can even find a motorcycle to ride in some areas, or swim through certain parts of a level.

The President and your fellow soldiers need you!</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Bloody Wolf (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19900101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Data East</developer>
    <publisher>NEC</publisher>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <players/>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T074114</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Bomberman '93 (U).zip</path>
    <name>Bomberman '93</name>
    <desc>Tension, strategy, action, excitement - Bomberman's back!

You can now battle against up to four computer-controlled maniacs by yourself for the ultimate five bomberman mode.
Choose from seven exciting new stages with loads of new power-up items like werps, conveyer belts, revolving doors and even kicking bombs!
Or for portable thrills, go head-to-head against a friend using TurboExpress for non-stop action.
The best competitive game is back, and it's more intense than ever!</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Bomberman '93 (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <releasedate>19930101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Hudson</developer>
    <publisher>TTI</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <players>4+</players>
    <playcount>2</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T074548</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Boxy Boy (U).zip</path>
    <name>Boxyboy</name>
    <desc>The player controls a worker in a warehouse. Gameplay is simple: the goal of each level is to push the crates onto specific squares marked with a yellow dot. It's very easy to get boxes trapped, so the player must carefully consider the route.

Boxyboy also features a level editor for players to create and play their own levels.

In Japan, Boxyboy is known as Sokoban World and is an official part of the Sokoban series.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Boxy Boy (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0.3</rating>
    <releasedate>19900316T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Media Rings Corporation</developer>
    <publisher>NEC Home Electronics</publisher>
    <genre>Puzzle</genre>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T074606</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Bravoman (U).zip</path>
    <name>Bravoman</name>
    <desc>The village of Nitta has been invaded by the army of Dr. Bomb, an evil scientist who is plotting to take over the world. Facing this crisis is Bravoman, who received his powers from Alpha Man to stand up against Dr. Bomb in the name of justice. The village of Nitta consists of 22 stages -- action stages that take place on the ground and shooting stages that take place underwater. Action stages use a unique control system in which the height of a jump and the distance of an attack changes depending on how long players hold down the button. Players collect the Luck Symbols that appear when they defeat enemies and give them to Lottery Man to get recovery and power-up items. Stop Dr. Bomb and bring peace to the village of Nitta and the rest of the world.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Bravoman (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19900101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Namco</developer>
    <publisher>NEC</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <players/>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T074708</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>/home/pi/RetroPie/roms/tg16/Cadash (U).zip</path>
    <name>Cadash</name>
    <desc>Arise brave warrior, our services are once again needed! Baarogue the Destroyer has kidnapped the King's only daughter, Princess Sarasa, and is now bent on universal dominance! Become a powerful Fighter, a resourceful Mage, a magic-laden Priestess, or an agile Ninja in your quest to return peace to the once-tranquil land of Deerzar! Be wary on the path to your goal! Baarogue has littered it with many foes, from the re-animated Hands of Stone to the Giant Pedra- Pods of Dokra-ri. Enlist the services of a trustworthy friend to aid you, for this quest allows two brave souls to venture forth via the Turbo Tap. You must succeed, for Baarogue's dark power grows by the second, and soon no soul will be able to halt his advance!</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Cadash (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>1</rating>
    <releasedate>19910101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Taito</developer>
    <publisher>Working Designs</publisher>
    <genre>Role-Playing</genre>
    <players>2</players>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T074740</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Champions Forever Boxing (U).zip</path>
    <name>Champions Forever Boxing</name>
    <desc>It's Ali, Foreman, Frazier, Holmes and Norton -- five of the world's greatest heavyweight boxing champs! Be them or battle them. Each has his actual physical traits and boxing style. Move and jab, or go toe-to-toe and unleash a flurry of punishing hooks, uppercuts and body shots. Protect yourself by blocking punches or clinching. Taunt opponents with showboat moves if you've got the guts. Fight exhibition matches or an entire 15-year career. Between round close-ups show each boxer's facial damage. Beat these five legends and become a Champion Forever!</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Champions Forever Boxing (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19910101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Distinctive Software</developer>
    <publisher>NEC</publisher>
    <genre>Sports</genre>
    <players>2</players>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T074850</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Taito Chase H.Q. (U).zip</path>
    <name>Chase H.Q.</name>
    <desc>The fastest, most thrilling, 3D driving game yet! Take the wheel of your turbo-charged Porsche as you and your partner go in pursuit of dangerous criminals all driving an evil array of souped-up roadsters. TURBO BOOST! Need to catch up in a hurry? Well, just one press of your Turbo Button will leave your eyes in the back of your head! Barrelling through the city streets, along the roughest of dirt tracks and through busy tunnels - if you can hold the line! The low-life can run, but they can't hide...</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Taito Chase H.Q. (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19920101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Daiei Seisakusho</developer>
    <publisher>Taito Corporation</publisher>
    <genre>Racing</genre>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T074913</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Chew Man Fu (U).zip</path>
    <name>Chew-Man-Fu</name>
    <desc>Chew-Man-Fu has gone too far! His evil curse deprives you, (and everyone else), of your beloved egg rolls and fried rice. To break his spell, roll 4 magic balls through a maze to matching colored squares. Sound easy? Hah! Chew's whole zoo is out to stop you. Prickly porcupines, wily penguins, rowdy apes and more! Use those balls to clobber 'em and smash through the walls. With 5 worlds and 550 wild rounds, the fun never stops.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Chew Man Fu (U)-image.png</image>
    <releasedate>19900101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Hudson Soft</developer>
    <publisher>NEC</publisher>
    <genre>Puzzle</genre>
    <players>2</players>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T075002</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./China Warrior (U).zip</path>
    <name>China Warrior</name>
    <desc>Boss Kara and his evil horde has captured the entire kungfu province. You are summoned - You obediently go knowing full any of Kara's bullies could no doubt put out your lights. You must face them and their specialties one by one .. then finally Kara himself. A sip of a sacred tea releases hidden powers, but will it be enough? Play it so .... a hundred million Chinese are counting on it.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/China Warrior (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0.6</rating>
    <releasedate>19871121T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Hudson</developer>
    <publisher>NEC</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T075016</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Cratermaze (U).zip</path>
    <name>Cratermaze</name>
    <desc>The evil Kublai from Zenzombie Land, has kidnapped four of your friends as you time-travelled on a magic carpet. Now you must rescue them. But run for your life! You're in a maze of monsters!

Hit them with your YOYO! Dig a hole so they'll fall in! Shoot them with your Freeze Beam! Kill them dead with your Bubble Gun! There are 60 incredible levels of action. So wear your helmet and watch your step!</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Cratermaze (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19900101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Hudson Soft</developer>
    <publisher>NEC</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T075030</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>/home/pi/RetroPie/roms/tg16/Darkwing Duck (U).zip</path>
    <name>Darkwing Duck</name>
    <desc>The kingpins of crime are at it again! The mysterious criminal organization F.O.W.L. has hatched a plan to take control of the peaceful city of St. Canard. Six of their most heinous henchmen are running rampant through the city and only the daring Darkwing Duck can bring them to justice! Join Darkwing as he explores the woods to weed out Bushroot's evil plan. Search the warehouses along the wharf for Mega Volt and pull the plug on an electrifying scheme. Track down all six of FOWL's crafty criminals and then prepare yourself as Darkwing squares off against the sinister Steelbeak in his fiendish floating fortress!</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Darkwing Duck (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19920101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Radiance Software, Interactive Designs</developer>
    <publisher>Turbo Technologies</publisher>
    <genre>Platform</genre>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T075214</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>/home/pi/RetroPie/roms/tg16/Davis Cup Tennis (U).zip</path>
    <name>Davis Cup Tennis</name>
    <desc>Challenge 32 top-seeded international pros in explosive court action, or take on your friends with tons of real playing options and a true player's view! Command an arsenal of pinpoint serves and powerful baseline passing shots. Attack the net with topspin or dropshot volleys. Then destroy your opponent's lob and morale with your overhead smash. Play singles and doubles on grass, clay, indoors or hard-court in exhibition and worldwide tournaments. Practice against the ball machine to perfect your skills for the ultimate quest, the coveted Davis Cup!</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Davis Cup Tennis (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19910101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Loriciel</developer>
    <publisher>NEC</publisher>
    <genre>Sports</genre>
    <players>4+</players>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T075423</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Dead Moon (U).zip</path>
    <name>Dead Moon</name>
    <desc>Alpha 27, the one planet in the galaxy that is fit for human habitation. For many years, the space observation system here was used for a wide range of research. One day, horrifying news arrived- a giant comet was hurtling toward the solar system, on its present course, it was going to colide with the moon. and then&#x2026;.Nothing! For some strange reason the humans and the moon seemed completely unaffected. The humans were unaware that a new nightmare had already begun. The giant comet had changed shape- it was not a comet at all, it was an alien mothership!</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Dead Moon (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19920101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Natsume</developer>
    <publisher>Natsume</publisher>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T075530</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Deep Blue (U).zip</path>
    <name>Deep Blue</name>
    <desc>You command an A.N.G.E.L. Fish Attack Sub. Your mission: rid the oceans of the evil aliens in their Undersea Palace deep in the ocean depths. On top of the water, all is calm and beautiful. But as you descend toward the Palace, you won't believe your goggles! Scaled creatures snarl. Swarms of mutant fish attack. Power up! Use the Swirl Cutter! Energy Fin full-throttle ... Fire! Fire! Fire!</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Deep Blue (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0.7</rating>
    <releasedate>19890101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Pack-in-Video</developer>
    <publisher>NEC</publisher>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <players/>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T075624</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Devil's Crush (U).zip</path>
    <name>Devil's Crush</name>
    <desc>Play video pinball that will set you on fire! Explosive graphics and demonic sound beckon you to the underworld for a devilish pinball simulation. Rebound off the She-Giant. So beautiful when she sleeps. So evil when she awakens. Burn up in the bonus rounds where dragons will roast you, skeletons will toast you and sorcerers will plan a barbecue around you. Finally, if you flip your way past them all, fight the ultimate Armageddon!</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Devil's Crush (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19900101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>NAXAT Soft</developer>
    <publisher>NEC</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T075638</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>/home/pi/RetroPie/roms/tg16/Double Dungeons (U).zip</path>
    <name>Double Dungeons</name>
    <desc>Summoned by the King, you are the last hope of a once peaceful land. Journey deep within the earth on your quest to destroy a strange, unnatural force. With new "split screen" action you and a partner can work together to uncover the mysteries of the eerie underground labyrinth and its evil inhabitants. Face the Death Crow, Pumpkin Head, and Savage Elf in over 22 levels of chilling adventure. You won't want to travel alone - and you don't have to!</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Double Dungeons (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19890101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>NCS</developer>
    <publisher>NEC</publisher>
    <genre>Role-Playing</genre>
    <players>2</players>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T075718</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Dragon Spirit (U).zip</path>
    <name>Dragon Spirit</name>
    <desc>Amur, the spirit of the dragon, lives within you. As the winged creature that breathes mega-tons of fire, your mission is revealed. Rescue Princess Alicia from Zowel, Demon of Darkness. So take to the skies and destroy enemy creatures with breath and fireballs. Add dragon heads and incredible power-ups. Confront Zowel in a Super Battle of Beasts! (Careful not to breathe on Alicia).</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Dragon Spirit (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0.6</rating>
    <releasedate>19890101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Namco</developer>
    <publisher>NEC</publisher>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T075822</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Drop Off (U).zip</path>
    <name>Drop Off</name>
    <desc>There's no waking up from this nightmare! You'll need all your nerve and strategy to get out alive! A dream of giant apples and diamonds goes berserk when they turn into deadly demons raining down on your head! You have to shoot 'em down with a steel ball. Ricochet your shots to knock 'em off in bunches! They're coming fast, and each level is more threatening than the last! Why are those skulls laughing? Shoot first and ask questions later!</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Drop Off (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19900101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Data East</developer>
    <publisher>NEC</publisher>
    <genre>Puzzle</genre>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T080003</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Order of the Griffon (U).zip</path>
    <name>Dungeons &amp; Dragons: Order of the Griffon</name>
    <desc>The Vampire has escaped and has arisen again just as the Ancient Ones predicted. The Vampire controls bands of monsters who do his destructive bidding. Using the evil Iron Ring, he bends the will of the common people in an attempt to take over the world. Even the great Radlebb Keep has been conquered by the Dark Once and been bent to his evil will.
Now, with your character in the Order of the Griffon, we have a chance to defeat the evil Vampire! World peace can be restored!</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Order of the Griffon (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19920101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Strategic Simulations, Inc.</developer>
    <publisher>Turbo Technologies, Inc.</publisher>
    <genre>Role-Playing</genre>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T080103</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Fantasy Zone (U).zip</path>
    <name>Fantasy Zone</name>
    <desc>An evil force has overcome this beautiful land of awesome colors and peaceful people. Plundering Golden Rubicom coins, your enemy is an intergalactic band of thieves. Armed with cannon and bombs, you must recover the stolen coins to buy expanded powers. But be careful! The alien Super Boss waits in ambush. Restore order for the Federation or kiss the galaxy's favorite vacation place good-bye!</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Fantasy Zone (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0.8</rating>
    <releasedate>19890101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Sega</developer>
    <publisher>NEC</publisher>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <players>2</players>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T080256</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>/home/pi/RetroPie/roms/tg16/Final Lap Twin (U).zip</path>
    <name>Final Lap Twin</name>
    <desc>Final Lap Twin is a hybrid racing/role-playing game released for the PC Engine in 1989 and the TurboGrafx-16 in 1990, as a spin-off to the 1987 arcade game Final Lap. The protagonist is on a quest to live up to the reputation of his racing-champion dad. He travels over the map, meeting small-time racers, and must race his car to earn money that he spends on upgrading his car, eventually facing the local racing champion. After beating the rest of the local racing champions in the various cities, the protagonist must go through a maze to find the final upgrades of the different parts of his car, and then face the world racing champion.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Final Lap Twin (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19890101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Nova Games Ltd.</developer>
    <publisher>NEC</publisher>
    <genre>Racing</genre>
    <players/>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T080349</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Galaga '90 (U).zip</path>
    <name>Galaga '90</name>
    <desc>Galaga is a smouldering planet that often erupts with angry mutants and misfits. As Galactic commander of the Federal Army, you have the job of making them dead. Not easy! Because they come at you in clusters like swarms of killer bees. This time, you will be flying the awesome Triple Proton Fighter that warps to new dimensions and increased firepower. Galaga goons, your graveyard awaits.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Galaga '90 (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19890703T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Namco</developer>
    <publisher>NEC</publisher>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T080443</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Gekisha Boy (J) [T+Eng].zip</path>
    <name>Gekibo: Gekisha Boy</name>
    <desc>David Goldman is an amateur photographer, who always loved to take pictures. One day, he went to Los Angeles Photography School to study more about taking pictures. Everyday, David commutes on the crowded trains, but trained and learned better in the academy so he can achieve his dreams on becoming the best photographer he ever wished for. He was happy at that time, but suddenly misfortune hit him. David's parents suddenly died in a plane crash, leaving him orphaned and all alone. He loved his parents deeply and cried at their burial, thinking that they will come back. David lost his confidence and is about to leave the academy to live a lonely and sad life. However for Dean, the principal of the academy saw him and made an unexpected proposal to him. The principal said if he completed 8 tests by taking 8 special photograph shots in 8 different locations, then he's allowed to graduate in the academy. Unsure about this offer, David still accepted the test and did everything he could to pass.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Gekisha Boy (J) [T+Eng]-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19921002T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Tomcat System</developer>
    <publisher>Irem</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T080527</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>/home/pi/RetroPie/roms/tg16/Ghost Manor (U).zip</path>
    <name>Ghost Manor</name>
    <desc>With an earth-shattering explosion, horror from another dimension grips your once peaceful town. Gristly creatures prey on the innocent. The dead rise to roam the streets. All resistance falls! But hey, no problem, you have a plan! Find the secret passage to their mansion stronghold and battle past the zombies and ghouls. Now get your axe, because it's way full of demons and ghastly surprises! Ride the awesome Skull Slammer and search for their leader, the hideous Orb gamut. Discover his weakness and be a hero. If you don't, you'll be dust.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Ghost Manor (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19920101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>ICOM Simulations</developer>
    <publisher>Turbo Technologies, Inc.</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <players/>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T080613</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>/home/pi/RetroPie/roms/tg16/Gunboat (U).zip</path>
    <name>Gunboat</name>
    <desc>Twist down treacherous jungle waters with eight tons of firepower and the threat of a deadly ambush around every bend. Command a Navy River Patrol Boat (PBR) in the most hostile and claustrophobic action -- riverine warfare! First hone your critical combat skills with gunnery, grenade and pilot practice. Then report for duty and equip your boat with the hottest weaponry for the mission. Take out enemy craft with twin armor-piercing .50 caliber machine guns. Blast land-based positions with 40mm grenades or fire your 60mm Mortar Launcher and get ready to hit the deck!</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Gunboat (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19920101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Accolade</developer>
    <publisher>NEC</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <players/>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T080713</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Side Arms - Hyper Dyne (U).zip</path>
    <name>Hyper Dyne: Sidearms</name>
    <desc>Sidearms is a side-scrolling shooter arcade title developed by Capcom, ported by NEC Avenue and published by NEC Interchannel, which was released in 1989. It is the US version of Japan's Hyper Dyne: SideArms. There is also an enhanced CD version, Hyper Dyne: SideArms Special. The arcade version allows 2 simultaneous players.
The spelling of the US title can be verified inside the cover of the US game manual, it is simply 'Sidearms'.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Side Arms - Hyper Dyne (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0.8</rating>
    <releasedate>19890101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Radiance Software, Capcom</developer>
    <publisher>NEC</publisher>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T080907</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>/home/pi/RetroPie/roms/tg16/Impossamole (U).zip</path>
    <name>Impossamole</name>
    <desc>For Monty Mole, a day at the beach turns into the adventure of his life when he's beamed aboard an alien spacecraft. He's transformed into Impossamole, with super powers to save their planet from the evil Vlarg! Now you're up to your cape in Vlarg's monster bosses with crack-up creatures ready to nail your tail! Power up your laser to blast the Dragon Boss. Bomb the Abominable Snowman. Then trash the Venus Moletrap before he has you for lunch. Swim, fly and blast through five wacky action-packed worlds. The fiendish Vlarg awaits your final desperate battle!</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Impossamole (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19910101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Gremlin Interactive Limited</developer>
    <publisher>NEC</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <players/>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T081007</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./J.J. &amp; Jeff (U).zip</path>
    <name>J.J. &amp; Jeff</name>
    <desc>You can be J.J. Or you can be Jeff. Either way, you're a wacko detective on a kidnap case who stumbles into some hilarious action. Clues and surprises pop up everywhere. Use your head, your foot (kicking things brings great results) and your secret weapon - the spray-can - on 30 different enemies. So grab some french fries for energy and get ready for action!

J.J. &amp; Jeff Detective Agency are assigned the task of locating a missing rich man, and you can choose either J.J. or Jeff to go on the mission. Your partner doesn't like this one bit, so he decides to make a nuisance of himself along the way. Similar to Adventure Island, you must make your way through several levels, destroying wildlife along the way, but instead of using a hammer, you have three different ways to kill them: jump on or kick them, or when they are walking on the ground, blow gas out of them.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/J.J. &amp; Jeff (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0.8</rating>
    <releasedate>19901130T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Hudson Soft</developer>
    <publisher>Hudson Soft</publisher>
    <genre>Platform</genre>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T081104</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Jack Nicklaus' Turbo Golf (U).zip</path>
    <name>Jack Nicklaus Turbo Golf</name>
    <desc>"I designed my golf game with one goal in mind - to create the most realistic simulation of championship golf in the world. Tee to green, it offers the most breathtaking scenery available. And I've made sure that there's variety and challenge built into every hole. It's my mind of golf - uncompromising. And I know you'll enjoy it as much as I do."

-Play against a computerized Jack Nicklaus
-Play in a foursome. Chose men or women oppopnents
-Play the Australian Golf Club, home of the Australian Open</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Jack Nicklaus' Turbo Golf (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19900101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Accolade</developer>
    <publisher>Victor Interactive Software</publisher>
    <genre>Sports</genre>
    <players/>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T081200</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Jackie Chan's Action Kung Fu (U).zip</path>
    <name>Jackie Chan's Action Kung Fu</name>
    <desc>Jackie and his sister, Josephine, are tough on tyrants. As China's supreme kung fu champs, they guard their country against the Prince of Sorcerers, who lurks just beyond the Great Wall. It comes as no surprise when this fiend and his ghouls try yet again to seize China for themselves. But this time they're clever, casting a spell over Josephine which causes her to vanish into thin air! Jackie is in shock! How can he save his country without his sister? The two have been an unbeatable team! Meanwhile, a demon horde led by the Sorcerer storms the Great Wall and prepares to establish a fierce empire. At the urging of his revered Master, Jackie must now battle the dreaded Sorcerer and rescue Josephine. Maybe he can learn a little magic on his own, because he's going to need all the help he can get!</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Jackie Chan's Action Kung Fu (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19910118T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Hudson</developer>
    <publisher>NEC</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T081248</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Keith Courage in Alpha Zones (U).zip</path>
    <name>Keith Courage in Alpha Zones</name>
    <desc>Now the Battle is in Your Hands.

You are Keith Courage. Struck by a giant meteor, the world has been invaded by strange creatures from another planet. Burrowing deep within the Earth's surface, the Planet of B.A.D. (Beastly Alien Dudes) seeks to take over the world. As a member of N.I.C.E. (Nations of International Citizens for Earth), your mission is to defeat B.A.D. and bring peace back to the world.

Armed only with a sword, you must first defeat the outpost guards. Then, enter the Underworld. Here you activate the awesome Nova Suit. A secret force left to you by your fallen father, you are half man, half mechanical monster. Nearly invincible, your sword cracks with the power of lightning, as you wreak havoc on the fearsome Dudes. Your goal is to reach the Robo Zone (the seventh Alpha Zone), headquarters of B.A.D. Succeed here and you will have won the game, recapturing the Earth and restoring humanity's place in the universe. You have help along the way. Four friends offer you advice, swords, bombs, and extra lives. Collect the stolen riches left behind by the invaders and buy your way out of trouble with money.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Keith Courage in Alpha Zones (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0.7</rating>
    <releasedate>19890101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Hudson</developer>
    <publisher>NEC</publisher>
    <genre>Platform</genre>
    <players/>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T081332</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./King of Casino (U).zip</path>
    <name>King Of Casino</name>
    <desc>The chips are down as you and your buddies travel to Vegas in this high stakes adventure. Match wits (and luck!) against the house or up to four of your friends in a game with all the glitz and glamor of a real casino. Play Poker, Blackjack, slot machines, Keno or Roulette. Choose one of 15 different casinos. You're the odds-on favorite in this high-rolling gambling simulation.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/King of Casino (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19900101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Victor Musical Industries</developer>
    <publisher>NEC</publisher>
    <genre>Strategy</genre>
    <players/>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T081347</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Klax (U).zip</path>
    <name>Klax</name>
    <desc>KLAX - It's simple in concept and easy to play. Catch the colored tiles with the paddle and flip them into bins to make same colored stacks, diagonals and rows of three. Sounds easy? It is. The hard part is pulling yourself away from this fun and addictive game!</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Klax (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19900101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Tengen</developer>
    <publisher>Tengen</publisher>
    <genre>Puzzle</genre>
    <players/>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T081445</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>/home/pi/RetroPie/roms/tg16/Legend of Hero Tonma (U).zip</path>
    <name>Legend of Hero Tonma</name>
    <desc>An Irem Arcade side-scrolling platformer, featuring the titular hero Tonma. His main weapon is a fireball that can be upgraded multiple times.

Legend of Hero Tonma is a 1989 Irem Arcade platformer, known for its difficulty, brightly colored graphics and its rarity in the US. The game was converted to the TurboGrafx-16 in 1993 (based on the 1991 PC Engine version) making it one of the last games to be released for the system in the US.

The game is graphically similar to Wonder Boy, but is also structured similarly to Ghouls n' Ghosts. The player must pass through areas filled with enemies, trying to survive long enough to upgrade their fireballs to the point where it becomes far easier to cope.

Legend of Hero Tonma is an action game that puts players in control of the magic-user Tonma, whose role &#x2013; as was typical for game heroes of the day &#x2013; is to travel to another world and save the princess. Fight your way through seven stages using Tonma&#x2019;s jump ability and shot power. Collect power-ups and barriers to grow in strength and pummel your enemies. Bring that strength to the end of each stage to face off against and defeat the menacing bosses that aim to keep you from the princess.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Legend of Hero Tonma (U)-image.png</image>
    <releasedate>19930101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Irem</developer>
    <publisher>NEC</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <players/>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T081540</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Magical Chase (U) [!].zip</path>
    <name>Magical Chase</name>
    <desc>Ripple is a student of magic, and her teacher is a terrifying witch. Ripple is particularly afraid of her teacher right now, because she's just broken a promise she made to the witch: Ripple took a peek inside the forbidden book Sleeping Demons! No sooner had she opened the cover then out jumped six demons, all of which raced away! Unless she can catch all six demons and get them back inside the book, the witch will turn Ripple into a frog for breaking her promise! So Ripple sets off on her quest with her two Elf-Star friends, Topsy and Turvy. Good luck, Ripple!</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Magical Chase (U) [!]-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19911115T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Palsoft</developer>
    <publisher>Quest</publisher>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T081804</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>/home/pi/RetroPie/roms/tg16/Military Madness (U).zip</path>
    <name>Military Madness</name>
    <desc>Space on Earth has become limited, and mankind has looked to colonize the moon. A group known as the Axis Powers has seized control over most of the lunar surface, and it's up to you as a member of the Allied Powers to fight against them. As you move around the map (shown in a top-down 2D perspective), enemy combatants will try and stop you from achieving your goal. Once encountered, the screen shifts view points to a close-up view of the skirmish at hand.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Military Madness (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>1</rating>
    <releasedate>19890101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Hudson Soft</developer>
    <publisher>Hudson Soft</publisher>
    <genre>Strategy</genre>
    <players/>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T081854</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Moto Roader (U).zip</path>
    <name>MOTO ROADER II</name>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Moto Roader (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <developer/>
    <publisher>NCS</publisher>
    <genre>Racing</genre>
    <players/>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T081949</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>/home/pi/RetroPie/roms/tg16/Neutopia (U).zip</path>
    <name>Neutopia</name>
    <desc>You are Jazeta, a berserker warrior, fearless in combat. Now you face your greatest quest: to rescue Princess Aurora from the evil Boss Dirth. Conquer a dangerous land of dungeons and demons, magic and monks. Choose which armor, what spell, which weapon you will use to capture each of the 8 medallions that bring you closer and closer to your final battle with demonic Dirth.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Neutopia (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0.9</rating>
    <releasedate>19891117T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Hudson</developer>
    <publisher>NEC</publisher>
    <genre>Role-Playing</genre>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T082036</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Neutopia II (U).zip</path>
    <name>Neutopia II</name>
    <desc>Jazeta brought peace back to the land. But as long as evil and fear live in the human heart, the dreaded Dirth, Emperor of Darkness, will be plotting his return. The Emperor is stirring under the peaceful surface of Neutopia, bringing suffering to its people. Who will save them? Jazeta, the hero, is lost in a labyrinth in a foreign land. Can his son withstand the powers of the Emperor of Darkness to rescue the good people of Neutopia from fear and despair?</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Neutopia II (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <releasedate>19910927T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Hudson</developer>
    <publisher>NEC</publisher>
    <genre>Role-Playing</genre>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T082140</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./New Adventure Island (U).zip</path>
    <name>New Adventure Island</name>
    <desc>The adventure begins on peaceful Adventure Island. Today, Master Higgins weds Tina, the new 'Miss Island&#x201C;. Everyone is assembled at the church to celebrate their wedding when, suddenly, the evil Baron Bronsky appears. He wants to marry Tina himself. The evil baron carries Tina off, along with six island children. To reach his castle and rescue Tina, Master Higgins must first rescue the six children, each of whom is hidden on a separate island. You are Master Higgins. Will you be able to save her?</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/New Adventure Island (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19920626T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Hudson</developer>
    <publisher>Hudson</publisher>
    <genre>Platform</genre>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T082228</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>/home/pi/RetroPie/roms/tg16/Night Creatures (U).zip</path>
    <name>Night Creatures</name>
    <desc>Hecate, the Queen of Darkness, has feasted on your blood. Now you must destroy her or be hers forever, one of the Walking Undead. Hecate's bite has given you the power to change into a wolf, a bear, and other animals to battle hordes of monsters and ghouls who protect her. You must search for the one correct route through level after level of unspeakable terror to find her. Choose the most devastating weapons and become the animal best able to fight each fiend. Will you defeat Hecate or become her grotesque slave for eternity? Either way, the Queen of Darkness waits for you!</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Night Creatures (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19920410T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Manley and Associates</developer>
    <publisher>NEC</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T082315</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Ninja Spirit (U).zip</path>
    <name>Ninja Spirit</name>
    <desc>Play as the ninja Moonlight and engage in a fierce battle to avenge his father's death and unlock the secrets of his birth. Select between the original Arcade Mode and PC-Engine MODE, which includes a life gauge. Use four types of weapons: katana, shuriken, bombs and chain and sickles to battle your way through the enemies. Pick up power-up items and switch between weapons to give you the advantage. You'll need to consider the enemy attacks and your weapon's abilities in order to deftly make it through all seven stages. Use your skills and attacks to get through the game's boundless enemies and traps. That's what ninja action is all about.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Ninja Spirit (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19900101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Hudson</developer>
    <publisher>NEC</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T082416</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Ordyne (U).zip</path>
    <name>Ordyne</name>
    <desc>The evil Kubota has kidnapped Dr. Tomari's fiancee, Kana, and taken the colossal nuclear reactor Ordyne. In order to reclaim them, Dr. Tomari and his assistant Felix take to their battleships and head off in pursuit. Avoid enemies and advance through seven different levels that take place on land, sea, and air. Collect crystals from defeated enemies and use them to buy items or upgrades for your ship at the Space Inn. Do you have what it takes to defeat the boss at the end of each level and ultimately reach Kubota in the final stage, Kubota World?</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Ordyne (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0.9</rating>
    <releasedate>19900101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Namco</developer>
    <publisher>NEC</publisher>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <players/>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T082502</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>/home/pi/RetroPie/roms/tg16/Pac-Land (U).zip</path>
    <name>Pac-Land</name>
    <desc>In Pac-Land, our friend Pac-Man is facing more daring adventures than ever before! In his new contest, Pac-Man comes face-to-face with ghosts on their own turf. In this 2D platforming adventure, his quiet day at home is disturbed by those nasty specters. A fairy princess has been kidnapped, and Pac-Man must leap over rivers, avoid dangerous water spouts, fly in magic shoes, dodge the Hoppers from the bushes, skip past the skulls aiming to drag you to Sand Prison -- all in the aims of reaching Monster Mansion and rescuing the princess to restore peace in Pac-Land!</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Pac-Land (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0.5</rating>
    <releasedate>19900101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Namco</developer>
    <publisher>Namco</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <players>2</players>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T082549</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Parasol Stars - The Story of Bubble Bobble III (U).zip</path>
    <name>Parasol Stars: The Story of Bubble Bobble III</name>
    <desc>Break out the bandages and get ready for some finger-searing action! Join Bubby on his latest quest to save the universe, this time with a Magic Umbrella. Umbrella!? Yes, Umbrella! This powerful parasol puts the elements themselves at your command! Shock the tonnage out of the whales with Lightning! Fry the feathers off the crazed, beady-eyed birds with Fire! Or, drown the demented dinosaurs with a tidal wave of Raindrops! Need help? Your buddy Bobby is always nearby. Have a friend plug into your TurboTap and blast into two player simultaneous play. Be prepared for a quest that will take you to eight amazing planets, forcing you to uncover the secret that will unleash the Parasol Stars!

Parasol Stars is the third game in the Bubble Bobble franchise (and is often labeled "Parasol Stars: The Story Bubble Bobble III"), as well as a semi-official sequel to the second Bubble Bobble spin-off, Rainbow Island.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Parasol Stars - The Story of Bubble Bobble III (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19910115T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Taito</developer>
    <publisher>NEC</publisher>
    <genre>Platform</genre>
    <players>2</players>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T082648</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Power Golf (U).zip</path>
    <name>Power Golf</name>
    <desc>Swing away on 18 lush holes, enter tournaments and compete to win. Keep your head down and concentrate. Release a ton of power coming out of your backswing -- like a coiled spring! Follow through. You'll need a picture-perfect swing, flawless timing and a pro's club selection. Why, you ask? Because this is real. The traps are real, the water is real, the ball is real, and your score is real.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Power Golf (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19890101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Hudson</developer>
    <publisher>NEC</publisher>
    <genre>Sports</genre>
    <players/>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T082736</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Psychosis (U).zip</path>
    <name>Psychosis</name>
    <desc>This is a side-scrolling shooter played in a world created from the mind of a twisted demon. Your soul has suddenly wandered into that evil world that exists in every person's heart. The only way out is to blast your way past the grotesque creatures that block your path in five "causes" (stages). You must face the dangers of this psychedelic world by making full use of three shot types and the satellite option. With power-ups, you can change your shots to a wide-coverage beam, a satellite-generated laser and more. Each shot type can be powered up to three levels. You can also block enemy fire by rotating the satellites to a desired position. How you use these features will be the key to successfully escaping this strange and surreal world</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Psychosis (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19900101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Naxat Soft</developer>
    <publisher>NEC</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <players/>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T082820</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>/home/pi/RetroPie/roms/tg16/R-Type (U).zip</path>
    <name>R-Type</name>
    <desc>A desperate battle is being fought out in the limitless and unknown dimensions of space which have been contaminated and corrupted by an evil power. The evil power is the Bydo Empire, which is determined to subjugate the world. It is inhabited by weird creatures, whose very sight inspires fear. But mankind is fighting back, and sends you into battle in an incredibly sophisticated plane, the R-9 fighter. Behind the control panel of this fantastic fighting machine, you are Mankind's only defence against the enemy.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/R-Type (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>1</rating>
    <releasedate>19890101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Irem</developer>
    <publisher>NEC</publisher>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <players/>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T082913</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Raiden (U).zip</path>
    <name>Raiden</name>
    <desc>Go ballistic with intense arcade action! The year is 2090 and it could be our last. Alien invaders are scorching the earth with vastly superior firepower. Our only hope is Raiden, an untested supersonic fighter built with captured enemy technology, and only you are ace enough to handle it! Power up your laser for deadly accuracy or wide shots of lethal fire! Zero in with your homing missiles. Then nuke those fiends deep into space! You're on their turf now. Blast 'em and return victorious or they'll be back to finish us off!</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Raiden (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19910101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Hudson Soft</developer>
    <publisher>NEC</publisher>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <players/>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T083003</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Samurai Ghost (U).zip</path>
    <name>Samurai-Ghost</name>
    <desc>This action platformer features a samurai ghost from the depths of the underworld. In a past war, Kagekiyo managed to defeat the shogun Yoritomo and his clan. However, their evil spirits were not completely destroyed, and now, in the world known as Dark Side, they seek the time of their rebirth. In order to shatter those ambitions, Kagekiyo must make his way across seven zones and head for "The Heart of the Darkside" where Yoritomo lies in wait. Use spirit weapons to power up your sword, or other items, such as candles to recover health, and defeat the endless hordes of enemies. Each zone is not only protected by a boss but also includes demons as well as real samurai from 12th-century Japan. Get ready for some intense one-on-one combat action.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Samurai Ghost (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19920101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Now Production</developer>
    <publisher>Namco</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <players/>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T083025</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Shanghai (J) [T+Eng].zip</path>
    <name>Shanghai</name>
    <desc>AKA: &#x4E0A;&#x6D77;. A Mahjong matching game.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Shanghai (J) [T+Eng]-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19871030T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Hudson / Activision</developer>
    <publisher>Hudson</publisher>
    <genre>Puzzle</genre>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T083104</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./ShockMan (U).zip</path>
    <name>Shockman</name>
    <desc>It's been two years since Arnold and Sonya were made into Shockmen. A message from the professor to return to their bodies has them head to his laboratory, but they are ambushed by a mysterious enemy along the way. After narrowly defeating the enemy, they catch a TV news flash announcing the Ryo Empire invasion. They find that the professor has been abducted and set out to rescue him.

Shockman is a side-view action shooter that has eight stages, including Action Stages, where you jump and use special techniques, and side-scrolling Shooting Stages. This game expands on the well-paced story from the previous version and contains cooperative elements like shared life and a powerful Team Shockbeam that can be used during two-player simultaneous play.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/ShockMan (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19920101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Hudson Soft</developer>
    <publisher>NCS</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <players/>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T083145</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>/home/pi/RetroPie/roms/tg16/Silent Debuggers (U).zip</path>
    <name>Silent Debuggers</name>
    <desc>Make your way through a dungeon-like space station and defeat the prowling monsters in this real-time first-person shooter. You're a member of the elite Debuggers, a group of warriors who are jacks-of- all-trades. Assigned to inspect an unmanned space station, you have exactly 100 minutes to get in, destroy the monsters lurking in each block, make your way to the lowest level and deactivate the automatic detonator placed there. With each monster that slips by you, the core block becomes harder to survive in, so speed is key in preserving the facility and each separate block. Experience the thrill of survival as the timer ticks away and you uncover the truth of the events that occurred.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Silent Debuggers (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19910101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Data East</developer>
    <publisher>NEC</publisher>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <players/>
    <playcount>2</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T083338</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Sinistron (U).zip</path>
    <name>Sinistron</name>
    <desc>Scramble Mode Zeta; A message to Cybernaut Squadron Calisto -- Priority Alpha-San 03... An intersystem intruder has been detected in quadrant FTU-770. Dronecraft sent to get a visual discovered an extremely large monolith, biomorphic in nature. All attempts at contact ended in destruction of drones. Your mission: locate, intercept and enter the Sinistron. Use any means to destroy it!</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Sinistron (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19910101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Alpha System</developer>
    <publisher>IGS</publisher>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <players/>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T083528</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Soldier Blade (U).zip</path>
    <name>Soldier Blade</name>
    <desc>Vertical sci-fi shoot &#x2018;em up from the Hudson stable. Soldier Blade sticks to the tried and tested formula of Hudson&#x2019;s previous games in the 'series', while throwing in some extra graphical effects. This time, the power up system involves collecting coloured pods - you can have three pods in stock at any one time, and the colour of the 'active' pod determines your weapon style. You also have the choice of ejecting a pod at any time, which results in a weapon-specific super attack.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Soldier Blade (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19920101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Hudson</developer>
    <publisher>NEC</publisher>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T083624</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Somer Assault (U).zip</path>
    <name>Somer Assault</name>
    <desc>Here begins the story from a time and a world not our own ... A sorceress used her evil powers to fulfill her conquest to rule the world. "Go my dead slaves to trample and rule the world which will belong to us!" You are the only one who can crush her wretched plans! Each stage is controlled by a boss who portrays a sign of the zodiac. Going through a maze, you have to find and destroy the boss before your time runs out. Save the world!</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Somer Assault (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19920101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Atlus U.S.A., Inc.</developer>
    <publisher>Atlus U.S.A., Inc.</publisher>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <players/>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T083723</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Sonic Spike - World Championship Beach Volleyball (U).zip</path>
    <name>Sonic Spike</name>
    <desc>The action sizzles in Sonic Spike, on the front line of the world's most brutal volleyball game. Blast the ball over the net -- bump, spike, dig, jump, and even quick-fake a return. Orbital lobs soar to the sun; earth-pounding spikes vibrate the ground. Score ... or eat sand! Select and create your own teams from 24 athletes pulled from six nations. Pit gals against guys in a battle of the sexes, or fight the competition of the century with Japan, Australia, Brazil, USA or USSR.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Sonic Spike - World Championship Beach Volleyball (U)-image.png</image>
    <releasedate>19900727T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>IGS</developer>
    <publisher>IGS</publisher>
    <genre>Sports</genre>
    <players>2</players>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T083811</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Son Son II (J) [T+Eng].zip</path>
    <name>SonSon II</name>
    <desc>Cute platformer based on the Chinese Legend of The Monkey King.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Son Son II (J) [T+Eng]-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19890127T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Capcom</developer>
    <publisher>Capcom</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T083835</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Splatterhouse (U).zip</path>
    <name>Splatterhouse</name>
    <desc>Two college students, Rick Taylor and Jennifer Willis, take refuge from a storm in West Mansion, a local landmark known as "Splatterhouse" for the rumors of hideous experiments purportedly conducted there by Dr. West, a renowned and missing parapsychologist. At the mansion, the two are attacked by demonic creatures that drag Jennifer inside and fatally wound Rick, leaving him for dead.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Splatterhouse (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0.9</rating>
    <releasedate>19900101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Namco</developer>
    <publisher>NEC</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T084039</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Super Star Soldier (U).zip</path>
    <name>Super Star Soldier</name>
    <desc>Move fast and blast! It's a nonstop explosion of fire power and you're streaking through space, right in the middle of it! The Brains Cult you once defeated is back, badder than ever. But your finger's on the trigger of an incredible new techno-attack! Scorch the Scorpion with a nuclear a sting. Fire your heat-seeking sidewinders. Then power-up to launch your doomsday Super Bomb! Blow those Brains out and save the galaxy. Then challenge your friends with a special competition time mode to prove who the Super Star really is!</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Super Star Soldier (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19900706T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Inter State</developer>
    <publisher>NEC</publisher>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T084124</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Takin' It to the Hoop (U).zip</path>
    <name>Takin' it to the Hoop</name>
    <desc>You're a high-scoring point guard capable of awesome vertical leaps and hangtime. Matter of fact, you can do it all! Dribble. Bounce-pass. Fake. Pivot. Jump. Shoot. Play Man or Zone. Drive the lane -- is the defender all over you? Give him a move and jam, slam in his face!</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Takin' It to the Hoop (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19900101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Alcom</developer>
    <publisher>NEC</publisher>
    <genre>Sports</genre>
    <players>2</players>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T084213</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>/home/pi/RetroPie/roms/tg16/TaleSpin (U).zip</path>
    <name>TaleSpin</name>
    <desc>Take off with those high-flying Disney heroes, Captain Baloo and Kit Cloudkicker in the action-packed adventure TaleSpin. Imagine, you're after the lost treasure of Ionia, and the Watusi Witch Doctor is after you! Can you defeat him to go on and defy the dreaded Iron Vulture and make it to the Ice Caves of Thembria? Are you brave enough to challenge Shere Khan for the treasure? Find out by playing TaleSpin, with seven thrilling levels and 150 danger-filled screens!</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/TaleSpin (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19911025T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Radiance Software</developer>
    <publisher>NEC</publisher>
    <genre>Platform</genre>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T084303</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Legendary Axe, The (U).zip</path>
    <name>The Legendary Axe</name>
    <desc>You are Gogan, a muscular powerhouse with enough guts to enter the Pits of Madness. Your mission: rescue the beautiful red-haired Flare. You are strong, but you also have Sting, a sacred axe to help you battle strange creatures and the savage cult of Jagu, fighting through mountain, jungle and cave environments to reach the lovely maiden.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Legendary Axe, The (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>1</rating>
    <releasedate>19890101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Atlus</developer>
    <publisher>NEC</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <players/>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T084401</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Legendary Axe II, The (U).zip</path>
    <name>The Legendary Axe II</name>
    <desc>The Axe is back ... with twice the force and twice the fury of 1988's classic TurboGrafx-16 videogame. This time it's brother against brother, locked in deadly combat. Your older brother has summoned forces of unspeakable evil to take control of the kingdom. Treachery rules! Your only hope is the legendary royal sword. But will its power be enough to overcome the Cliffs of Chaos? The Skull Dungeon? And the treacherous Crypts of Slime? Only your courage, your fighting skill, and the Legendary Axe can answer that challenge!</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Legendary Axe II, The (U)-image.png</image>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <releasedate>19900101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Atlus</developer>
    <publisher>NEC</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <players/>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T084453</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Time Cruise (U).zip</path>
    <name>Time Cruise</name>
    <desc>Time Cruise is a futuristic pinball game, developed by Sankindo and published by Face, which was released in 1992.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Time Cruise (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19920101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Sankindo</developer>
    <publisher>FACE</publisher>
    <genre>Sports</genre>
    <players/>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T084637</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>/home/pi/RetroPie/roms/tg16/Timeball (U).zip</path>
    <name>Timeball</name>
    <desc>Get wrapped up in this mind-bending game that will test your mental agility. The action seems simple -- just keep a ball rolling through a winding maze by shifting around pieces of tubing. But the action is intense! Race against time and the track to keep the ball from crashing. There are 100 challenging levels -- plus the unique edit feature lets you build your own puzzles!</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Timeball (U)-image.png</image>
    <releasedate>19900101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Hudson Soft</developer>
    <publisher>NEC</publisher>
    <genre>Puzzle</genre>
    <players/>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T084710</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>/home/pi/RetroPie/roms/tg16/Tricky Kick (U).zip</path>
    <name>Tricky Kick</name>
    <desc>Flex your thumbs and tease your brain! TRICKY KICK takes brain teasing puzzle gaming into the next dimension. Six different Heroes, trapped in a mixed-up, matched-up world of obstacles, baffle their way through hostile hazards. Weave your way through 120 levels of mind-bending possibilities where wild animals, robots, spooks, and trolls try to keep you from your goal. Designed for puzzlers of all ages, TRICKY KICK will quickly become a game you'll find hard to quit.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Tricky Kick (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19900101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Information Global Services, Inc.</developer>
    <publisher>NEC</publisher>
    <genre>Puzzle</genre>
    <playcount>2</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T084848</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>/home/pi/RetroPie/roms/tg16/TV Sports Basketball (U).zip</path>
    <name>TV Sports Basketball</name>
    <desc>The arena's rockin'. Network cameras are rollin'. It's showtime! Here's ultra-real pro roundball that puts you right on the floor with an awesome on-the-court view and total control. Set your offense. Use your screen to nail a three-pointer. Roll off your pick to hit the jumper. Or post up in the paint and power slam with one second left on the shot clock! Now turn up the heat on defense. Trap and go for the steal! Do it all in the only game for up to five players with action more real than you've ever seen!</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/TV Sports Basketball (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19910101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Cinemaware Corporation</developer>
    <publisher>NEC</publisher>
    <genre>Sports</genre>
    <players>4+</players>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T085015</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>/home/pi/RetroPie/roms/tg16/TV Sports Football (U).zip</path>
    <name>TV Sports Football</name>
    <desc>The crowd's roaring. TV cameras are rolling. You're in a pro football war more real than you've ever played. Digitized sound lets you feel every bone-crunching hit. Call all the plays and audibles. Then control a sophisticated offense and slashing, head-bashing defense as TV announcers broadcast the game. It's fast, furious action for up to 5 players! Battle through a full season schedule to the League Championship!</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/TV Sports Football (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19901225T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Cinemaware</developer>
    <publisher>NEC</publisher>
    <genre>Sports</genre>
    <players>4+</players>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T085148</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>/home/pi/RetroPie/roms/tg16/TV Sports Hockey (U).zip</path>
    <name>TV Sports Hockey</name>
    <desc>The stadium organ is pumping as you faceoff against international competition. Play any position, even goalie, with total control. Experience all the stick handling, slap shots, body checks and fisticuffs of world class hockey. Make strategic goalie and line changes. If their goon slams you into the boards, drop your gloves and duke it out. Now you're flying down the ice on a power play. You wind up and crank a high, blazing slap shot, but their goalie's reaching up and...Welcome to World War III, hockey style!</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/TV Sports Hockey (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19910101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Cinemaware Corporation</developer>
    <publisher>NEC</publisher>
    <genre>Sports</genre>
    <players>4+</players>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T085232</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Veigues Tactical Gladiator (U).zip</path>
    <name>Veigues Tactical Gladiator</name>
    <desc>For 3 years, alien invaders have been pounding the earth into a smoldering ruin. There isn't a man alive who can stop them. But now, there's Veigues, a devastating fighting machine! Built with captured enemy technology, he's our last desperate hope for survival ... and you're in control! Trash the invaders with the Plazma Cannon! Just keep your firepower hot and fight like there's no tomorrow. Destroy the aliens or there won't be!.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Veigues Tactical Gladiator (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0.5</rating>
    <releasedate>19900101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Victor Musical Industries</developer>
    <publisher>NEC</publisher>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T085355</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>/home/pi/RetroPie/roms/tg16/Victory Run (U).zip</path>
    <name>Victory Run</name>
    <desc>Strap on this red turbo-charged beauty and punch it. Barrel through the streets of night-time Paris. Lean into the rolling countryside curves. Sweat the hot Sahara straightaway. The famous Paris to Dakar Road Rally tests driving skills, reaction time and your knowledge of the needs of your machine in various conditions. Great sights! Great sounds! If you've got the skills-hit the road, Jack. The best time wins!</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Victory Run (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19910119T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Hudson Soft</developer>
    <publisher>Hudson Soft</publisher>
    <genre>Racing</genre>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T085459</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Super Volley Ball (U).zip</path>
    <name>World Beach Volley</name>
    <desc>Cute and colourful volleyball action game.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Super Volley Ball (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19900727T000000</releasedate>
    <developer/>
    <publisher/>
    <genre>Sports</genre>
    <players>2</players>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T085539</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./World Class Baseball (U).zip</path>
    <name>World Class Baseball</name>
    <desc>This game belongs in the Baseball Hall of Fame. Nothing takes you out to the ballgame like World Class Baseball! It tests all your baseball knowledge and skills. Bunt. Throw a slider. A change-u. Pick runners off base. Call in a relief pitcher. Hear the roar of the crowd and the crack of the bat. Play another player. Play against the computer. Play the Turbo Champs. Knock the dirt from your spikes. You're up!</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/World Class Baseball (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19890101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Hudson Soft</developer>
    <publisher>NEC</publisher>
    <genre>Sports</genre>
    <players>2</players>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T085552</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>/home/pi/RetroPie/roms/tg16/World Court Tennis (U).zip</path>
    <name>World Court Tennis</name>
    <desc>It's your serve. WHOP! The ball clears the net at 100 MPH and raises a little dust just inside the chalkline. An ace? no. WHOP! Your opponent returns with a powerful backhand that kills your plan of charging the net. No matter how you play - with up to 3 friends, singles, doubles, or against the computer - World Court Tennis will tax your endurance and test your skill with action that's fast and furious. Just don't scream at the line judge. He's never wrong.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/World Court Tennis (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19890101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Namco</developer>
    <publisher>NEC</publisher>
    <genre>Sports</genre>
    <players>4+</players>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T085612</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>/home/pi/RetroPie/roms/tg16/World Sports Competition (U).zip</path>
    <name>World Sports Competition</name>
    <desc>Top Athletes Battle for Glory!

You create an athlete who runs, jumps, and throws! Aim for the world record...and never give up!

With 18 events to choose from...
With 6 categories, and a total of 18 exciting events, you'll have a wide choice to train for. Then go on to challenge Olympic Mode in your chose event. you too can be a world record holder!

Excitement x 5!
Exciting alone, unbelievable with friends! Up to five players can compete at once, for some serious adrenalin action!</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/World Sports Competition (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19930101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Hudson Soft</developer>
    <publisher>Hudson Soft</publisher>
    <genre>Sports</genre>
    <players>2</players>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T085644</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Darius Plus (J) (SGX).zip</path>
    <name>Darius Plus</name>
    <desc>Amidst the clutter of arcade shooters in the late 1980s, companies needed to make their games stand out in some way. Simply flying a ship into outer space simply wasn't going to cut it anymore. Taito had an idea. Yes, there was still a spaceship. And yeah, that "outer space" part was still there too. But instead of the usual aliens, you fought fish.

Yes, fish.

Not even regular, aquatic fish, but robotic fish with lasers equipped to their fins, giant metal teeth and missiles firing from their gills. And not just fish either. There are squid, snails, and other undersea variations out for your blood as well.

The requisite plot is about the people of the planet Darius, who are being terrorized by said intergalatic fish. Only the heroic pilots Proco Jr and Tiat Young can save the day. The constant star of the Darius series is the Silver Hawk. Much like Gradius, it has a primary, forward firing weapon, along with bombs that can be used to attack vertically, and the usual shield.

The arcade game Darius games also used a unique system that attached three monitors together to create one massive horizontal playing field (also used in Taito's Ninja Warriors.) Naturally, this couldn't quite be replicated on the console system, so that nifty little gimmick is lost, but emulators can still replicate the dimensions of the screen, even if you end up looking at a tiny picture.

Looking to further set itself apart from the crowd, every Darius game has multiple levels, with several branching paths throughout the game. It adds tremendously to the replay value, especially since there are usual multiple endings, depending on which final zone you end up at.

Darius is a two-dimensional horizontally scrolling shoot 'em up set in a fictional future. Uniquely among shoot 'em ups, the game's screen was three times wider than conventional size, and the arcade cabinet used an arrangement of three screens to accommodate it. The player controls an ornate fighter spacecraft, named the Silver Hawk, and must navigate through scrolling terrain while battling a variety of fighter craft, ground vehicles, turrets, and other obstacles throughout the game's stages (referred to as zones in the game). The ship's arsenal consists of forward-firing missiles, aerial bombs and a protective force field, all of which can be upgraded by power-ups (in the form of large, colored orbs) that are dropped by specially-colored enemies throughout the game's zones. When the player reaches the end of a zone, a boss appears, which must be defeated to proceed. Once the boss of a zone is destroyed, the player is given a choice of which zone to play next via a branching path. While there are 28 zones in total, only seven can be played in a single run.

When various ports of it were made for different consoles, Taito (and others) were forced to shrink the playfield to fit on one screen.

It was released for the Commodore Amiga, Atari ST, PC Engine, PC Engine (Super CD-ROM), Wii (Virtual Console), and ZX Spectrum.

The PC Engine saw three releases:  

Darius Alpha (1990): A very rare beta release. This is one of the rarest Hu-Cards ever published. You could only get a copy of this hardcore shoot-em-up by buying Darius Plus and Super Darius and then mailing coupons to the publisher. 800 copies were made available, and names were drawn from those who mailed their info in. Some copies of the game were also given away as prizes by PC Engine Gekken and Marakatsu magazines.

Darius Plus (1990): The full game itself, again a PC Engine HuCard. The bosses that were removed in Alpha do not return here. Both Alpha and Plus were actually written for the PC Engine SuperGrafx and playing them on that console results in slightly improved graphics (less flicker and slowdown).

Super Darius (1990): A conversion of Darius for the PC Engine's Super CD-ROM, very close to the original arcade version other than being single-screen. Features new bosses, as well as a "boss rush" mode.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Darius Plus (J) (SGX)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19900316T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Taito</developer>
    <publisher>NEC</publisher>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Hit the Ice - VHL - The Official Video Hockey League (U).zip</path>
    <name>Hit the Ice: The Official Video Hockey League</name>
    <desc>If you've ever heard the joke, "The other night I went to a fight, and a hockey game broke out," then you already know what Hit the Ice is all about. This is rough and tumble, no holds barred hockey action that will challenge your stick-handling skills as well as your head-bashing abilities. While the traditional rules of hockey apply, that doesn't mean you can't throw an elbow or a high stick when the ref isn't looking. And since this is two-on-two hockey, the action is fast and furious as you try to outscore and outslug your opponent in four-player hockey action.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Hit the Ice - VHL - The Official Video Hockey League (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19920101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Taito</developer>
    <publisher>Taito</publisher>
    <genre>Sports</genre>
    <players>4+</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Lode Runner - Lost Labyrinth (J) [T+Eng_DavidShadoff].zip</path>
    <name>Lode Runner</name>
    <desc>This TurboGrafx-16 release of Lode Runner allows users to create and save levels, much like the original computer-based releases.

Lode Runner: Lost Labyrinth (a.k.a. Lode Runner: Ushina Wareta Meikyuu) is a platforming/puzzle game developed by Pack-In-Video and published by Br&#xF8;derbund Software for the TurboGrafx-16.

Though considered a very basic game when compared to other TurboGrafx-16 releases, Lode Runner: Lost Labyrinth contains the same feature set as the original computer versions of the game, including the ability to create and save user-created levels. Like other console releases, the action takes place on a scrolling screen, rather than a fixed single screen. The graphics have also been created specifically for this version, making the enemies look more deliberately like robots and the player character appears to be some sort of suited-up super human.

A password system exists alongside a proper backup option for saving single-player progress.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Lode Runner - Lost Labyrinth (J) [T+Eng_DavidShadoff]-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19900727T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Pack-in-Video</developer>
    <publisher>Broderbund</publisher>
    <genre>Platform</genre>
    <playcount>2</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181126T035139</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Aoi Blink (J) [T+Eng].zip</path>
    <name>Aoi Blink</name>
    <desc>Based on a TV anime series (from the grandfather of manga Osamu Tezuka), Blue Blink is a cute platformer that manages to find its place among the crowd. The game is divided up into different areas, each represented by a map screen. Within these areas, you can choose your route to the end (by exiting levels at certain points). Throughout each area you have to find a 'master key' allowing you access to the boss - this can be hard to locate at times and requires lots of shooting at blank areas of screen just in case.

Control of your character is original - on each stage you have three characters which you can choose between, with the CPU controlled ones following behind you like some bizarre congo line. The characters are preset and vary from stage to stage, and each one has different attributes. For example, some have very high jumping ability, whereas others are poor at jumping but have spread-shot weapons. Once you have found the master key and reached the final level in the area, you are entered into a boss battle, where you sit astride the titular donkey and attempt to fight your way to the next area.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Aoi Blink (J) [T+Eng]-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19900427T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Hudson</developer>
    <publisher>Hudson</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <players/>
    <playcount>2</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181126T041308</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Appare Gateball (J).zip</path>
    <name>Appare! Gateball</name>
    <desc>OK. So croquet may not be a popular idea for a video game, but the Japanese being as Japanese as they are, they went and did it anyway. So what does Appare! Gate Ball have to offer? First up is the choice between action and simulation mode. The main difference that I can make out between the two is that in action mode you have to both aim the shot and set the power, in simulation only the shot aiming is required. Your game is played out in two teams, rather than two individuals, and the members of your team are chosen from a variety of weird and crazy looking characters with varying attributes. Shots are aimed in a simple overhead viewpoint, which then switches to a standard view for the execution of the shot itself. All this is accompanied by a jolly little tune that plays away in the background.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Appare Gateball (J)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19881222T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Azuma</developer>
    <publisher>Hudson</publisher>
    <genre>Sports</genre>
    <players/>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Armed Formation F (J).zip</path>
    <name>Formation Armed F</name>
    <desc>Biologically themed shooter including side-pod powerups that can be positioned around your ship.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Armed Formation F (J)-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0.7</rating>
    <releasedate>19900323T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Pack-in-Video</developer>
    <publisher>Pack-in-Video</publisher>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <players/>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Artist Tool (J).zip</path>
    <name>Artist Tool</name>
    <desc>A unique piece of software for the PC Engine, Artist Tool is a graphics program that allows you to draw and print your own artwork when combined with the 'Illust Booster', 'Print Booster' and 'Photo Reader'. The interface has a rudimentary set of tools to choose from, like freehand, straight line and circle, and also a few tunes to listen to while you draw.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Artist Tool (J)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19911018T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>NEC</developer>
    <publisher>NEC</publisher>
    <genre>Sandbox</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Bari Bari Densetsu (J).zip</path>
    <name>Bari Bari Densetsu</name>
    <desc>Based on a manga, Bari Bari Densetsu is something of a rare breed on the Engine - a motorcycle racing game. You can pretty much guess how it works - there's a World GP mode where you have to compete in a variety of races in order and a Travel mode that let's you pick a track of your choice. Also to consider is the gubbins that make up your bike, such as tyres, engine, brakes etc as these have an effect depending on the type of course and the weather conditions. Races are started with a qualifying lap that lets you get the feel of the track, followed by the race proper. You are then placed and can hopefully move on to the next country.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Bari Bari Densetsu (J)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19891129T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Taito</developer>
    <publisher/>
    <genre>Racing</genre>
    <players/>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Barunba (J).zip</path>
    <name>Barunba</name>
    <desc>The Engine is hardly lacking in shooters, so to be successful, you have to stand out from the crowd. Barunba tries to add a hint of originality in its own subtle way. You control what is basically a floating globe (complete with little man inside) that has a weapons ring around it - this ring can be rotated right around the ship giving a fully controllable direction of fire, something obviously useful for those pesky critters approaching from behind. From the start, you are equipped with several different types of weapon, each of which can be temporarily boosted by collecting items that are dropped by exploding enemies. The levels are auto-scroll, moving around in all directions and contain mid-level as well as end-of-level bosses. Your ship has an energy bar, located at the bottom left of the screen, and once it is depleted it's 'Game Over'.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Barunba (J)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19900427T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Namco</developer>
    <publisher/>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <players/>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Batman (J).zip</path>
    <name>Batman</name>
    <desc>Having witnessed his parents' brutal murder as a child, millionaire philanthropist Bruce Wayne fights crime in Gotham City disguised as Batman, a costumed hero who strikes fear into the hearts of villains. But when a deformed madman who calls himself "The Joker" seizes control of Gotham's criminal underworld, Batman must face his most ruthless nemesis ever.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Batman (J)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19901012T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Sunsoft</developer>
    <publisher>Sunsoft</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Battle Lode Runner (J).zip</path>
    <name>Battle Lode Runner</name>
    <desc>Once an ancient arcade game, and with a previous version on the PC Engine by Pack In Video, Hudson Soft have taken the addictive gameplay of Lode Runner and given the graphics a complete face lift. The puzzle-based action in Lode Runner is simple: You are presented with a side-view platforms-and-ladders based level and you have to collect all the gold and escape without getting caught by the baddies. To defend yourself, you can dig holes in the ground, either to the left or to the right, and enemies stumbling upon them will fall down and be trapped. If you time it right, the hole will re-fill before the enemy can climb out, forcing them to respawn elsewhere in the level. If you prefer evasive action, make sure the coast is clear so you can escape up a ladder or across a well-placed rope, but be warned - they will follow! Once you have collected all the gold, hotfoot it to the nearest long ladder and escape out the top of the screen. In magazine previews, this was originally titled Lode Runner II.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Battle Lode Runner (J)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19930129T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Hudson</developer>
    <publisher>Hudson</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <players/>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Be Ball (J).zip</path>
    <name>Be Ball</name>
    <desc>Be Ball is an action/puzzle game in which you have to roll coloured globes around the play area and deposit them on their relevant coloured squares. Once all balls are in place it's on to the next level. Easy, right? Well, maybe not, as there is all manner of wildlife out to put paid to your spherical antics, from hedgehogs to monkeys and penguins. Luckily, the balls themselves do have a use - give them a swift kick and they'll get rid of any creature barring your way. And if you are persistent, you can even whack down walls. Also, be on the lookout for various items scattered around that aid you in your task, like time-stops, smart bombs etc</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Be Ball (J)-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0.6</rating>
    <releasedate>19900330T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Hudson</developer>
    <publisher/>
    <genre>Puzzle</genre>
    <players/>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Bikkuriman World (J) [T+Eng1.00_DemiForce].zip</path>
    <name>Bikkuriman World</name>
    <desc>Despite being Hudson&#x2019;s Vol.2, this was in fact released almost a month before The Kung Fu. It&#x2019;s a conversion of what most people know as Wonder Boy in Monster Land, and it&#x2019;s as perfect a conversion from the arcade as you&#x2019;re likely to get. As with a number of TurboGrafx games, Westone encountered licensing issues with this title and rebranded the game under the popular Japanese Bikkuriman franchise. This game takes a different pace from the first Wonder Boy game, being more of an adventure with a slower pace and more strategy. You start the game with barely a thread on and are given a sword by some wise looking dude who lives in a tree - so far so good. It is then your task to travel through the various platform-based levels defeating monsters and evil bosses along the way. Each enemy you kill leaves behind a coin or money bag (these are also at various hidden locations if you jump at the right spot) and shops will offer you armour, shields, weaponry and go-faster shoes. You can also pop into a bar and top up your energy if you can afford it. Levels are time limited (shown by an egg-timer on the left) so you need to be quick, or energy is taken away from your heart meter.
There appear to be two versions of this rom, indicated but the difference in spelling on the first sign - Monster Land and monsterland.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Bikkuriman World (J) [T+Eng1.00_DemiForce]-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19871030T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Hudson</developer>
    <publisher>Hudson</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <playcount>2</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181126T041903</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Blodia (J).zip</path>
    <name>Blodia</name>
    <desc>Puzzle games. Don't you just love 'em? Classics like Tetris, Puzzle Bobble, Klax....and then there's Blodia. The concept behind Blodia is very simple: 1-You have a screen of pipe-work. 2-There is a ball travelling down the pipe. 3-If the ball drops down a gap in the pipe you have to start again. That's it. So what this all amounts to is you frantically sliding the tiles around block-puzzle style to keep that cursed ball bearing on track. God forbid that you think the ball is moving too slowly, you can even push a button to speed the damn thing up, but you have to wonder why you would ever want to do that.

(from the PC Engine Software Bible)</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Blodia (J)-image.jpg</image>
    <developer>Hudson</developer>
    <publisher>Broderbund</publisher>
    <genre>Puzzle</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Bouken Danshaku Don - The Lost Sunheart (J).zip</path>
    <name>Bouken Danshaku Don: The Lost Sunheart</name>
    <desc>A horizontal shoot 'em up with a surreal edge. A group of evil eyes have stolen parts of the Sunheart, and the player needs to recover them.

Bouken Danshaku Don: The Lost Sunheart ("Adventures of Don Baron: The Lost Sunheart", roughly) is a horizontal shoot 'em up exclusive to the PC Engine. The game's plot concerns the titular Sunheart device, which is broken into several pieces and spirited away by a group of malicious eyeball enemies. The hero, in a series of vehicles, takes down each of the boss creatures that are protecting a piece of the stolen Sunheart.

The game is distinct among shoot 'em ups for allowing players to keep their power-ups after dying. This does not mitigate the game's difficulty, as it has some very strict checkpointing and many enemies with difficult-to-avoid homing shots. The game's surreal sense of humor comes through with its bizarre bosses, in some way invoking the flamboyant Cho Aniki series.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Bouken Danshaku Don - The Lost Sunheart (J)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19920104T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Manjyudo</developer>
    <publisher>I'Max</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <players/>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Break In (J).zip</path>
    <name>Break In</name>
    <desc>The Engine doesn't really have much in the way of pool games. In fact, this is the only one that I can think of. It looks and plays like those games you used to see in arcades and has plenty of options to choose from. Firstly you get to choose from simulation, action and technique (which lets you try out loads of trick shots). Then, you can play against other humans, your coach or try out the challenge mode that sets you up as a stowaway on a cruise liner, having to beat 14 opponents to be let off the hook! The play screen is laid out clearly - you aim by positioning a target anywhere on the table (unlike some games that make you aim to the cushion), then you can choose the regulars like spin and shot power.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Break In (J)-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0.1</rating>
    <releasedate>19890810T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Naxat</developer>
    <publisher/>
    <genre>Sports</genre>
    <players/>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Busou Keiji Cyber Cross (J).zip</path>
    <name>Cyber Cross</name>
    <desc>Rolling Thunder-esque platform beat 'em up which gives you the ability to transform into a brightly coloured Power Suit as you fight crime on the streets.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Busou Keiji Cyber Cross (J)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19890623T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Face</developer>
    <publisher/>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <players/>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Champion Wrestler (J).zip</path>
    <name>Champion Wrestler</name>
    <desc>Champion Wrestler gained popularity in the arcade, and now it is reborn on the PC Engine! Up to 2 people can play simultaneously as well, and you can also enjoy a large number of wrestlers and tag team. In order to take the TWF championship belt, the game will challenge you with formidable enemy skills.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Champion Wrestler (J)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19901214T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Taito</developer>
    <publisher>Taito</publisher>
    <genre>Fighting</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Circus Lido (J).zip</path>
    <name>Circus Lido</name>
    <desc>A single-screen action game featuring a chameleon that feeds bugs to Venus flytraps.

Circus Lido, or Circus Ride, is an action game published by Uni Post exclusively for the PC Engine.

The goal of the game is to navigate the stage and defeat the enemies using the chameleon's two powers: his long tongue and his prehensile tail. The tongue can be used to capture enemies and spit them out towards the Venus flytraps, which are the only way to remove them from the stage. The tail can be used to climb vines scattered around, which allows the chameleon to ascend through the stage.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Circus Lido (J)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19910406T000000</releasedate>
    <developer/>
    <publisher>Uni Post</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <players/>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Columns (J).zip</path>
    <name>Columns</name>
    <desc>Columns was one of the many Tetris-like puzzles that appeared after that game's great success in the late 1980s. It takes place inside a tall, rectangular playing area. Columns of three different symbols (such as differently-colored jewels) appear, one at a time, at the top of the well and fall to the bottom, landing either on the floor or on top of previously-fallen "Columns"

While a column is falling, the player can move it left and right, and can also cycle the positions of the symbols within it.

If, after a column has fallen, there are three or more of the same symbols connected in a straight line horizontally, vertically, or diagonally, those symbols disappear. The pile of columns then settles under gravity. If this causes three or more other symbols to become aligned, they also disappear and the pile settles again. This process repeats as many times as necessary. It is not uncommon for this to happen three or four times in a row - it often happens by accident when the well is becoming crowded. If the well fills beyond the top of the screen, the game ends.

Occasionally, a special column called the Magic Jewel Column appears. The Magic Jewel flashes with different colors and when it lands, it destroys all the jewels with the same color as the one underneath it.

The columns fall at a faster rate as the player progresses. The goal of the game is to play for as long as possible before the well fills up with Jewels.

Some ports of the game offer alternate game modes as well. "Flash columns" involves mining their way through a set number of lines to get to a flashing jewel at the bottom. "Doubles" allows two players work together in the same well. "Time trial" involves racking up as many points as possible within the time limit.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Columns (J)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19910329T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Sega</developer>
    <publisher>Sega</publisher>
    <genre>Puzzle</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Darius Alpha (J).zip</path>
    <name>Darius Alpha</name>
    <desc>It's a straight run through only the bosses from Darius Plus. Only around 800 copies were produced and given to those persons who bought both Darius Plus and Super Darius only in Japan.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Darius Alpha (J)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19900316T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>NEC Avenue</developer>
    <publisher>Taito</publisher>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181126T043318</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Adventure Island (J).zip</path>
    <name>Adventure Island</name>
    <desc>Life as a roaming adventurer is never easy. One minute you're shoving several feet of cold steel between the gaping jaws of some evil robot dragon, and the next thing you know, you've been transformed into a fire breathing lizard man. Such is the problem that you first encounter at the beginning of Adventure Island, Hudson Soft's conversion of the Master System game 'Wonder Boy III: The Dragon's Trap'. Taking more of its influence from the second game in the Wonder Boy series than the first, Adventure Island has a more balanced structure and more exploratory gameplay.

The main game is centred around a small village which acts as a sort of 'hub' to the surrounding levels. Each of these levels are gradually accessed over time with the acquisition of keys or new transformations. As the game progresses, you will find yourself transforming into five different creatures, which can (and need to) be switched between in special rooms. The lizard is the basic transformation and does little more than breathe fire at any passing fauna. Mouse man is a tiny little critter and aside from being able to fit under small obstacles, he can also run up and around special chequered walls and ceilings. Next up is a green amphibian that gives you the power to swim around freely, followed by a tiger man who swings his sword around in a wide arc, allowing you to break blocks above and below. Finally, there is the bird transformation which lets you fly around by repeatedly tapping the jump button.

As you progress, your quest will take you over many types of terrain from jungle to desert to the inside of a giant pyramid - but to help you out there is a password/backup save feature in a church in the main village. As you viciously hack up the cute little inhabitants of the island, you find that they considerately drop money and helpful items for you. The money is used in shops to upgrade your armour, or buy healing at the hospital, while the other items are special weapons that can be set from the pause menu. These include homing fireballs, ground based mini whirlwinds and arrows that shoot directly upwards (and are a blessing when you are trying to get rid of flame-dropping clouds).</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Adventure Island (J)-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>1</rating>
    <releasedate>19910419T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Westone</developer>
    <publisher>Hudson Soft</publisher>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Bomberman (U).zip</path>
    <name>Bomberman</name>
    <desc>The black spaceman kidnapped Bomberman's beloved and brought her to his chambers in the castle, far beyond his reach, over the rivers, forest and mountains. Bomberman's job is to save her, battling the sea of the enemies, with only bombs at his disposal.

The range of Bomberman's bomb explosions can be upgraded with time, but if he dies, the range resets back to the minimum range and Bomberman loses his previous skills. Some updates can make Bomberman walk through the walls, increase his speed, and give him some other assets to aid him in his quest to save the woman he loves.

This top-down action-arcade game consists of nine levels per stage, each tougher than the other, and each final one consisting of the boss that will have to be dealt with. Bomberman can move horizontally and vertically and lay down bombs behind him, thus evaporating the enemies, but beware: Bomberman can block himself with his own bomb, and thus become a victim of his own bomb.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Bomberman (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19900101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Hudson Soft</developer>
    <publisher>Turbo Technologies Inc.</publisher>
    <genre>Puzzle</genre>
    <players>4+</players>
    <playcount>2</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181126T044149</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Bomberman '94 (J).zip</path>
    <name>Bomberman '94</name>
    <desc>BOMBERMAN has arrived to restore peace on the planet, which has been split into five parts by an evil hand! In addition to the nine members of the Bomber Family, the character ROOI shows up to lend a hand. Jump on the EGGS that appear from destroyed SOFT BLOCKS, and you can ride one of five types of ROOI. Each ROOI has different special abilitiesuse these well and youll ride to victory! Bombs that turn according to arrows and other new gimmicks have been added to BATTLE GAME, increased to ten stages. Tag-team matches are now possible, ensuring that this game will be a blast!

Bomberman '94 is a video game from the Bomberman series which was developed and published by Hudson Soft for the PC Engine and released on December 10, 1993 in Japan. It was later re-developed by Westone and re-published by Sega as Mega Bomberman on the Sega Mega Drive/Genesis in 1994 in other areas. The PC Engine Bomberman '94 was later released outside Japan through the Wii's Virtual Console and the PlayStation 3's PlayStation Network.

The game supports single-player and multi-player modes. In single player, the player navigates several levels of mazes, destroying creatures with bombs. In multi-player mode, players defeat each other with bombs.

Bomberman '94 is the final HuCard title to be made and released by Hudson Soft, the original designers of the PC Engine console.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Bomberman '94 (J)-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <releasedate>19931210T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Hudson</developer>
    <publisher>Hudson</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <players/>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181126T044137</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Yo, Bro (U).zip</path>
    <name>Yo, Bro</name>
    <desc>Ratz attack! Ratz attack! The city of Los Angeles is being invaded! Only Lil Bro', Camp California's rad skateboarding dude, can save it. The evil Ratz gang is unleashing a barrage of killer creatures and devices. Find incredibly cool weapons to fight back. Wipe out their earthquake machines and nasty man-eating plants with rocket grenades. Fight off wicked space aliens and launch your bonus attacks. It'll take everything you've got to send the Ratz packing.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Yo, Bro (U)-image.png</image>
    <rating>0.5</rating>
    <releasedate>19910131T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>ICOM Simulations</developer>
    <publisher>NEC</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181122T085712</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Alien Crush (U).zip</path>
    <name>Alien Crush</name>
    <desc>Imagine a living pinball machine...with aliens and outlandish worlds to throw at you. And turbo-charged, speed-of-light pinball action. You control the flippers and ball speed to defeat the Slime, the Tentacloid and Scorpion. Go for the eyes! This is full-tilt, out-of-this-world action! Surrealistic graphics plus true-to-life, earsplitting arcade pinball sound.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Alien Crush (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19880914T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Compile, Kaga Create</developer>
    <publisher>Turbo Technologies</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <playcount>3</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181127T054835</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Altered Beast (Juuouki) (J).zip</path>
    <name>Altered Beast</name>
    <desc>Zeus has called upon you! Only a brave and fearless warrior can save his beloved daughter, Athena, from the cunning clutches of Nelf, evil Lord of the Underworld. Risen from the grave, you are presented with supernatural powers beyond this world. Collect the mystical spirit balls and transform into an awesome array of creatures - as Strongman, punch and kick harder than ever before, as WereWolf and WereTiger, rip the flesh of the demons of hell, and as Bear, knock out your enemies with one bad breath! You hear the distant cries of the beautiful Athena and as the terrors of the Underworld tighten their grasp, the beast within you rises to face the final battle!

This game was released only for the japanese NEC PC Engine.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Altered Beast (Juuouki) (J)-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <releasedate>19890929T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Sega</developer>
    <publisher>NEC Avenue</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./After Burner II (J).zip</path>
    <name>After Burner II</name>
    <desc>One of Sega's big arcade hits using their 'super scaler' technology, it was a bold move to try and convert this to any home machine. After Burner II is, quite simply, one of the most mindless shooters that you're ever likely to play: simply fly your F-14 into the screen, dodging missiles like crazy and letting all hell loose with your vulcan cannon. There is precious little strategy - even less than Space Harrier, and often luck plays more of a part than skill. The action is split up by the occasional bonus stage - a run through a canyon blowing up anything that dares to exist in front of you. Fuelling planes and landing strips also make a regular appearance.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/After Burner II (J)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19900928T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Sega</developer>
    <publisher>NEC</publisher>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <players/>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181201T192950</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Atomic Robo-Kid Special (J).zip</path>
    <name>Atomic Robo-Kid Special</name>
    <desc>More of an explorative shooter than the standard blasting affairs, Atomic Robo-Kid Special takes all the elements from the arcade version and jiggles around with them a bit for the PC Engine. The control method takes a little getting used to - pressing button I selects from one of four weapons collected along the way, whereas holding down button I will lock you to the direction you are facing, making backing-away and firing easier. It can be fiddly at first, but it's essential that you master it.

The four weapons available are variable in quality. The forward shot and diagonal shot are both only useful when you've lost the other weapons, as the missile and full-fire are the ones that you will utilise most often. The missile is particularly useful as in some levels you are required to blast away areas of wall to progress. Levels are varied - some are horizontal, some are more like mazes and there are also two types of boss area: one with a small enemy over the opposite side of the screen protected by a barrier you have to destroy, and another with a huge mechanical monster that follows you relentlessly around an arena.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Atomic Robo-Kid Special (J)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19900119T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>UPL</developer>
    <publisher>UPL</publisher>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <players/>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181201T194242</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Space Harrier (U).zip</path>
    <name>Space Harrier</name>
    <desc>You are Harrier, the resourceful extra-terrestrial warrior. And space is your battlefield. Your mission is to save the Land of the Dragons from vicious creatures led by the vile and crafty One-Eyed Mammoth. Aided by your only friends, the Dragons, you find yourself attacked again and again. Armed only with an Autolock Energy Launcher and your wits, you must fight off one heavily-armed alien after another. You must use every trick in the book. Every skill at your command. The clashes are thrilling and demanding. The combat scenes are powerful. Can you survive the intense fighting? For your sake, for the sake of the Land of the Dragons, you must!</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Space Harrier (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19881209T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>NEC</developer>
    <publisher>NEC</publisher>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <players/>
    <playcount>3</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181206T003637</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Tiger Road (U).zip</path>
    <name>Tiger Road</name>
    <desc>This arcade conversion is a beat 'em up in which you (as Lee Wong) must rescue the village children from the evil Ryo Ken Oh. Many levels are horizontally scrolling, although with high ledges to jump onto and follow for a slightly different path. Magic urns containing improved weapons appear frequently. Most enemies are easy to attack and only need one hit to kill, although they come at you in large hordes. Once you get to the indoor sections you will find big enemies with the ability to kill you with one hit, in sections set on multiple levels complete with stairways.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Tiger Road (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0.8</rating>
    <releasedate>19900101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Capcom</developer>
    <publisher>NEC</publisher>
    <genre>Fighting</genre>
    <players/>
    <playcount>2</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181228T225651</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Turrican (U).zip</path>
    <name>Turrican</name>
    <desc>From beyond the edge of darkness, evil incarnate is back. He is Morgul, master of all the fears and nightmares of mankind. As a world trembles in sleepless terror, a single warrior emerges - you are Turrican! Battle through the five worlds of darkness encountering thunder and storm, mechanical monsters, hidden rooms, awesome end of level guardians, reptillian beasts, and anywhere... the unexpected! Featuring 13 levels with over 1,300 screens, 10 hi-tech weapons systems, multi-directional scrolling, 20 musically excellent soundtracks, countless special effects and bonus features, and 50 different aliens and 8 gigantic end-level monsters.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Turrican (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19910801T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>The Code Monkeys</developer>
    <publisher>Ballistic</publisher>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <playcount>2</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181228T225226</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Burning Angels (J).zip</path>
    <name>Burning Angels</name>
    <desc>Evil forces have kidnapped the leader of the Burning Project! It's up to the Burning Angels to rescue her! And so starts another vertically scrolling shooter on the PC Engine. There are no surprises in the gameplay here - choose one of two ships, shoot down enemies and collect power upgrades and energy pods. Levels range from the city to the desert and the obligatory sci-fi enemy base. At the end of each level, defeat the large boss craft to move on.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Burning Angels (J)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19901207T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Naxat</developer>
    <publisher>Naxat</publisher>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <players/>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20190721T153110</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Cyber Core (U).zip</path>
    <name>Cyber-Core</name>
    <desc>Cyber-core is a vertically scrolling shooter in which the player fights insects. The basic idea is traditional: shooting everything before they can shoot/touch the player: after three hits the chitin armor breaks and a life is lost. Besides flying enemies which are disposed of with the standard gun, the player also has to deal with enemies on the ground which need to be hit with one of the unlimited bomb.

The player has the choice between four insect forms which are changed by collecting the associated extra symbols. Collecting more of the same symbol upgrades the insect, but this also rises the difficulty level. Other extras include smart bombs, extra lives, armor refreshments or a protection shield. The game features the possibility to turn on rapid fire or to slow down the speed as well as big boss enemies at the end and within the levels.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Cyber Core (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19900101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>AlfaSystem Co., Ltd.</developer>
    <publisher>Information Global Service</publisher>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <playcount>14</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20190721T153455</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Bonk's Adventure (U).zip</path>
    <name>Bonk's Adventure</name>
    <desc>Bonk yourself out in this head-buttin', head-splittin' adventure. As Bonk the Caveman, use your head against Kongo Zilla, Tractorhead and wackiest array of prehistoric foes ever seen. Be sure to eat your meat-and-vegetables as you power-up to battle Evil King Drool himself. It's a real head-banger!</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Bonk's Adventure (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0.8</rating>
    <releasedate>19891215T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Hudson</developer>
    <publisher>NEC</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <playcount>12</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20200112T161055</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Bonk's Revenge (U).zip</path>
    <name>Bonk's Revenge</name>
    <desc>Bonk is back! Last year's video smash is bashing his way through a totally awesome new adventure! Help that radical cave dude save the Dinosaur Kingdom from the heinous King Drool III. Bigger, badder bosses. More powerful power-ups. More excellent hidden secrets. And more worlds of pre-hysterical action that'll have you cracking up while you're out cracking heads. Blast back to the Bonk Age, mankind's coolest era, and Bonk yourself out!</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Bonk's Revenge (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19910308T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Mutech</developer>
    <publisher>NEC</publisher>
    <genre>Platform</genre>
    <playcount>4</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20200112T161128</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Bonk III - Bonk's Big Adventure (U).zip</path>
    <name>Bonk 3: Bonk's Big Adventure</name>
    <desc>Bonk is back! And he's bigger and better than ever! Use your head (literally) to traverse 6 wild locations- including a forest grove, an antartic ice prison and more! Chomp on blue miracle candy to grow to gigantic proportions and break right through large obstacles. Chomp red candy to shrink to microscopic size and slip right under narrow cracks to discover secret items! Catch the magic flower in each stage to be transported to a bonus round- where you can score more points and earn bonus men! On your way, you will defeat menacing bosses that include acrobatic dinosaur, a sneaky squid and other! Are you ready to save the world, little cave dude!?</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Bonk III - Bonk's Big Adventure (U)-image.png</image>
    <releasedate>19930402T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Hudson Soft</developer>
    <publisher>NEC</publisher>
    <genre>Platform</genre>
    <players>2</players>
    <playcount>6</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20200112T191753</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Vigilante (U).zip</path>
    <name>Vigilante</name>
    <desc>Some New York City punks have kidnapped a girl. Your girl. Throwing your muscle around is not your normal style, but these are mean streets! If it has to be you versus these big city greaseballs and junkyard dudes -- bring them on! They won't come at your one at a time, so it's a good thing you can be quick and mean. Go to it, Vigilante! Or never see her smile again.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Vigilante (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0.6</rating>
    <releasedate>19890101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>IREM</developer>
    <publisher>NEC</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <playcount>2</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20200509T005333</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Air Zonk (U).zip</path>
    <name>Air Zonk</name>
    <desc>The powered-up Zonk gathers his friends to form Team Cool, and they set out to stop King Drool&#x2019;s plan to conquer the world. Choose from 3 levels of difficulty and 3 types of Friend Modes. Shoot King Drool's cyber robots and avoid their attacks while collecting the Air Bones to unleash a variety of attacks. Enjoy unique moves such as combining with a friend to create an invincible hybrid form or blasting enemies with a charged attack. Air &#x201C;Zonk&#x201D; is filled with humor, like its wacky theme song that plays when you post a huge score or when your game is over.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Air Zonk (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19921212T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Hudson Soft</developer>
    <publisher>Red Company</publisher>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <playcount>2</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20200513T210922</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./1943 Kai (J).zip</path>
    <name>1943: Kai</name>
    <desc>Developed and released alongside the Family Computer version, 1943 Kai: Midway Kaisen is an arcade game, an "alternate" version of the original 1943, released in 1987[3] only in Japan. Most of the graphics and sounds have been reworked, and the game has been made more "extreme" (laser-firing WWII planes and ships that run on ground). Further, the trademark P-38 has been replaced with a Boeing Stearman E75 N68828.

In 1991, this version was converted to the PC Engine as simply 1943 Kai, again Japan-only; this version itself contains many additional levels and original music.

The game is set in the Pacific theater of World War II, off the coast of the Midway Atoll. The goal is to attack the Japanese air fleet that bombed the American aircraft carrier, pursue all Japanese air and sea forces, fly through the 16 stages of play, and make their way to the Japanese battleship Yamato and destroy her. 11 of these stages consist of an air-to-sea battle (with a huge battleship or an aircraft carrier as the stage boss), while 5 stages consist of an all-aerial battle against a squadron of Japanese bombers with a mother bomber at the end.

As in 1942, players pilot a P-38 Lightning. Controls are also similar: button 1 fires main weapons, and button two performs two special actions: a loop maneuver like in 1942, or one of three special attacks in exchange for some of the player's fuel. Indeed, players now have only one life, in the form of a large "fuel" meter; constantly depleting, but refillable by collecting various powerups (chiefly "Pow" icons). In 2-player mode, when both players overlap their planes on screen, the energy bar can be transferred from the player with more fuel to the player with less. Destroying a complete formation of red enemy planes will result in a power-up, such as a health boost or a new main weapon.

There are cheat codes, different for every stage, ranging from holding down a fire button or pointing the joystick in certain direction, player(s) are rewarded with fully upgraded weapons.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/1943 Kai (J)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Capcom</developer>
    <publisher>Capcom</publisher>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <players>2</players>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20200515T223756</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Street Fighter II' - Champion Edition (J).zip</path>
    <name>Street Fighter II: Champion Edition</name>
    <desc>From the corners of the globe come twelve of the toughest fighters to ever prowl the streets. Choose your champion and step into the arena as one of the eight original challengers or as one of the four Grand Masters! Pound your opponent as Balrog and knock them out for the count. Tower over your prey as Sagat and daze them with your awesome Tiger Shot. Slash your opponent with Bison's claw and send them running for cover. Or strike fear into your enemies as Vega, the greatest Grand Master of them all!</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg16/Street Fighter II' - Champion Edition (J)-image.png</image>
    <releasedate>19930612T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>NEC Avenue</developer>
    <publisher>Capcom</publisher>
    <genre>Fighting</genre>
    <players>2</players>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20200515T223932</lastplayed>
  </game>
</gameList>
