<?xml version="1.0"?>
<gameList>
  <game>
    <path>./Advanced Dungeons &amp; Dragons Eye of the Beholder (U).cue</path>
    <name>Advanced Dungeons &amp; Dragons: Eye of the Beholder</name>
    <desc>Eye of the Beholder is a dungeon crawler RPG with a first-person perspective based on the 2nd Edition AD&amp;D rules. The starting party consists of four characters and up to two NPCs can join later. Combat and magic happen in real time. Fight over a dozen different monster varieties and cast over 40 spells. A point-and-click interface makes exploring, fighting, spellcasting and handling objects easy.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Advanced Dungeons &amp; Dragons Eye of the Beholder (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19940629T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Westwood Studios, Inc.</developer>
    <publisher>Sega</publisher>
    <genre>Role-Playing</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Adventures of Batman &amp; Robin, The (U).cue</path>
    <name>The Adventures of Batman &amp; Robin</name>
    <desc>Robin and Commissioner Gordon have mysteriously disappeared, and Batman suspects kidnapping. Have our two comrades succumb to the deadly beauty of Poison Ivy? Does the Riddler know the answer? Or will The Joker have the last laugh? Tune in on Sega CD to find out!</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Adventures of Batman &amp; Robin, The (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19950701T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Clockwork Tortoise</developer>
    <publisher>Sega</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Adventures Of Willy Beamish, The (U).cue</path>
    <name>The Adventures of Willy Beamish</name>
    <desc>Willy Beamish is a kid who likes to goof off and have fun. Naturally all the grown-ups get in the way by making him go to school, making him clean his room, etc. But now that's school's out for the summer, Willy is determined to have a good time and maybe even have his pet frog win the frog jumping contest. However Willy has a habit of getting into trouble, and naturally that means it will be a challenge to get out of it.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Adventures Of Willy Beamish, The (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19930202T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Dynamix, Inc.</developer>
    <publisher>Sega</publisher>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./AH-3 Thunderstrike (U).cue</path>
    <name>AH-3 Thunderstrike</name>
    <desc>AH-3 Thunderstrike is a helicopter sim/shooter. You will pilot the AH-3 over 10 operations all over the world. Each operation is composed of several missions, such as destroying tanks, or destroying bridges, or escorting trucks, and so on.

Thunderstrike's graphics consist of scaled sprites arranged to create a 3D environment. It makes use of the Sega CD's scaling and rotation hardware to create this effect with a smooth frame rate.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/AH-3 Thunderstrike (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19930101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Core Design Ltd.</developer>
    <publisher>Core Design Ltd.</publisher>
    <genre>Shooter, Flight Simulator</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Amazing Spider-Man vs. The Kingpin, The (U).cue</path>
    <name>The Amazing Spider-Man vs. The Kingpin</name>
    <desc>Enter a vicious web of danger and disaster! The Kingpin of Crime frames Spider-Man for planting a bomb in New York; and Spidey's only hope is to find the keys to the bomb's location before it explodes. Help Spider-Man stick it to the Kingpin and his horde of vicious assassins along the way. Enter hand-to-hand combat with Dr. Octopus! Put the Sandman to sleep! Use dazzling acrobatics to take on the Lizard, Hobgoblin and Venom! Dodge Electro's amped-up charge! Don't be fooled by the new trickery of Mysterio and the villainy of the Vulture! Take aim with Spidey's gadgets. Shoot webs! Stick to walls and ceilings! Swing from skyscrapers!</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Amazing Spider-Man vs. The Kingpin, The (U)-image.png</image>
    <releasedate>19931103T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Sega</developer>
    <publisher>Sega</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Android Assault (U).cue</path>
    <name>Android Assault: The Revenge of Bari-Arm</name>
    <desc>In Android Assault an alien species called the Xias have targeted human beings for extermination. They have assembled a massive fleet that has crushed any opposing ship that has been sent their way and has started to attacking colonies stationed on nearby planets with a collision course to Earth and it is up to the player to stop them.

The gameplay is a side-scrolling shooter, similar to R-Type, where the player takes control of a space fighter that can morph into a cyborg called Bari-Arm and has an arsenal of weaponry to take down enemy ships including the Thundercracker, Burning Wave and the Chase Cannon along with picking up health and power-ups left behind by destroyed enemies.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Android Assault (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19940101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Human Entertainment, Inc.</developer>
    <publisher>Human Entertainment, Inc.</publisher>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./AX-101 (U).cue</path>
    <name>A/X-101</name>
    <desc>In the future date of 2500, mankind has reached its zenith in space travel and peace. However, after making contact with alien life for the first time, Earth is soon attacked and nearly conquered by a war-driven alien race called the Gurzons. The Earth's Defense Force discover the Gurzon's enemy resides on the distant alien planet Prism, who made contact with Earth as a warning against the oncoming Gurzon invasion. Further investigation leads to the discovery of a computer upgrade system located on Prism called the A/X-101, a weapon program that promises to liberate Earth from the Gurzon's grip. Earth Defense sends four of its best fighter pilots - Bob, Kelly, Chris and their Captain (the player) - to travel to Prism, retrieve the A/X-101 and use it against all of the Gurzon's planetary bases.

The game is an on-rails shooter, with gameplay seen from a first-person cockpit perspective. The player's ship moves automatically through pre-rendered space and planetary environments and only the targeting crosshair can be moved freely. Laser Cannons and Fusion Warheads are available to hit the numerous enemies. Lasers have unlimited ammunition but need a few moments time to recharge. The warheads function as smart bombs and clear the screen of enemies, but are available only in limited supply. They are restocked when reaching a certain score. The ship's energy shield functions as a life bar.

Between the shooting levels, there are transitional cutscenes, pre-rendered in the same way as the actual gameplay.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/AX-101 (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19941130T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Micronet Co. Ltd.</developer>
    <publisher>Absolute Entertainment</publisher>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./B.C. Racers (U).cue</path>
    <name>BC Racers</name>
    <desc>Millionaire playboy caveman Millstone Rockerfella arranges a wild 'n' wacky BC bike race, the winner of which receives the ULTIMATE BOULDERDASH BIKE. 

Cool 'n' crazy Cliff Ace has had his sunglasses set on a boulderdash bike since he was knee-high to a baby diplodocus, so he signs up for the race - taking his cave-babe Roxy along for the ride! Join them as they speed n' smash their way on a dino-powered dirtbike through 32 howlin' heats in a madcap, 3D cartoon race against a hardrock host of rocky racers!</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/B.C. Racers (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19941201T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Core Design Ltd.</developer>
    <publisher>Time Warner Interactive, Inc.</publisher>
    <genre>Racing</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Batman Returns (U).cue</path>
    <name>Batman Returns</name>
    <desc>The Pengiun and the Red Triangle Circus Gang have Gotham City in a death grip! Look out! Catwoman prowls the streets. It's time to duke it out with Gotham's notorious hoodlums. Just like the hit movie! New Sega CD racing combat! Blast through hostile traffic in the Batmobile! Race through flooded sewers in the Batskiboat to the ultimate showdown in The Penguin's lair!</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Batman Returns (U)-image.png</image>
    <releasedate>19930501T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Malibu Interactive</developer>
    <publisher>Sega</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Battle Frenzy (U).cue</path>
    <name>Battle Frenzy</name>
    <desc>Bloodshot (Battle Frenzy) is a video game developed by Jim Blackler for Domark and published by Acclaim in 1994 for the Sega Mega Drive/Genesis console in Europe. A North American release was planned, and reviewed in gaming magazines, but was not released. The game was re-released the same year for both the Mega Drive and the Sega CD in Europe.

Superbly smooth 3D graphics and frantic one or two player split screen action as you can through an alien troop carrier containing a deadly cargo of pre-programmed killing machines. Your weapons include the surgically inserted "Battle Frenzy Chip" which gives you super strength, lightning reflexes and an insatiable desire to kill; a condition known as 'Bloodshot'. Your partner had better watch his back...</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Battle Frenzy (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <developer>The Kremlin</developer>
    <publisher>Good Deal Games</publisher>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Battlecorps (U).cue</path>
    <name>BattleCorps</name>
    <desc>Battlecorps is a giant-mech game that takes place on a mining planet known as Mandlebrot's World. The colony supercomputer has been infected with a virus, and now the planet's giant machines are turning against the people who created them. You must pilot your bipedal attack machine through 12 missions to reboot the computer.

The graphics in this game use scaled and rotated sprites to achieve a 3D environment. The effect is similar to other Core Design games for the Sega CD.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Battlecorps (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19930101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Core Design Ltd.</developer>
    <publisher>Core Design Ltd.</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Bill Walsh College Football (U).cue</path>
    <name>Bill Walsh College Football</name>
    <desc>The game features 24 college football teams from the 1992 season and 24 of the all-time college teams since 1978. Play modes include exhibition, playoffs and all-time playoffs and the SNES version also has an eleven week season mode with the National Championship as the ultimate goal.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Bill Walsh College Football (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19930602T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>High Score</developer>
    <publisher>Electronic Arts</publisher>
    <genre>Strategy, Sports</genre>
    <players>4</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Black Hole Assault (U).cue</path>
    <name>BlackHole Assault</name>
    <desc>According to Blackhole Assault, the 22nd century sees earth technology advance to the point where exploration of the immediate solar system is not only possible, but necessary due to resource constraints. Humans are attempting to harvest the resources of the entire solar system but have met with trouble from alien invaders. It is up to a small force of humans who recognize and understand the threat to confront the aliens head on.

The weapon of choice in this game is the Cybernetic Anthropomorphized Machine, or C.A.M. The C.A.M. is a large robot that fights 1-on-1 against alien robots. All of the gameplay in Blackhole Assault revolves around single-round, 1-on-1 robot fighting action. There are 10 backdrops against which to beat up robots, including various planets and moons around the solar system.

The game has 4 different modes. The main story mode is Operation BHA. The exhibition mode allows players to customize matches down to the robots each player will use and the backdrop to play on. The exhibition mode can be configured to allow one or even both fighters to be controlled by the computer. Further, the game has tournament and league modes.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Black Hole Assault (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19921023T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Micronet Co. Ltd.</developer>
    <publisher>Micronet Co. Ltd.</publisher>
    <genre>Fighting</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Bouncers (U).cue</path>
    <name>Bouncers</name>
    <desc>Arcade basketball game where YOU are the ball. You can't jump high enough on your own to go through the hoop, so you must bounce off other players. Supports up to four simultaneous players.

There are eight characters to choose from, powerups (and powerdowns) that affect your speed and jumping ability.

Games can turn into fighting matches of sorts, as players can kick each other to get their opponent in the air. With practice, you can learn to shoot three pointers and slam dunk yourself into the basket.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Bouncers (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19940101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Dynamix, Inc.</developer>
    <publisher>Sega</publisher>
    <genre>Sports</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Bram Stoker's Dracula (U).cue</path>
    <name>Bram Stoker's Dracula</name>
    <desc>Bram Stoker's Dracula sucks you into a terrifying world of evil. And there's only one way to survive. Kill the Prince of Darkness! But it won't be easy. From deep in the cold, dark dungeons of Castle Dracula to the brutal Transylvanian countryside, you'll be in a constant fight for your life. As the sun sets, the evil Prince of Darkness rises and attacks as a bat, a vicious wolf, even an old man. With every multiple level - each divided into day and night - you're plunged deeper into the ultimate interactive experience, as Dracula rises in search of blood... yours! Incredibly realistic 3D graphics, digitized footage from the actual movie, CD sound, and characters based on real actors, turn this game into the ultimate interactive horror movie for your Sega CD.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Bram Stoker's Dracula (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19940610T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Psygnosis Limited</developer>
    <publisher>Sony Imagesoft</publisher>
    <genre>Action, Fighting, Horror</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Brutal - Paws of Fury (U).cue</path>
    <name>Brutal: Paws of Fury</name>
    <desc>Brutal: Paws of Fury is a standard one-on-one beat 'em up across a variety of levels, with mostly outdoor terrain. You can choose of the many characters. Throughout the game, your character travels across Dalai Llama's island, fighting a series of duels before getting to the final showdown.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Brutal - Paws of Fury (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19930101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>GameTek, Inc.</developer>
    <publisher>GameTek, Inc.</publisher>
    <genre>Fighting</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Bug Blasters - The Exterminators (U).cue</path>
    <name>Bug Blasters: The Exterminators</name>
    <desc>Bug Blasters: The Exterminators is an Action game, developed by Stargate and published by Good Deal Games, which was released in Europe in 2000.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Bug Blasters - The Exterminators (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>20160106T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Good Deal Games, Stargate Productions</developer>
    <publisher>Good Deal Games, Stargate Productions</publisher>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Burning Fists - Force Striker (U).cue</path>
    <name>Burning Fists: Force Striker</name>
    <desc>Burning Fist (also known as Force Striker in its early alpha build) is a cancelled fighting game that was in development in 1994 by Sega of Japan for the Mega CD. As we can read at Sega Base, both the Force Striker alpha and the Burning Fists beta were leaked rom a former SoJ employee and sold on eBay some years ago. Burning Fist was never officially released, but in 2006 those alpha / beta builds were re-sold to Good Deal Games.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Burning Fists - Force Striker (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>20060726T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Sega</developer>
    <publisher>Good Deal Games</publisher>
    <genre>Fighting</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Cadillacs &amp; Dinosaurs - The Second Cataclysm (U).cue</path>
    <name>Cadillacs and Dinosaurs: The Second Cataclysm</name>
    <desc>You find yourself in the so-called Xenozoic Age - after a cataclysm in 2020 A.D., mankind was forced to hide beneath the surface. Once it could come out again, it found the world terribly changed, with dinosaurs roaming freely once again. A mysterious mutant-like race, called the Grith, believe the cataclysm was caused by the upsetting of the natural balance. Now, the leader of the restored City in the Sea, Scharnhorst, is using old technology and disrupting the balance again. The Girth chose you, Jack Tenrec, and your partner Hannah Dundee, to rid the world of Scharnhorst. And you get to do it in a red '53 Cadillac with mounted machine guns.

While you're at the task, you must battle hungry, mean dinosaurs, but also be careful not to upset the balance of nature. Also, try not to upset your volcanic-energy fueled caddy by hitting too much obstacles along the way.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Cadillacs &amp; Dinosaurs - The Second Cataclysm (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19940101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Rocket Science Games</developer>
    <publisher>Rocket Science Games, Inc.</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Championship Soccer '94 (U).cue</path>
    <name>Championship Soccer '94</name>
    <desc>Sensible Soccer (known in the US as Championship Soccer '94) is a soccer (football) game similar to the Kick Off series. The graphical view is from a distance overhead, making the players small on screen, but allowing player to view around half the pitch.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Championship Soccer '94 (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19940101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Sensible Software</developer>
    <publisher>Sega</publisher>
    <genre>Sports</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Chuck Rock (U).cue</path>
    <name>Chuck Rock</name>
    <desc>Chuck Rock is your typical average cave man. He likes to spend his Sunday afternoons watching football and drinking beer. Unfortunately, his peaceful existence is interrupted one day when his wife, Ophelia Rock, is kidnapped by the village wierdo, Gary Gritter. So, Chuck is rather upset about this whole situation and you have to help him make things right.

The game is a side-scrolling platformer. Chuck fights of a variety of dinosaurs using his belly-buster attack and a jump kick. Occasionally he has to pick up and throw rocks to defeat enemies and allow him to jump to greater heights.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Chuck Rock (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19920101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Core Design Ltd.</developer>
    <publisher>Virgin Games, Ltd.</publisher>
    <genre>Platform</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Chuck Rock II - Son of Chuck (U).cue</path>
    <name>Chuck Rock II: Son of Chuck</name>
    <desc>The story in this Chuck Rock game takes up a little while after the end of the first game. As you may remember, Chuck Rock had to rescue his girl, Ophelia from the bad dude Gary Gritter. Well, he was successful in his efforts, and now Chuck and Ophelia are married. Eventually, they have a son, named Junior. Chuck works in a factory, where he develops great skill at carving automobiles out of stone. A rival manufacturer becomes jealous of Chuck's abilities and kidnaps him. Now it is up to Junior to rescue his dad!

The gameplay in this sequel is similar to the first game, but with some minor differences since you are playing as Junior, rather than Chuck. This is a side-scrolling platform game with occasional rock-moving puzzles thrown in. Unlike Chuck, Junior carries a club that gives his attacks further reach.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Chuck Rock II - Son of Chuck (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19930101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Core Design Ltd.</developer>
    <publisher>Virgin Games, Ltd.</publisher>
    <genre>Action, Puzzle</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Citizen X (U) (Unreleased).cue</path>
    <name>Citizen X</name>
    <desc>OUR WORST FEARS HAVE COME TRUE!!

An elite terrorist organization lead by a madman has vowed to destroy the world as we know it. Saving the world 
might not have been in your weekend plans but things change.

You are the only one left to take on a task which literally fell into your lap. A dying government agent begs you to continue her failed mission while handing you a hi-tech watch connected to the command center now giving you orders.

Diseased sewer rats, psychotic circus clowns, mafia hitmen, and cannibalistic martial arts masters are just a few of the obstacles in your way. Let's not forget, you will still need to find the antidote to save the human race from biowarfare extinction!

Oh yeah, one more important thing
-- you only have 15 minutes...

Citizen X is an unreleased Sega Mega-CD game developed by Digital Pictures. It was a side-scrolling action game paired with many full motion video cutscenes set for release in 1993.

Though the game was not officially released, a mostly-finished prototype emerged and was distributed commercially by Good Deal Games in 2002.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Citizen X (U) (Unreleased)-image.jpg</image>
    <publisher>Good Deal Games</publisher>
    <genre>Fighting</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Cliffhanger (U).cue</path>
    <name>Cliffhanger</name>
    <desc>CLIFFHANGER challenges you to brave thundering avalanches, icy cliffs and the head-spinning heights of the Rocky Mountains while combatting a vicious group of well-armed, extremely dangerous fugitives. Based on the white-knuckle, action-adventure movie starring Sylvester Stallone, you'll hang on for dear life through seven exciting levels requiring all your strength and skill just to survive. Experience the excitement of incredible hand-to-hand action and armed combat. The adventure isn't over until you find $100 million in stolen loot, defeat the fugitives, and reunite with your friends.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Cliffhanger (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19931204T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Malibu Interactive</developer>
    <publisher>Sony Imagesoft</publisher>
    <genre>Action, Fighting</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Cobra Command (U).cue</path>
    <name>Cobra Command</name>
    <desc>Cobra Command is an arcade conversion of a helicopter shooting game from Data East. It is an "on rails" style shooter with the player controlling only the aiming of the shooting but not the direction of the helicopter.

Your job is to shoot down the enemies as you are flown through footage of New York streets, the Statue of Liberty, the Atlantic Ocean, Italy, the Grand Canyon and finally, the treacherous corners and return fire of the enemy's stronghold on Easter Island.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Cobra Command (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19921101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Data East Corporation</developer>
    <publisher>Renovation Products, Inc.</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Colors of Modern Rock, The (U).cue</path>
    <name>The Colors of Modern Rock</name>
    <desc>Demo disc: The best new rock comes alive in Virtual VCR</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Colors of Modern Rock, The (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19930101T000000</releasedate>
    <publisher>WB Games</publisher>
    <genre>Music</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Compton's Interactive Encyclopedia (U).cue</path>
    <name>Compton's Interactive Encyclopedia</name>
    <desc>Compton's Interactive Encyclopedia is a 1994 software program developed by The Learning Company for the Mega-CD; it was only released in North America, both as a stand-alone product and as a pack-in with the X'eye.

CIE is, of course, an multimedia encyclopedia licensed from the Compton's series of print encyclopedias, sporting a comparatively impressive 34,000 subjects, 5,000 pictures, and 30 video articles from the American Library Accociation.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Compton's Interactive Encyclopedia (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19940101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>The Learning Company</developer>
    <publisher>Sega</publisher>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Corpse Killer (U).cue</path>
    <name>Corpse Killer</name>
    <desc>Corpse Killer is a full-motion-video (FMV) shoot-'em up. It seems the evil genius Dr. Hellman has found a way to raise the dead and created an island of zombies. The player is an elite special forces soldier who has been parachuted onto the island; it is up to them to shoot their way through the undead hordes and stop Dr. Hellman.

The game is played from a first-person perspective. Various zombies pop up in front of a video background and the player must shoot them down either by moving a mouse cursor on screen or by using a light gun.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Corpse Killer (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19940101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Digital Pictures</developer>
    <publisher>Digital Pictures, Inc.</publisher>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Crime Patrol (U).cue</path>
    <name>Crime Patrol</name>
    <desc>Crime Patrol puts the player in the shoes of a police officer, who starts as a Rookie and has to work his way up to become a member of SWAT and eventually the Delta Force team. To do that, he has to complete missions, which involve taking down criminals in a variety of locations. Beginning with smaller-scale criminals (such as shoplifters), the hero will later have to face gangsters, drug lords, and eventually terrorists. For each set of missions, the player characters is being teamed up with another police officer. The gameplay is quite similar to any other of the large live-action laser-gun games found in the arcades - all the player has to do is take the gun (or the mouse in the computer version) and show those criminals who's the boss!</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Crime Patrol (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19940101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>American Laser Games, Inc.</developer>
    <publisher>American Laser Games, Inc.</publisher>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Cyborg 009 (J).cue</path>
    <name>Cyborg 009</name>
    <desc>Cyborg 009 (&amp;#x30B5;&amp;#x30A4;&amp;#x30DC;&amp;#x30FC;&amp;#x30B0;&amp;#xFF10;&amp;#xFF10;&amp;#xFF19;) is a Sega Mega-CD action game released exclusively in Japan.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Cyborg 009 (J)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19930730T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Telenet Japan</developer>
    <publisher>Riot</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Dark Wizard (U).cue</path>
    <name>Dark Wizard</name>
    <desc>These are epic times for the people of Cheshire. The kingdom of Quentin is the last stronghold in all of Cheshire against the forces of darkness. But Quentin's king has been killed in battle. Cheshire desperately needs a successor to come forward and lead the warriors of light against the forces of darkness and, eventually, against the Dark Wizard himself. If you fail, darkness will rule Cheshire - forever!</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Dark Wizard (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19931112T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>H.I.C.</developer>
    <publisher>Sega</publisher>
    <genre>Role-Playing</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Demolition Man (U).cue</path>
    <name>Demolition Man</name>
    <desc>Two men enter the future. bringing with them the values of a brutal past. One cop. One criminal. One mission: destroy the other man first! You're John Spartan, freshly dethawed from the San Angeles Cryo-Prison. Armed with shotguns, magnum handguns and grenades, hunt Simon Phoenix through 10 explosive Levels from the ravaged Wasteland to the Hall of Violence!

Be WeII.
DEMOLITION MAN...

-Control DEMOLITION MAN John Spartan in the futuristic action adventure based on the Warner bros/John Silver (Die Hard and Lethal Weapon I and II) hit movie.

-Multiple player perspectives including side-scrolling and top-down view.

-10 explosive levels including an infra-red chase through the subterranean Wasteland.

-Shoot enemies from all angles with a stash of grenades, shotguns and the magnum handgun.

-Track down Simon Phoenix and his escaped cryo-cons on the hazardous city streets and decidedly dangerous Wastelands of San Angeles.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Demolition Man (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19951115T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Alexandria</developer>
    <publisher>Acclaim Entertainment, Inc.</publisher>
    <genre>Action, Platform</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Devastator (J).cue</path>
    <name>Devastator</name>
    <desc>Ryo begins working for a company called Yaesu as a replacement for his friend Masato. During a test ride with a new machine, however, he is somehow thrown into another dimension. After being rescued there by a group of mecha pilots from vile creatures named Devastators, he learns that nefarious people are working on a connection between that and his own dimension, and sets out to stop them.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Devastator (J)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19930528T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Wolf Team</developer>
    <publisher>Wolf Team</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Double Switch (U).cue</path>
    <name>Double Switch</name>
    <desc>Double Switch is a "trap-'em-up" game very similar to Night Trap in gameplay and visual presentation. The player has to manipulate cameras to avoid or set traps, affecting the course of the storyline which is represented by live action movie sequences.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Double Switch (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19930101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Digital Pictures</developer>
    <publisher>Sega</publisher>
    <genre>Adventure, Horror</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Dragon's Lair (U).cue</path>
    <name>Dragon's Lair</name>
    <desc>Dragon's Lair features the hero, Dirk the Daring, attempting to rescue Princess Daphne from the evil dragon Singe, who has locked Daphne in a wizard's castle. The screen shows animated scenes, and the player executes an action by selecting a direction or pressing the sword button with correct timing. The comedy of the game stemmed not only from the bizarre looking creatures and death scenes, but also the fact that while Dirk was a skilled knight, he was somewhat clumsy in his efforts, as well as being a reluctant hero, prone to shrieking and reacting in horror to the various dangers he encounters.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Dragon's Lair (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19940619T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Advanced Microcomputer Systems</developer>
    <publisher>Taito Corporation</publisher>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Dune (U).cue</path>
    <name>Dune</name>
    <desc>Based on the legendary Frank Herbert novel of the same name and visually inspired by the 1984 David Lynch movie, Dune is a strategy-adventure hybrid where the player takes the role of young Paul Atreides, the son of Duke Leto. The Emperor Shaddam Corrino IV has given the Atreides House the rights to manage the extraction of the most precious substance in the entire universe - the Melange, commonly known as Spice in the desolate desert planet Arrakis (Dune), the only place in the universe capable of producing the substance. While everything indicates the offer is a trap orchestrated by their enemies the Harkonnen, the Atreides family agrees on moving, as he who controls the spice, controls the universe.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Dune (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19930101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Cryo Interactive Entertainment</developer>
    <publisher>Sega</publisher>
    <genre>Strategy</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Dungeon Explorer (U).cue</path>
    <name>Dungeon Explorer</name>
    <desc>Dungeon Explorer is an action role-playing game. It supports up to four players with a choice of six different character classes: monk, knight, elf, mage, beast and ninja. The game starts in the area surrounding a save point. This area functions as a central hub to access all the six dungeons. If a character leaves it, the food counter starts decreasing. If it reaches zero, the life points start diminishing until the character dies. Food can be found as potions or pots around the mazes. Returning the character to the save point area replenishes all the counters and cures all conditions (like poisoning and confusion). The gold collected in the game can be spent on equipment upgrades at the weapons shop. The tavern allows the player to switch characters.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Dungeon Explorer (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19940101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Hudson Entertainment, Inc.</developer>
    <publisher>Sega</publisher>
    <genre>Action, Role-Playing</genre>
    <players>4</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Dungeon Master II - Skull Keep (U).cue</path>
    <name>Dungeon Master II: Skullkeep</name>
    <desc>The game fuses real-time battles with puzzle solving and travelling, although the game now auto-maps. Rain and magic usage effects are incorporated into the engine. The first part of the game is spent above ground, visiting villages with shops and temples, and trawling through forests.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Dungeon Master II - Skull Keep (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19940101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>FTL Games</developer>
    <publisher>JVC Musical Industries, Inc.</publisher>
    <genre>Role-Playing</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Dynamic Country Club - 3D Golf Simulation (J).cue</path>
    <name>Dynamic Country Club: 3D Golf Simulation</name>
    <desc>Dynamic Country Club (&amp;#x30C0;&amp;#x30A4;&amp;#x30CA;&amp;#x30DF;&amp;#x30C3;&amp;#x30AF;&amp;#x30AB;&amp;#x30F3;&amp;#x30C8;&amp;#x30EA;&amp;#x30FC;&amp;#x30AF;&amp;#x30E9;&amp;#x30D6;) is a 1991 arcade golf game by Sega released on Sega System 24 hardware. Both floppy disk-based and ROM board-based versions of the game exist. The game presents itself in a pseudo-3D setting a la T&amp;E Soft golf games like Pebble Beach Golf Links where the screen slowly redraws itself at certain intervals in your swing.

A game with the same name for the Sega Mega-CD was produced, but only released in Japan. Whether or not this is the same game is unknown.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Dynamic Country Club - 3D Golf Simulation (J)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19930706T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Sega AM3 R&amp;D Division</developer>
    <publisher>Sega</publisher>
    <genre>Sports</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Earnest Evans (J).cue</path>
    <name>Earnest Evans</name>
    <desc>In the 1930's, famed archaeologist Earnest Evans unearthed his greatest challenge: three ancient idols that together could bring an end to life on Earth. The idols were scattered at random throughout the world by the god of the winds, Hastur, before its power was crushed. Yet Evans was injured before he could complete the search.

Fifty years pass and now its up to Dr. Evans' grandson Earnest to save the world.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Earnest Evans (J)-image.png</image>
    <releasedate>19911220T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Wolf Team</developer>
    <publisher>Wolf Team</publisher>
    <genre>Action, Platform</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Earthworm Jim - Special Edition (U).cue</path>
    <name>Earthworm Jim: Special Edition</name>
    <desc>This special edition includes: a password system, a new world &amp; new hidden Areas, a new weapon, over 1000 additional frames of animation. All new CD quality soundtrack, totally new endings in two of the worlds, all the extra cool ideas and special features that Shiny couldn't fit onto the cartridge are on this special edition.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Earthworm Jim - Special Edition (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19950315T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Shiny Entertainment, Inc.</developer>
    <publisher>Playmates Interactive Entertainment, Inc.</publisher>
    <genre>Platform</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Ecco - The Tides of Time (U).cue</path>
    <name>Ecco: The Tides of Time</name>
    <desc>The Tides of Time picked up right where the original Ecco the Dolphin left off. It turned out that the Vortex Queen was far from vanquished, and had, in fact, followed Ecco to Earth to build a new hive for herself. Ecco lost his powers from the Asterite early on, and soon after met a dolphin with unusually long fins. She was his descendant, Trellia, and had come to take him to her present in Ecco's distant future.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Ecco - The Tides of Time (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19940825T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Novotrade International</developer>
    <publisher>Sega</publisher>
    <genre>Action, Adventure</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Ecco the Dolphin (U).cue</path>
    <name>Ecco the Dolphin</name>
    <desc>The game begins with Ecco as he and his pod are swimming in their home bay. One podmate challenges him to see how high into the air he can jump. When he is in the air, a waterspout storm forms and sucks up all marine life in the bay except Ecco, leaving him alone in the bay. Upon leaving the bay to search for his pod, he contacts several dolphins from other pods, who tell him the entire sea is in chaos, and that all marine creatures had felt the storm. After talking to an orca, Ecco travels to the Arctic to find a blue whale named The Big Blue. The Big Blue tells him such storms had been occurring every 500 years and directs him to the Asterite, the oldest creature on Earth. He leaves the Arctic and travels to a deep cavern where he finds the Asterite. Although it has the power to aid him, one of its globes is missing, and needs it returned. However, this can only be achieved by traveling back in time using a machine built by the ancient Atlanteans.
Ecco travels to the sunken city of Atlantis, where he discovers the time machine and an ancient library. He learns the cause of the storm; it was a harvest of Earth's waters that was conducted every 500 years by an alien species known as the Vortex. The Vortex had lost their ability to make their own food, and so every 500 years, they would harvest from the waters of Earth. Learning this, he activates the time machine and travels 55 million years into Earth's past. Ecco locates the Asterite in the past but is immediately attacked by it. Forced into battle, he manages to dislodge a globe from it. This opens a time portal and he is sent back into the present. After receiving the globe, the Asterite grants him the power to turn his sonar into a deadly weapon against the Vortex, as well as the abilities to breathe underwater and to slowly regenerate lost health. The Asterite instructs him to use the time machine to travel back in time to the hour of the harvest. This time he manages to be sucked into the waterspout with his pod. Once inside the waterspout, Ecco makes his way towards the Vortex Queen, the leader of the Vortex race. Eventually, the Vortex Queen is destroyed and Ecco rescues his pod.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Ecco the Dolphin (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19920729T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Novotrade International</developer>
    <publisher>Sega</publisher>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Egawa Suguru no Super League CD (J).cue</path>
    <name>Egawa Suguru no Super League CD</name>
    <desc>Egawa Suguru no Super League CD (&amp;#x6C5F;&amp;#x5DDD;&amp;#x5353;&amp;#x306E;&amp;#x30B9;&amp;#x30FC;&amp;#x30D1;&amp;#x30FC;&amp;#x30EA;&amp;#x30FC;&amp;#x30B0;&amp;#xFF23;&amp;#xFF24;) is a baseball game released as part of the Super League and a sequel to Pro Yakyuu Super League CD (?).</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Egawa Suguru no Super League CD (J)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19930806T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Sega</developer>
    <publisher>Sega</publisher>
    <genre>Sports</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./ESPN Baseball Tonight (U).cue</path>
    <name>ESPN Baseball Tonight</name>
    <desc>ESPN Baseball Tonight is a baseball game with both exhibition and playoff modes. Other modes included are both practice (both pitching and batting) and Home Run Derby modes. The game contains 28 real MLB teams but no actual players. Gameplay options include being able to turn errors on or off and to have assisted fielding on or off.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/ESPN Baseball Tonight (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19930101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Park Place Productions</developer>
    <publisher>Sony</publisher>
    <genre>Sports</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./ESPN National Hockey Night (U).cue</path>
    <name>ESPN National Hockey Night</name>
    <desc>ESPN National Hockey Night was one of the many hockey games released back in the day. This one featured all the NHL teams for its time, but lacked an official players license.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/ESPN National Hockey Night (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19940101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Park Place Productions</developer>
    <publisher>Sony</publisher>
    <genre>Sports</genre>
    <players>4</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./ESPN NBA Hang Time '95 (U).cue</path>
    <name>ESPN NBA HangTime '95</name>
    <desc>NBA HAngtime '95 takes it to the hoop with the ultimate in 2-on-2 half-court action. Choose from 81 of the hottest players in the NBA from all 27 teams. Special button combos let you unleash awesome player moves - two handed power dunks by Hakeem Olajuwon, reverse dunks by Chris Webber, spin moves by Scottie Pippen and more! Then for something completely different, play ESPN 2-on-2 World Tour mode with streetball players from around the world. NBA Hangtime '95, Everything Else is Just Practice.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/ESPN NBA Hang Time '95 (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19940101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Sony Imagesoft</developer>
    <publisher>Sony Imagesoft</publisher>
    <genre>Sports</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./ESPN Sunday Night NFL (U).cue</path>
    <name>ESPN Sunday Night NFL</name>
    <desc>ESPN Sunday Night NFL was one of the many football games released back in the day. It features all 28 official NFL teams and their respective logos, but doesn't feature a license from the NFLPA, so there are no actual players names in the game.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/ESPN Sunday Night NFL (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19930101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Ringler Studios</developer>
    <publisher>Sony</publisher>
    <genre>Sports</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Eternal Champions (U).cue</path>
    <name>Eternal Champions: Challenge from the Dark Side</name>
    <desc>From various time periods of past, present and future, nine fighters killed in an unjust manner find themselves given a second chance for life. An alien being, known only as the Eternal Champion, brings back the fighters into a competition for one reason: to find one among them worthy of being resurrected, giving them a chance to avert their death and tip the balance between good and evil.

The fighters range from different eras of Earth's History: Larcen, the cat burglar. Jetta, the circus acrobat. Blade, the futuristic bounty hunter. Midknight, the vampiric bio-chemist. Rax, the cyborg. Shadow, the corporate assassin. Slash, the neanderthal. Trident, a Atlantean warrior. And Xavier, a warlock and alchemist.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Eternal Champions (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19940101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>SEGA Interactive Development Division</developer>
    <publisher>Sega</publisher>
    <genre>Fighting</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./F1 Circus CD (J).cue</path>
    <name>F1 Circus CD</name>
    <desc>F1 Circus CD (&amp;#xFF26;&amp;#xFF11;&amp;#x30B5;&amp;#x30FC;&amp;#x30AB;&amp;#x30B9;&amp;#xFF23;&amp;#xFF24;) is a formula one racing game released for the Sega Mega-CD exclusively in Japan. It is the sequel to F1 Circus MD.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/F1 Circus CD (J)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19940308T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Nichibutsu</developer>
    <publisher>Nihon Bussan Co., Ltd.</publisher>
    <genre>Racing</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Fatal Fury Special (U).cue</path>
    <name>Fatal Fury Special</name>
    <desc>Fatal Fury Special is an improved version of SNK's 2D one-on-one fighter Fatal Fury 2. It's a conversion of the 1993 arcade game of the same name. The objective is still to win the tournament by defeating all other fighters including end boss Wolfgang Krauser. 
Fatal Fury Special still features the series' trademark pseudo-3D movement along two planes.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Fatal Fury Special (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19930101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>SNK</developer>
    <publisher>JVC Musical Industries, Inc.</publisher>
    <genre>Fighting</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./FIFA International Soccer (U).cue</path>
    <name>FIFA International Soccer</name>
    <desc>Based on international teams (with fictional player names), their abilities in each skill area rated out of 10 to give the player an overall impression of how good they are. The options available follow the standard set: fouls and offsides can be toggled on and off, the match length can be set, and if the timer operates continuously, or only while the ball is in play. Gameplay privileges quick runs, short passes and blistering shots outside the penalty box, and set pieces are controlled by moving a box into the target area for the ball, and then passed, lobbed or kicked directly. On the tactical side, formations can be selected, with 5 different strategies also available (although not all of these combinations make sense) as can the team Coverage - the areas which defenders, midfielders and strikers cover.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/FIFA International Soccer (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19940101T000000</releasedate>
    <publisher>EA Sports</publisher>
    <genre>Sports</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Final Fight CD (U).cue</path>
    <name>Final Fight CD</name>
    <desc>Final Fight punches its way onto Sega CD.

When the Mad Gear Gang is around, you know laws are being broken. Enter the good guys, Haggar, Cody and Guy, with killer roundhouse kicks, back fists, uppercuts and body slams. All raging to the coolest CD quality tunes. When the going gets tough, grab a pipe, knife or sword, and take a slice out of crime!

* 6 brutal levels of street fighting head trauma and shattered rib cages!
* Choose from 3 characters for 1 or 2 player bone-busting action!
* Arcade-quality music and sound effects.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Final Fight CD (U)-image.png</image>
    <releasedate>19930701T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Capcom</developer>
    <publisher>Capcom</publisher>
    <genre>Action, Fighting</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Flashback - The Quest for Identity (U).cue</path>
    <name>Flashback: The Quest for Identity</name>
    <desc>You've lost your mind! You're trapped on a distant planet inhabited by aliens plotting to overtake the Earth. The only problem is - you don't even know who you are! To stop the alien attack, you must discover your true identity and fight your way back through the galaxy to warn Earth!</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Flashback - The Quest for Identity (U)-image.png</image>
    <releasedate>19921202T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Delphine Software International</developer>
    <publisher>U.S. Gold Ltd.</publisher>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Formula One World Championship - Beyond the Limit (U).cue</path>
    <name>Formula One World Championship: Beyond the Limit</name>
    <desc>Beyond the Limit is a racing sim based on Formula One circa 1993. It features real-life cars, tracks, and drivers from the world of F1.

The graphics in Beyond the Limit are created from scaled and rotated sprites that create a 3D effect. It also features a lot of full-screen video clips taken from Fuji TV's coverage of actual races.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Formula One World Championship - Beyond the Limit (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19940424T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Fuji Television Network</developer>
    <publisher>Sega</publisher>
    <genre>Racing</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Heart of the Alien (U).cue</path>
    <name>Heart of the Alien: Out of this World Parts I And II</name>
    <desc>Enter the award-winning sci fi universe of Out of This World. A cool blue world where the past and future coexist. Where electric torture chambers are manned by primitive humanoids. And the merciful turn merciless just to survive. Imagine an alien prison. Where every passage you enter is one you may never exit. Every creature lives to try and take your life. And the further you run the closer you get to the sadist they call The Warden.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Heart of the Alien (U)-image.png</image>
    <releasedate>19940101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Delphine Software International</developer>
    <publisher>Virgin Games, Ltd.</publisher>
    <genre>Puzzle</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Heavy Nova (J).cue</path>
    <name>Heavy Nova</name>
    <desc>Heavy Nova (&amp;#x30D8;&amp;#x30D3;&amp;#x30FC;&amp;#x30CE;&amp;#x30D0;) is a 1991 action game for the Sharp X68000 by Micronet. It was ported to the Sega Mega-CD as one of the system's two launch titles (the other being Wolf Team's Sol-Feace); the Mega-CD port was not released outside Japan. Micronet subsequently ported it to the Sega Mega Drive for an American release in 1992.

You play as a giant mech beating up other mechs of various sizes. A punches and B kicks. Up rockets up for as long as the button is held; you will eventually come back down.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Heavy Nova (J)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19911212T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Micronet Co. Ltd.</developer>
    <publisher>Micronet Co. Ltd.</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Heimdall (U).cue</path>
    <name>Heimdall</name>
    <desc>You play as Heimdall, a demi-god based in Norse mythology. Heimdall's job is to protect the entrance to Asgard, the home of the gods, from all evil, including the terrible Ragnarok, when all the evil forces come together to try and destroy the gods and ultimately everything.

Unfortunately Ragnarok is on its way and if that wasn't bad enough, Loki, god of mischief, has hidden Thor's hammer, Odin's sword and Frey's spear in three worlds. You, as the newly mortalized Heimdall, must visit each of these worlds to collect the god's weapons.

The first is Midgard (or Earth), the second is Utgard (the world of the giants) and the third is Asgard itself, the home of the gods. Each world has around 15 islands and each island has countless rooms.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Heimdall (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19940101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Core Design Ltd.</developer>
    <publisher>JVC Musical Industries, Inc.</publisher>
    <genre>Role-Playing</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Hook (U).cue</path>
    <name>Hook</name>
    <desc>PETER PAN has now grown up, far away from NEVERLAND, but his old enemy CAPTAIN HOOK has not forgotten, and schemes his revenge. Kidnapping Peter's children, he lures our hero back to the island of PIRATES and "LOST BOYS" for a final confrontation. With the help of TINKERBELL, the faithful fairy, you take on the role of PETER PAN in this magic adventure fraught with danger and excitement!</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Hook (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19920401T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Ocean Software Ltd., Ocean, Enigma Variations Ltd</developer>
    <publisher>Sony Imagesoft</publisher>
    <genre>Action, Adventure</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./INXS - Make My Video (U).cue</path>
    <name>INXS: Make My Video</name>
    <desc>Make My Video: INXS is a video game based on real-time editing of music video footage. The setup is that a pair of female friends is hanging around a bar and monopolizing the pool table. The game explores the duo's interpersonal interactions with other patrons at the bar: There's the Fly, an aloof cool guy; Ted and Gomez, braindead surfer dudes trying to pick up the ladies, and who are thinly-veiled parodies of Bill &amp; Ted; Poindexter, the nerd who is also trying to work up the courage to talk to the women; and Flo and Tiger, a pair of leather-clad tough chicks whose interest is beating the main subjects of the game so that they can control the bar music and play their Megadeth videotape. Each person or pair has own their ideas about what an ideal INXS video should or should not contain. The specifications normally come in the form of a set of pictures they either do or don't want to see, and perhaps some effects. The game features three INXS videos from which to choose: "Heaven Sent", "Not Enough Time", and "Baby Don&amp;#x2019;t Cry".</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/INXS - Make My Video (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19921015T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Digital Pictures</developer>
    <publisher>Sega</publisher>
    <genre>Music</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Iron Helix (U).cue</path>
    <name>Iron Helix</name>
    <desc>A rogue navy ship, Jeremiah Obrian, threatens to start a war. A virus has wiped out its crew, but the threat of it firing its Iron Helix doomsday weapon is still there. You must remotely pilot an unarmed science robot to explore the ship and work out how to shut the weapon down.

The game uses interactive quarter-screen footage to display the ship's interiors. The main challenge is that an automated security device is chasing you down, and must be avoided and ultimately destroyed. A delay between your commands and the robot's receipt of them forces you to pay close attention to the security drone and plan several steps ahead.

As you explore the ship, you will find data ports, which can be jacked into to gain information or to open doorways. To access most of these, you will need to find and collect a DNA sample from a member of staff whose role gave him/her access.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Iron Helix (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19920101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Drew Pictures</developer>
    <publisher>Spectrum Holobyte, Inc.</publisher>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Jaguar XJ220 (U).cue</path>
    <name>Jaguar XJ220</name>
    <desc>Jaguar XJ220 is a view from behind racer. There are 32 tracks all over the world, with varying road conditions and animated weather conditions such as rain and fog in England, snow in Switzerland, and tumbleweed crossing the street in Egypt. You race your Jaguar in a constructor grand prix, with opponents running for Porsche, Ferrari and other famous makers. Between races, you must mend the damage your car has sustained, which eats up your prize money.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Jaguar XJ220 (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19930101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Core Design Ltd.</developer>
    <publisher>JVC Musical Industries, Inc.</publisher>
    <genre>Racing</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Jeopardy! (U).cue</path>
    <name>Jeopardy!</name>
    <desc>Jeopardy! is an American quiz show featuring trivia in history, literature, the arts, pop culture, science, sports, geography, wordplay, and more. The show has a unique answer-and-question format in which contestants are presented with clues in the form of answers, and must phrase their responses in question form.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Jeopardy! (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19940101T000000</releasedate>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Joe Montana's NFL Football (U).cue</path>
    <name>Joe Montana's NFL Football</name>
    <desc>This enhanced version of the Joe Montana series features 3D models and even full-motion video of Joe Montana himself. It sports a full NFL license with all 28 teams of the time with their respective nicknames and logos, along with 10 of the all-time greatest Super Bowl teams including '85 Bears, the '72 Dolphins, just to name a few, that the player can compete against if they win the biggest game of the year.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Joe Montana's NFL Football (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19930101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Malibu Interactive</developer>
    <publisher>Sega</publisher>
    <genre>Sports</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Jurassic Park (U).cue</path>
    <name>Jurassic Park</name>
    <desc>This is the Sega CD game based on the 1993 Steven Spielberg movie based on the book by Michael Crichton. This game differs greatly from other Jurassic Park games. It is a point-and-click adventure game, with a strong emphasis on action sequences which require split-second timing.

The story takes place after the events of the movie/book. You are sent back to Jurassic Park to retrieve dinosaur eggs from around the park and put them in an incubator. You only have 12 hours to retrieve one egg from every species of dino in the park. Unfortunately, shortly before arriving at the park, your helicopter crashes!</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Jurassic Park (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19930101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Sega</developer>
    <publisher>Sega</publisher>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Keio Flying Squadron (U).cue</path>
    <name>Keio Flying Squadron</name>
    <desc>Keio Flying Squadron (&amp;#x6176;&amp;#x5FDC;&amp;#x904A;&amp;#x6483;&amp;#x968A; Kei&amp;#x14D;y&amp;#x16B;gekitai?) is a scrolling shooter video game developed and published by Victor Entertainment in 1994 for the Sega/Mega CD in Japan, Europe, and North America. It is the first game of the Keio Flying Squadron series with a simple shoot-'em-up style of play.
Gameplay
The game consists of the protagonist Rami riding on top of Spot, who can shoot fireballs at enemies. When Spot is not firing, two smaller dragons (Companion fighters) appear one after another to assist Rami and Spot. The lesser dragons shoot smaller fireballs and can be sacrificed to do larger damage, only to reappear when Spot ceases to shoot.
Release
In Europe, a demo of the first level of this game was provided by Sega Pro magazine. The game seemed to end after the first level, but in fact the whole game was accessible on the disc by using a level-select cheat to skip to the second level, and then continuing through the game.
Reception
Retro Gamer included among top ten Mega CD games, calling it "a perfectly acceptable substitute" OF Konami's Parodius that features "similar style of horizontally scrolling wackiness and puts the Mega-CD hardware to good use to produce some excellent cut-scenes and a brilliant CD-quality soundtrack."</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Keio Flying Squadron (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19930806T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Victor Musical Industries</developer>
    <publisher>JVC Musical Industries, Inc.</publisher>
    <genre>Action, Shooter</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Kids on Site (U).cue</path>
    <name>Kids on Site</name>
    <desc>Remember the days as a kid when you were fascinated with these big machines on the building site? With this game you have the opportunity to try them out! You can use either the excavator, bulldozer, steamroller or wrecking ball. The handling couldn't be easier, there are just three buttons to press: left, right and use.

With each machine you get a simple task, e.g. carry three shovels of dirt on a truck. But the fun thing is that you aren't restricted to this and can just screw around. Why wreck an old house when the pit latrine is so much more tempting? The whole game is presented in full motion video - the reactions are very humorous and with a fair share of slapstick. To improve the long time motivation there are even multiple videos for every action, e.g. the first time you break a road block with the the excavator you drive on a highway, the second time into a canyon, the third time onto a rollercoaster and so on...</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Kids on Site (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19940101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Digital Pictures</developer>
    <publisher>Sega</publisher>
    <genre>Construction and Management Simulation</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Kris Kross - Make My Video (U).cue</path>
    <name>Kris Kross: Make My Video</name>
    <desc>Make My Video: Kris Kross is a video game based on real-time editing of music video footage. The setup is that a radio DJ is taking calls from listeners who want to see custom videos for their favorite Kris Kross videos. The specifications normally come in the form of a set of pictures they either do or don't want to see, and perhaps some effects. The game has three Kris Kross videos from which to choose: "Jump", "Warm It Up", and "I Missed The Bus".

After receiving the video specifications, the player enters the video editing console in the EditChallenge mode. From this console, the player can view and select between 3 video streams that are playing. The selected stream will be edited into the final video. One stream is the original video while the other 2 feature assorted random footage that nonetheless often carries images that happened to have been specified in the video request. The video editing console also allows the player to apply a variety of real-time filters, such as mosaic and blur filters, RGB color filters, strobe and motion filters, lyric subtitles, among others.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Kris Kross - Make My Video (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19920101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Digital Pictures</developer>
    <publisher>Sony</publisher>
    <genre>Music</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Lawnmower Man, The (U).cue</path>
    <name>The Lawnmower Man</name>
    <desc>Based on the 1992 feature film, The Lawnmower Man is a collection of minigames based on the revolutionary virtual reality sequences seen in the movie. The plot parallels the central conflict - the player controls Dr. Angelo (Pierce Brosnan) as he heads into cyberspace to confront the psychotic digital god Jobe (Jeff Fahey) he has created.

As the ruler of his digital domain, Jobe shifts and manipulates the virtual world into a series of challenges to test the player. These range from digital IQ tests, chase sequences requiring precision timing for jumping and ducking, and a tunnel flight as one of the virtual jets from the movie. Characters from the movie are also digitized by Jobe into willing henchmen, and must be defeated by the player in a series of quick time events.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Lawnmower Man, The (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19940403T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>The Sales Curve Ltd.</developer>
    <publisher>Time Warner Interactive, Inc.</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Lethal Enforcers (U).cue</path>
    <name>Lethal Enforcers</name>
    <desc>Pick up your pistol and be the cop you need to be in order to rid the streets of the criminals out to make your day hell. Aim wisely and quickly, otherwise your lives will be lost quickly in this 1st person arcade shooter, cleaning up the streets. The higher the difficulty level, the more crimes there will be to eliminate, but watch out for the other weapons that can help you along the way.

Go straight into the mayhem, practice in the targeting range or have a friend back you up in two player mode. Use a gun accessory or play with the gamepad.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Lethal Enforcers (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19930101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Konami</developer>
    <publisher>Konami</publisher>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Lethal Enforcers II - Gun Fighters (U).cue</path>
    <name>Lethal Enforcers II: Gunfighters</name>
    <desc>In this sequel to Lethal Enforcers you are the sheriff of a town set in the old Wild West. Using the control pad or Konami's own Justifier lightgun, you'll be taking out outlaws who are robbing banks and kidnapping innocents. You have the opportunity to upgrade and keep you gun, as long as you don't shoot the people you are trying to save.

The action is usually shown on a single screen with enemies "popping out" from various sections. If you do not shoot them in time they will either shoot or throw various weapons at you. You will lose energy if they hit you or you hit an innocent civilian.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Lethal Enforcers II - Gun Fighters (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19941124T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Konami</developer>
    <publisher>Konami</publisher>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Links - The Challenge of Golf (U).cue</path>
    <name>Links: The Challenge of Golf</name>
    <desc>Links: The Challenge of Golf is a golf simulation that tries to implement realistic aspects of golf in a video game format.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Links - The Challenge of Golf (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19940101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Access Software, Inc.</developer>
    <publisher>Virgin Games, Ltd.</publisher>
    <genre>Sports</genre>
    <players>4</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Loadstar - The Legend of Tully Bodine (U).cue</path>
    <name>Loadstar: The Legend of Tully Bodine</name>
    <desc>Loadstar is a rail-shooter concerned with shooting enemies while navigating your ship, much like Sewer Shark. You're actually on rails in this game, as you travel in a truck/train called Loadstar along a magnetic rail network covering the moon. Shifting the cursor to the edge of the screen changes to a different track when available, with incorrect turns either killing you instantly or moving you off-course from the level end. Direction indicators and distant landmarks help keep you driving in the right direction, while accidents, track closures, and robot cops work to keep you from it. Your weapons "tag" enemies and force them to explode, or can tag incoming shots and deflect them with a separate shield button.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Loadstar - The Legend of Tully Bodine (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19940101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Rocket Science Games</developer>
    <publisher>Rocket Science Games, Inc.</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Lords of Thunder (U).cue</path>
    <name>Lords of Thunder</name>
    <desc>In the once peaceful land of Mistral, legend holds of a brave knight named Drak who has sealed an evil god named Deoric beneath the six continents of the land. However, peace never lasts. The Garuda Empire has invaded the lands of Mistral, and the six Dark Generals, led by Sornbul, have conquered the continents. Sornbul's ambition is nothing less than to resurrect Deoric and plunge the land into chaos.

Duran, descendant of Drak, is the only one who can stop the Garuda Empire's mad plan, and with the power of Drak's mystic armors, he heads off to stop Sornbul at any cost.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Lords of Thunder (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19950101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Hudson Entertainment, Inc.</developer>
    <publisher>Sega</publisher>
    <genre>Action, Shooter</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Lunar - Eternal Blue (U).cue</path>
    <name>Lunar: Eternal Blue</name>
    <desc>Come back to the enchanting world of Lunar! Join Hiro and Ruby 1,000 years after the first adventure, as they work to unlock the secrets of the Blue Spire and the strange young girl they found within it! But be careful! Forces are at work trying to revive the evil Zophar and immerse Lunar in darkness forever! Journey to distant lands in search of the Goddess Althena, who may be the only one powerful enough to stop Zophar. Along the way, you'll meet exciting new characters, fight fully animated monsters, traverse snow-covered peaks, and crawl through slimy dungeons as you work towards the terrifying climax!</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Lunar - Eternal Blue (U)-image.png</image>
    <releasedate>19950915T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Game Arts</developer>
    <publisher>Working Designs</publisher>
    <genre>Role-Playing</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Lunar - The Silver Star (U).cue</path>
    <name>Lunar: The Silver Star</name>
    <desc>Welcome to the world of Lunar, where dragons yet live and magic is valued above all else. Join Alex, the young adventurer as he begins a quest with his friends to save their land from the crushing advances of the Magic Emperor. Explore dungeons, fight terrifying monsters, and gather information from the locals as you advance toward the explosive confrontation with the Magic Emperor himself! Exciting, menu-driven combat will keep you challenged until the last. And thanks to the storage power of the CD, Lunar contains awesome animation sequences that'll get you involved in the story -- fast! Get ready for the ride of your life...</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Lunar - The Silver Star (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19931201T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Game Arts</developer>
    <publisher>Working Designs</publisher>
    <genre>Role-Playing</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Mad Dog II - The Lost Gold (U).cue</path>
    <name>Mad Dog II: The Lost Gold</name>
    <desc>The sequel to American Laser Game's original Mad Dog McCree, with pretty much the same gameplay and motion capture graphics. This PC conversion seems to have been tweaked a bit to be more stable than the original Mad Dog. There's also somewhat limited replay value as you can choose from 3 different guides for 3 different routes through the game.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Mad Dog II - The Lost Gold (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19940101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>American Laser Games, Inc.</developer>
    <publisher>American Laser Games, Inc.</publisher>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Mad Dog McCree (U).cue</path>
    <name>Mad Dog McCree</name>
    <desc>Mag Dog McCree and his gang have kidnapped the Mayor and his daughter, and its up to you to rescue them. You must blast through bars and bank robberies to take the gang out and save everything you regard as good and true. Where the game differs from other Operation Wolf-influenced shoot-'em-ups is in the use of live video, with real people appearing on the screen before you shoot them down. You have unlimited continues with which to reach the end, so the actors will have their screen deaths seen by as many people as they would had they starred in a film.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Mad Dog McCree (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19930101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>American Laser Games, Inc.</developer>
    <publisher>American Laser Games, Inc.</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Mansion of Hidden Souls (U).cue</path>
    <name>Mansion of Hidden Souls</name>
    <desc>Mansion of Hidden Souls is an adventure game created entirely with full-motion video. It takes place in a pre-rendered mansion that the player explores from a first-person perspective. As they wander from room to room, the action unfolds via video sequences.

The player takes on the role of Jonathan, a boy whose sister has wandered into the spooky mansion. When she entered the mansion, she disappeared! What's more, the mansion is full of talking butterflies. The player must search the whole mansion to unlock its secrets and find Jonathan's sister.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Mansion of Hidden Souls (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19931209T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>System Sacom</developer>
    <publisher>Sega</publisher>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Marko (U).cue</path>
    <name>Marko</name>
    <desc>A side-scrolling platformer featuring a kid and his magical soccer ball. Marko has to stop a mad scientist pumping any more dangerous mutation-causing sludge into the wildlife.

Marko's Magic Football, known as simply Marko in the US, is a side-scrolling platformer that is based around soccer. Marko has a soccer ball that magically returns to his feet whenever he needs it, and he can use to defeat enemies in various different ways: either by kicking the ball directly at them, or by bouncing it on his head to deter overhead enemies. It follows similar soccer platformers such as Hurricanes and Soccer Kid.

The game was developed by Domark Software for the Sega Genesis, Sega CD, Sega Game Gear and Super Nintendo. The Sega CD version contains additional cutscenes and redbook audio. The Oliver Twins, previously of Codemasters, were brought in to complete the game after Domark's lead programmer left close to the game's completion. They would work with Domark to produce console versions of Theme Park and Syndicate for the Sega CD.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Marko (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <developer>The Cartoon Mavericks</developer>
    <publisher>Good Deal Games</publisher>
    <genre>Platform</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Marky Mark and the Funky Bunch - Make My Video (U).cue</path>
    <name>Marky Mark and the Funky Bunch: Make My Video</name>
    <desc>Make My Video: Marky Mark and the Funky Bunch is a video game based on real-time editing of music video footage. The setup is that a brother and sister pair is arguing about what would make the best Marky Mark video. Since they can not agree, they enlist help from some other people: A boxer and his trainer, a trio of teenage girls, the members of a garage band, and their parents. Each group has their ideas about what an ideal Marky Mark video should or should not contain. The specifications normally come in the form of a set of pictures they either do or don't want to see, and perhaps some effects. The game has three Marky Mark videos from which to choose: "Good Vibrations", "I Need Money", and "You Gotta Believe".</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Marky Mark and the Funky Bunch - Make My Video (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19920101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Digital Pictures</developer>
    <publisher>Sega</publisher>
    <genre>Music</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Mary Shelley's Frankenstein (U).cue</path>
    <name>Mary Shelley's Frankenstein</name>
    <desc>MARY SHELLEY'S FRANKENSTEIN: Three game play views - isometric, forced isometric and side views - offer enhanced 3D environment. Six huge levels of action, from the cholera-infested streets of Ingolstadt to the freezing ice fields of the Arctic. Fantastic assortment of bosses including outlaws, landlords and wolves</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Mary Shelley's Frankenstein (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19941231T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Bits Studios</developer>
    <publisher>Sony Imagesoft</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Masked Rider, The - Kamen Rider ZO (U).cue</path>
    <name>The Masked Rider: Kamen Rider ZO</name>
    <desc>The Masked Rider is a Japanese super hero, a man who has become genetically altered to be a man/grasshopper who rides a motorcycle.

This FMV game adapts scenes from the movie Masked Rider ZO, and creates a Dragon's Lair style experience. The game centers around 10 battles of the film's 3 main characters.

The player watches the video and hits the correct direction or button at the right time to achieve success. The visual cues of the movie suggest the correct buttons. For example, when the Masked Rider punches, the player should press the Punch button. If he dodges left on screen, the player should press the left direction pad. Correct timing hits the enemy harder, lowering their health bar. Failure reduces the players health.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Masked Rider, The - Kamen Rider ZO (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19940101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Toei Animation</developer>
    <publisher>Sega</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./MegaRace (U).cue</path>
    <name>MegaRace</name>
    <desc>Virtual Television has given us a chance to do the things that we can't make real in everyday life: Race through 14 great tracks in 5 different environments in a totally virtual place where you can kill each other quite easily with sidekicks or guns. In every track you will see some symbols that can make your car speed up, slow up or even blow up, like your mega-host Lance Boyle says, "Who knows; who cares!" Everything you see in MegaRace is virtual and no one really dies there. So have fun!</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/MegaRace (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19940101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Cryo Interactive Entertainment</developer>
    <publisher>The Software Toolworks, Inc.</publisher>
    <genre>Racing</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Mickey Mania - The Timeless Adventures of Mickey Mouse (U).cue</path>
    <name>Mickey Mania: The Timeless Adventures of Mickey Mouse</name>
    <desc>Mickey has friends wherever he goes. Not here. No Goofy! No Minnie! No mercy! This is Mickey Mouse like you've never seen him before. Faster, tougher and smarter than ever. In 26 action-packed levels, Mickey takes on a ton of bosses from six of his coolest animated classics. From Steamboat Willie, The Mad Doctor and Moose Hunters to Lonesome Ghosts, Mickey and the Beanstalk and The Prince and the Pauper, this is Mickey on the adventure of a lifetime. Mickey Mania. This mouse roars!</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Mickey Mania - The Timeless Adventures of Mickey Mouse (U)-image.png</image>
    <releasedate>19941124T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Traveller's Tales Ltd.</developer>
    <publisher>Sony</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Microcosm (U).cue</path>
    <name>Microcosm</name>
    <desc>Microcosm is a 3D action shooter, similar to Descent, that takes place entirely within the human body. The concept was inspired by the 1966 movie Fantastic Voyage. The player pilots his way through various parts of the anatomy, blasting virii and enemy ships, while gaining power-ups and faster, stronger craft. The goal of the game is to eventually reach the brain to stop Grey M, the entity that controls Korsby's body.

Microcosm makes heavy use of full-motion video and features high-resolution fractal graphics (to simulate the walls of veins and arteries), digital music and sound effects.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Microcosm (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19930101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Psygnosis Limited</developer>
    <publisher>Psygnosis Limited</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Midnight Raiders (U).cue</path>
    <name>Midnight Raiders</name>
    <desc>A FMV rail shooter placing you in the helmet of rookie chopper gunner "Joker." Terrorists have kidnapped a German biochemist and taken him to a Middle Eastern oil refinery, where he is forced to work on a lethal toxin. Joker and crew must fly to the refinery, shooting down enemy tanks and helicopters, then Joker must rappel down to the refinery and rescue the chemist on foot.

The helicopter sections follow a pattern similar to Tomcat Alley, showing brief clips of the cast in the cockpit, followed by a "nose camera" shot of an enemy approaching. During this shot, you have the ability to move a set of crosshairs over the enemy and press the "fire" button. If you're on target, you are rewarded with military archival footage of helicopters shooting rockets, and close up footage of models exploding.

The on-foot sections follow an identical pattern, though with hand-held cameras placing you in the "eyes" of Joker, and black-clad guards taking the place of helicopters. Otherwise, the idea of having a few seconds to react and aim crosshairs is the same. The plot is expanded through occasional cutscenes in both the helicopter and foot sections.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Midnight Raiders (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19940401T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Stargate Productions</developer>
    <publisher>Sega</publisher>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Mighty Morphin Power Rangers (U).cue</path>
    <name>Mighty Morphin Power Rangers</name>
    <desc>This take on the Power Rangers franchise is different from the many other Power Ranger games as it features FMV with real video of the actual TV show. The footage is spliced from nine different episodes and the gameplay is reminiscent of games such as Dragon's Lair and Space Ace where the player must press a button at a certain time to avoid being punched, kicked, avoid a trap, etc. Failure to miss pressing a button will continue to play the footage, but cause the player to loose a life. After a certain set of lives are lost, the game will be over.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Mighty Morphin Power Rangers (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19950101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Saban</developer>
    <publisher>Sega</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Misadventures of Flink, The (U).cue</path>
    <name>Flink</name>
    <desc>Disaster strikes Imagica Island and Wicked Wainwright's taken over! He's kidnapped the four island leaders, separated them, and has them under the watchful eyes of the Demon Guardians. Excited by his newfound control, he's gone absolutely crazy! He's casting dark clouds of smoke across the land, bringing unpleasant weather and much sadness to the people of Imagica. In a huge panic, the islanders appoint Flink, an apprentice wizard, to challenge Wicked Wainwright and to force the Demon Guardians to release the island leaders. Locate the leaders, bring their powers together, and help make Flink the full-fledged wizard he's always wanted to be!</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Misadventures of Flink, The (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19941111T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Psygnosis Limited</developer>
    <publisher>Vic Tokai</publisher>
    <genre>Platform</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Mortal Kombat (U).cue</path>
    <name>Mortal Kombat</name>
    <desc>In Mortal Kombat, the player receives information concerning the backstories of the characters and their relationships with one another mainly in biographies that are displayed when the start button is not pressed, during attract mode in the title screen. These bios featured short videos of the characters taking their fighting stances and text informing the motives for each character to enter the tournament. The game takes place in a fantasy setting, with most of the game's events occurring on the fictional realms of the Mortal Kombat series. The original game is notably the only title in the series that features only one realm, that being Earthrealm. The tournament featured in the story actually takes place fully at Shang Tsung's Island, located somewhere on Earth, with seven of its locations serving as Kombat Zones.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Mortal Kombat (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19940526T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Midway</developer>
    <publisher>Arena Entertainment</publisher>
    <genre>Fighting</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./My Paint - The Animated Paint Program (U).cue</path>
    <name>My Paint: The Animated Paint Program</name>
    <desc>My Paint, the world's first animated paint program gives you the power to push your creativity to new heights! It's a full featured paint program you not only see, but hear! Freehand draw your own masterpiece or choose from any of the over 200 built-in drawings. Everything from Planes, Trains and Automobiles to Velociraptors, Bats and Panthers are included. Use any of the many patterns like dinosaur skins, moving water, stripes, dots, or the cool animated stickers to bring your drawings to life!</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/My Paint - The Animated Paint Program (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19930101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>WayForward Technologies</developer>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./NBA Jam (U).cue</path>
    <name>NBA Jam</name>
    <desc>NBA Jam is a two-on-two basketball game You can play any NBA team, and you can play as players like Barkley, Starks, Pippen, and Grant. Each human player controls a single player, so choose your squad wisely to take team-mate skill into account. The game is action-oriented, and players can perform unrealistic slam-dunks. Full performance statistics are automatically recorded. The play clock and 3-point line apply, but other rules are largely overlooked.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/NBA Jam (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19940101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Midway</developer>
    <publisher>Acclaim Entertainment, Inc.</publisher>
    <genre>Sports</genre>
    <players>4</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./NFL Football Trivia Challenge (U).cue</path>
    <name>NFL Football Trivia Challenge</name>
    <desc>NFL Football Trivia Challenge is a trivia game with an National Football League license. Either player can pick his favourite team to play with. TV commentators Pat Summerall and Tom Bookshier describe various situations in play accompanied by 1200 images and 300 Full Motion Video clips. 1500 multiple choice questions are waiting to be answered in the game. For each correct answer the player gains yardage in the game and increases his chances of scoring a point. The player with most points after 60 questions wins the game. There are three different difficulty levels to play at.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/NFL Football Trivia Challenge (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19930101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Capitol Disc Interactive</developer>
    <publisher>Capitol Disc Interactive Corporation</publisher>
    <genre>Puzzle</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./NFL's Greatest - San Francisco vs. Dallas 1978-1993 (U).cue</path>
    <name>NFL's Greatest: San Francisco vs. Dallas 1978-1993</name>
    <desc>Top stars for the Cowboys and 49ers from the 70's, 80's, and 90's in one game. Staubach, Dorsett, "Too Tall" Jones, Aikman, Irvin, Smith - take the field against Montana, Lott, Clark, Rice, Watters, Young - just to name a few! You choose the quarterback, you call the plays - then watch the action unfold in full color TruVideo! Imagine Tony Dorsett and Troy Aikman in the same backfield, or Steve Young hitting Dwight Clark with a TD pass, or "Too Tall" Jones chasing down Young - it can happen! 15 years of real football footage from the NFL Films Library and the latest Sega CD sound and technology make your dream game come to life!</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/NFL's Greatest - San Francisco vs. Dallas 1978-1993 (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19930101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Park Place Productions</developer>
    <genre>Sports</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./NHL '94 (U).cue</path>
    <name>NHL '94</name>
    <desc>After establishing themselves in the virtual rinks, EA combined both NHL and NHLPA licenses in NHL '94, allowing them to feature all 26 real teams (including both expansion teams) and players of the new NHL season for the first time in the series.

Aside from the licenses, the gameplay for this edition sees for the first time the inclusion of the devastating one-timer shot, but to keep forwards (literally) in check, defenders also feature harder body checks, with new animations. For an additional challenge, players can also choose to control the goalkeeper manually. A popular feature in previous editions, fighting is completely removed from the game. Game modes include exhibition games (or "regular season" in-game), playoffs (best of one or best of seven) and an all new shoot-out mode. The main options remain basically the same couple since the establishment of the series - period length (5, 10 or 20 minutes), line changes (off, manual or the new automatic mode) and penalties. (off, on, on but no offsides).</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/NHL '94 (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19930801T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Electronic Arts</developer>
    <publisher>Electronic Arts</publisher>
    <genre>Sports</genre>
    <players>4</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Night Striker (J).cue</path>
    <name>Night Striker</name>
    <desc>Night Striker (&amp;#x30CA;&amp;#x30A4;&amp;#x30C8;&amp;#x30B9;&amp;#x30C8;&amp;#x30E9;&amp;#x30A4;&amp;#x30AB;&amp;#x30FC;) is an arcade game developed by Taito. It is a futuristic on-the-rails shooter which plays similarly to Sega's Space Harrier, though has you pilot a hover vehicle instead.

The game was brought to the Sega Mega-CD in 1993, where graphically it was downscaled for the weaker hardware. It was also brought to the Sega Saturn as Night Striker S (&amp;#x30CA;&amp;#x30A4;&amp;#x30C8;&amp;#x30B9;&amp;#x30C8;&amp;#x30E9;&amp;#x30A4;&amp;#x30AB;&amp;#x30FC;&amp;#xFF33;) in 1996 - essentially the same game, but with an extra "Saturn Mode" and a few small enhancements. No versions have ever left Japan.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Night Striker (J)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19930528T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Aisystem Tokyo, Taito Corporation</developer>
    <publisher>Taito Corporation</publisher>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Ninja Warriors, The (J).cue</path>
    <name>The Ninja Warriors</name>
    <desc>The Ninja Warriors (&amp;#x30CB;&amp;#x30F3;&amp;#x30B8;&amp;#x30E3;&amp;#x30A6;&amp;#x30A9;&amp;#x30FC;&amp;#x30EA;&amp;#x30A2;&amp;#x30FC;&amp;#x30BA;) is a beat-'em-up originally developed by Taito for the arcades. It was brought to the Sega Mega-CD in 1993 exclusively for Japan. To emulate the three-screen setup of the original arcade game (3 288x224 screens arranged in a horizontal line like with the Darius games), porters Aisystem Tokyo simply capped the screen resolution in software, resulting in the entire game running in a small window.

Playable characters are two androids called Kunoichi (female ninja, red color) and Ninja (male ninja, blue color). Both characters play identically.

As indicated by the boxart, one of the game's main selling points was the soundtrack composed by Taito's inhouse band Zuntata. The game includes both the arcade versions's soundtrack as well as remixed tracks. An exclusive Zuntata mode was also included, which is bascially a movie scene that explains the game's backstory. Members of Zuntata served as actors.

To this day, this is the most faithful port of The Ninja Warriors.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Ninja Warriors, The (J)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19930312T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Aisystem Tokyo, Taito Corporation</developer>
    <publisher>Taito Corporation</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Novastorm (U).cue</path>
    <name>Novastorm</name>
    <desc>A behind-the-view perspective of a shooter's dream: Blast enemies against a cinematic backdrop. Kill the computer-controlled fighters before they take over the world!

Unlike first-generation interactive movies with action, Novastorm has hooks into the environment; if you move into the path of a pre-rendered obstacle and it "hits" you, you take damage, etc.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Novastorm (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19940101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Psygnosis Limited</developer>
    <publisher>Psygnosis Limited</publisher>
    <genre>Action, Shooter</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Panic! (U).cue</path>
    <name>Panic!</name>
    <desc>A virus has infected the world's computer network, which effects all electronical devices on the earth. However, a special program called "Panic!" is designed to counter the effects of the virus and restore the network back to working order. You play Slap the Boy and his sidekick, Stick the Dog(they're not actions, it's their names) who set out to restore the network back to working order.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Panic! (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19940101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Office 1</developer>
    <publisher>Data East Corporation</publisher>
    <genre>Puzzle</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Pitfall - The Mayan Adventure (U).cue</path>
    <name>Pitfall: The Mayan Adventure</name>
    <desc>The legendary PITFALL! is back! Twelve years later, the classic returns with ground-breaking gameplay that'll rattle your nerves and leave you in a cold sweat... Join Harry Jr., son of Pitfall Harry, as he tracks an evil Mayan warrior spirit, to rescue his kidnapped father... Run, swing, skate and bungee through deep, dark rainforests, raging waterfalls and Mayan temple ruins that reek of lethal enemies and deadly traps... until you face the master of evil - Zakelua. Adventure so real, you'll feel the sweat!</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Pitfall - The Mayan Adventure (U)-image.png</image>
    <releasedate>19950215T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Activision</developer>
    <publisher>Activision</publisher>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Popful Mail (U).cue</path>
    <name>Popful Mail</name>
    <desc>Kazyr, Necros, Ulgar. Ghosts from the past that nearly once destroyed Popful Mail's world. Now, the Black Seal is about to be broken so they can return to wreak havoc on the world once again. Three ragtag adventurers become the only hope of stopping the second coming of Evil. Play as Mail, tomboy bounty-hunter wannabe who's handy with a blade, Tatt, the ultra-polite apprentice magician with a deadly staff, or Gaw, a winged blue blob with breath of fire, as you search for the manicial Muttonhead, who holds all the answers. During your quest, change characters at any time! You'll need to, because Nuts Cracker and the minions of Evil will stop at nothing to end your party before it starts! And, thanks to the storage power of CD, Popful Mail comes alive with over 2.5 hours of spoken dialogue and 20 minutes of heart-pounding animation. Face it, your butt's gonna be glued to the couch till the credits roll!</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Popful Mail (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19950223T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Falcom</developer>
    <publisher>Working Designs</publisher>
    <genre>Adventure, Role-Playing</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Power Factory Featuring C&amp;C Music Factory - Make My Video (U).cue</path>
    <name>Power Factory Featuring C+C Music Factory</name>
    <desc>The first of Digital Pictures' "Make My Video" line has you "editing" three of C + C Music Factory's most famous songs - "Gonna Make You Sweat," "Things That Make You Go Hmm..." and "Here We Go Let's Rock &amp; Roll."

The plot puts you inside the music factory of the game's name, where two linemen sweat and toil under the oppressive thumb of a wheelchair-bound corporate executive. Video discs literally roll down an assembly line while C + C record their sounds behind three closed doors. You are asked to help out in editing these videos, appease the corporate masters, and lift the burden from everyone.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Power Factory Featuring C&amp;C Music Factory - Make My Video (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19920101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Digital Pictures</developer>
    <publisher>Sony</publisher>
    <genre>Music</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Power Monger (U).cue</path>
    <name>Power Monger</name>
    <desc>Powermonger takes the basic design and concepts of Bullfrog's previous game Populous, and places it in a war context. The game cast the player as a dispossessed warlord plundering his way through 195 territories on the way to world conquest. Several other leaders have the same goal.

The gameworld is now made up of polygons, so the view can be rotated and moved with greater freedom than Populous. Trade, diplomacy, inventions, and scorched earth invasions all play a key role in how the player progressed through the game. Two-player games via modem links are available on computer versions.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Power Monger (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19940101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Bullfrog Productions</developer>
    <publisher>Electronic Arts</publisher>
    <genre>Strategy</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Prince of Persia (U).cue</path>
    <name>Prince of Persia</name>
    <desc>The Grand Vizier Jaffar has thrown you into a dark dungeon and plans to marry the girl of your dreams in an hour. You're not going to let that happen are you? Try to escape from the dungeon, take out Jaffar's guards, find your way through the Sultan's palace and defeat Jaffar himself. Now go, you've got 60 minutes!

Prince of Persia is a 2D platformer with run and jump gameplay. Your hero must avoid deadly traps, solve some simple puzzles and engage in sword fights with the guards. The player has an infinite amount of lives, but has to restart at the beginning of a level each time he dies, and must complete the game within an hour. An especially noteworthy aspect of the game is the very fluent animation of your character.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Prince of Persia (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19920428T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Atari Games</developer>
    <genre>Platform</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Pro Yakyuu Super League CD (J).cue</path>
    <name>Pro Yakyuu Super League CD</name>
    <desc>Pro Yakyuu Super League CD (&amp;#x30D7;&amp;#x30ED;&amp;#x91CE;&amp;#x7403;&amp;#x30B9;&amp;#x30FC;&amp;#x30D1;&amp;#x30FC;&amp;#x30EA;&amp;#x30FC;&amp;#x30B0;&amp;#xFF23;&amp;#xFF24;) is a baseball game released as part of the Super League series for the Sega Mega-CD exclusively in Japan.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Pro Yakyuu Super League CD (J)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19921030T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Sega</developer>
    <publisher>Sega</publisher>
    <genre>Sports</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Puggsy (U).cue</path>
    <name>Puggsy</name>
    <desc>Puggsy is a platform game with a combination of action and puzzle-solving elements. You control the the creature Puggsy, who has crash landed on an alien planet and had his spaceship stolen. Your goal is find the spaceship so you can get off the planet and return home. To do this, you will need to make your way from the start to the exit of numerous levels which take place in a variety of environments. Throughout each level are a variety of objects which you can pick up; on many of the levels you will need to figure out how to use the objects available to you in order to reach the exit. Some objects can be used (like a gun or keys), and objects may be thrown, moved around and stacked. Of course, each level will also have a variety of bad guys wandering about which will cost Puggsy one of his lives if he's caught. On your quest there will also be six evil guardians which will need to be defeated before you get your spaceship back!</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Puggsy (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19930101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Traveller's Tales Ltd.</developer>
    <publisher>Psygnosis Limited</publisher>
    <genre>Action, Puzzle, Platform</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Racing Aces (U).cue</path>
    <name>Racing Aces</name>
    <desc>Racing Aces puts you behind the stick of World War 1, World War 2, and modern day fighting aircraft. Each competition is a dogfight as much as a race, and you will have to gun down your enemies to win. The tracks are littered with power up balloons to give you extra weapons and speed.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Racing Aces (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19930101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Hammond &amp; Leyland</developer>
    <publisher>Sega</publisher>
    <genre>Racing</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Radical Rex (U).cue</path>
    <name>Radical Rex</name>
    <desc>Radical Rex is a fire-breathing Tyrannosaurus on a skateboard who has to save the dinosaur race under the spell of an evil creature. The game consists of 10 levels set in the prehistoric age. Radical Rex can use a skateboard or glide down hills, jump, kick and breath fire. Tougher enemies need multiple hits and when burnt Rex needs to kick them once more to destroy them or use his scream (hits everything on the screen). While playing Rex collects eggs, health, power-ups for his fire breath and scream refills. Checkpoints are shown as torches that need to be charged with fire. After each level, there is a Bomberman-like sequence to earn an extra continue. Enemies include flies, turtles, toads and all kinds of dinosaurs.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Radical Rex (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19940101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Beam Software</developer>
    <publisher>Activision</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./RDF - Global Conflict (U).cue</path>
    <name>RDF Global Conflict</name>
    <desc>RDF (Rapid Deployment Force) is a first-person 3D tank shooter with the player going up against a plethora of enemies including other tanks, missile launchers, helicopters among many others. The player can use either their 120mm cannon or their laser-guided missiles in a variety of locations that including the Eastern European countryside to the Alaskan Tundra. The story is told through FMV clips</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/RDF - Global Conflict (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19940101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Imagineering Inc.</developer>
    <publisher>Absolute Entertainment</publisher>
    <genre>Action, Shooter</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Revenge of the Ninja (U).cue</path>
    <name>Revenge of the Ninja</name>
    <desc>The story takes place in Japan, you play as Hayate, a young up and coming ninja warrior out to stop the evil of Lougi and his army of ghouls and goblins. You are out to avenge your father's death as well as the emperor and rescue your girlfriend from the clutches of evil and bring an end to the terror visited upon your lands.

Some of the villians you face are Marco Killmore (a half man, half eagle samurai warrior), Zallen (a disgraced samurai warrior out to destroy Hayate), Vengor (a stone shiva-type character), Desfal (a medusa-like woman), Destroyer MPK (a possessed collection of samurai armor) and of course the evil samurai knight himself, Lougi.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Revenge of the Ninja (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19930101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Taito Corporation</developer>
    <publisher>Renovation Products, Inc.</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Revengers of Vengeance (U).cue</path>
    <name>Revengers of Vengeance</name>
    <desc>Revengers of Vengeance is a combination of RPG, vertical shooter, and fighting game with a fantasy/anime style. There are ten available characters, each with their own animated backstory and fighting techniques. You must choose a hero and guide their stats to create a formidable fighter capable of taking down the Devil King and freeing the land.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Revengers of Vengeance (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19940101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Micronet Co. Ltd.</developer>
    <publisher>Extreme Entertainment Group</publisher>
    <genre>Action, Role-Playing</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Rise of the Dragon (U).cue</path>
    <name>Rise of the Dragon</name>
    <desc>Rise of the Dragon is a futuristic first-person adventure game. The game's visuals are reminiscent of a comic book, with digitized photos of actors and hand-painted backgrounds. Unlike most other adventure games of the time, it relies less on inventory puzzles and more on specific choices made by the player. The game has an internal clock and requires the player to plan the protagonist's moves ahead in order to be in the right place at the right time. Dialogues with multiple choices are utilized as a gameplay tool; a wrong choice will often lead to a premature end of the adventure.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Rise of the Dragon (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19930101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Dynamix, Inc.</developer>
    <publisher>Sega</publisher>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Road Avenger (U).cue</path>
    <name>Road Avenger</name>
    <desc>Action that reaches out and grabs you! Wipe S.C.U.M. (Secret Criminal Underground Movement) off the highway. Smash through a hotel lobby, spin off a bridge at high speed, and tear up the beach on the tail of perpetrators. Shift into high gear for the ultimate hot pursuit. So much fun it should be illegal!</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Road Avenger (U)-image.png</image>
    <releasedate>19930305T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Data East Corporation</developer>
    <publisher>Wolf Team</publisher>
    <genre>Action, Racing</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Road Rash (U).cue</path>
    <name>Road Rash</name>
    <desc>Road Rash for Sega CD is another title in the series, this time it's an attempt to mate the classic gameplay of Genesis Road Rash games with full-motion video and avant-garde rock soundtrack.

This game was released the same time with the famous 3DO Road Rash. And it borrowed a lot of content from the Panasonic 3DO version: all the FMV videos, CD-quality soundtrack and overall menu design. The quality of FMV and music is inferior to 3DO version given the limitations of Sega CD hardware. Graphically and gameplay-wise the game is a continuation of Road Rash II for Sega Genesis.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Road Rash (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19930101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>New Level Software</developer>
    <publisher>Electronic Arts</publisher>
    <genre>Racing, Fighting</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Robo Aleste (U).cue</path>
    <name>Robo Aleste</name>
    <desc>Pilot your massive mecha Aleste in the name of the Oda clan and seek revenge against the evil Chugoku Army for their atrocities!  Robo Aleste is another title in the Aleste series by famed shoot-'em-up developer Compile where players must collect power-ups to defeat countless waves of enemies and large bosses.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Robo Aleste (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19921127T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Compile</developer>
    <publisher>Tengen</publisher>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Samurai Showdown (U).cue</path>
    <name>Samurai Shodown</name>
    <desc>In early Japan, a man named Shiro Tokisada Amakusa preaches a heretic religion. Little does anyone know that Amakusa is really a servant of the evil Ambrosia, who took over Amakusa's body. Ambrosia wishes to shroud the world in darkness. Now, choose between 12 warriors (and 3 bonus characters) to fight for the honor of destroying Amakusa, and fulfilling a mission.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Samurai Showdown (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19930101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>SNK</developer>
    <publisher>JVC Musical Industries, Inc.</publisher>
    <genre>Action, Fighting</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Secret of Monkey Island, The (U).cue</path>
    <name>The Secret of Monkey Island</name>
    <desc>The Secret of Monkey Island is an adventure game that utilizes the command verb-based SCUMM interface first introduced in Maniac Mansion: the player constructs commands for Guybrush by selecting an appropriate verb and then combining it with an object or an inventory item. Objects that can be interacted with are highlighted when the player places a cursor over them. The game is the first LucasArts adventure in which it is impossible to get irrevocably stuck; like in Loom, the player character also cannot die. The branching dialogue system, where the player chooses between several available responses during conversations, allows the player to talk to characters in different ways without fearing a wrong choice, and is often used as a humorous device.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Secret of Monkey Island, The (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19920101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>LucasArts Entertainment Company LLC</developer>
    <publisher>JVC Musical Industries, Inc.</publisher>
    <genre>Adventure, Puzzle</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Sega Classics Arcade Collection 5-in-1 (U).cue</path>
    <name>Sega Classics Arcade Collection 5-in-1</name>
    <desc>Sega Classics Arcade Collection is a compilation of four (or five) Sega Mega Drive games for the Sega Mega-CD. It was a pack-in game bundled with launch Mega CDs in the United Kingdom and North America, and was released separately in other regions.

 Two variants of Sega Classics Arcade Collection exist; an earlier version seen in North America and Japan, which contains Golden Axe, Streets of Rage, Columns and The Revenge of Shinobi, and a later version seen in Europe and later North American bundles, which throws in Super Monaco GP. In North America the older "4-in-1" variant came in the same box as Sherlock Holmes: Consulting Detective Vol. I, while the later "5-in-1" one came with Ecco the Dolphin.

 Each game is mostly identical to their Mega Drive counterparts, though have minor changes thanks to the Mega CD's enhancements. All digitised speech samples have been replaced with higher quality audio, the first level in Golden Axe uses different instruments and Super Monaco GP has extra drums. The Revenge of Shinobi is based on a later version than its cartridge counterparts, altering some of the bosses which infringe copyrights. For unknown reasons, Golden Axe is only a one-player game in this compilation.

 Despite being the Mega CD's selling point, only two games have an updated CD soundtrack (Golden Axe in the form of music recorded from its arcade board, and Columns which has a new title theme). This means only a small fraction of the disc is used. 

Games:
Columns
Golden Axe
Revenge of Shinobi
Streets of Rage
Super Monaco GP</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Sega Classics Arcade Collection 5-in-1 (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19940101T000000</releasedate>
    <publisher>Sega</publisher>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Sengoku Denshou (J).cue</path>
    <name>Sengoku Denshou</name>
    <desc>Sengoku Denshou (&amp;#x6226;&amp;#x56FD;&amp;#x4F1D;&amp;#x627F;) is a beat-'em-up released for the Sega Mega-CD exclusively in Japan.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Sengoku Denshou (J)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19931228T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>SNK</developer>
    <publisher>Sammy Corporation</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Sewer Shark (U).cue</path>
    <name>Sewer Shark</name>
    <desc>Sewer Shark takes place sometime in the future, where environmental destruction has forced most of humanity to live underground. The player takes the role of a rookie pilot in a band of "sewer jockies", whose job is to exterminate dangerous mutated creatures to keep a vast network of sewers clean for the resort area "Solar City", an island paradise ruled by the evil Commissioner Stenchler (Robert Costanzo). The player's co-pilot, Ghost (David Underwood), evaluates the player's performance throughout the game, while a small robot named Catfish scouts ahead and gives directions. The player is later assisted by Falco, a female jockey who believes that there is a hidden route to the surface. Falco is later captured by Stenchler, who threatens to turn her into one of his mindless minions. This plot is thwarted when Ghost and the player reach Solar City.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Sewer Shark (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19921015T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Digital Pictures</developer>
    <publisher>Sony Imagesoft</publisher>
    <genre>Shooter, Vehicle Simulation</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Shadow of the Beast II (U).cue</path>
    <name>Shadow of the Beast II</name>
    <desc>Combining non-stop battle action with perplexing puzzle solving, Shadow of the Beast II thrusts you into a dark and mysterious world where wits and combat-hardened game playing skills are your only defense. Take the action to the limit as you fight a relentless onslaught of monsters and ogres. Bashing them into submission, you make your way through a labyrinth of adventure and enter final confrontation with the Beast Mage!</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Shadow of the Beast II (U)-image.png</image>
    <releasedate>19940607T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Reflections Interactive</developer>
    <publisher>Psygnosis Limited</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Sherlock Holmes - Consulting Detective (U).cue</path>
    <name>Sherlock Holmes: Consulting Detective</name>
    <desc>Sherlock Holmes: Consulting Detective can be described as a hybrid of adventure game and simulation. Gameplay process involves traveling to various locations in London, interrogating suspects, gathering clues, checking out the newspapers, and eventually presenting all the evidence to the judge; if the latter finds the circumstances incriminating, he will accept the results of the investigation, and the case will be considered solved. Though the basic gameplay is rather typical for adventure games, the amount of real detective work and the focus of the game on purely case-related actions rather than exploration and manipulation of items makes it comparable to a simulation of a criminal investigation.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Sherlock Holmes - Consulting Detective (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19920101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>ICOM Simulations, Inc.</developer>
    <publisher>Sega</publisher>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Shining Force CD (U).cue</path>
    <name>Shining Force CD</name>
    <desc>This strategy RPG is a remastered compilation of two earlier Shining force titles: Shining Force Gaiden (originally released in Japan only) and Shining Force: The Sword of Hajya, both for the Game Gear.  The two stories put players in the role of Nick, a hero of royal blood who must rescue Queen Anri of Gardiana and reclaim the kingdom of Cypress from the evil empire of Iom's clutches.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Shining Force CD (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19940721T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Sonic! Software Planning</developer>
    <publisher>Sega</publisher>
    <genre>Role-Playing, Strategy</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Silpheed (U).cue</path>
    <name>Silpheed</name>
    <desc>Fight back against Xacalite's terrorist forces and reclaim Earth's mother computer in your SA-77 Silpheed starfighter!  A remake of the 1986 Japanese PC game, Silpheed is a shoot-'em-up that combines polygonal graphics with creative use of the Sega CD's FMV capabilities to provide excellent visuals and gameplay.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Silpheed (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19930707T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Game Arts</developer>
    <publisher>Game Arts Co., Ltd.</publisher>
    <genre>Action, Shooter</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Smurfs, The (E).cue</path>
    <name>The Smurfs</name>
    <desc>Gargamel has just perfected a terrible plot to kidnap ALL the Smurfs. Four of them have disappeared already. You will have to brave the Angry Smurfs and Buzz flies before smurfing the mountain riding on a sledge, travel on the back of a stork and finally challenge the infamous Gargamel!</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Smurfs, The (E)-image.png</image>
    <releasedate>19950505T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Infogrames</developer>
    <publisher>Infogrames Entertainment</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Snatcher (U).cue</path>
    <name>Snatcher</name>
    <desc>A.D. 2047. Neo Kobe City, Japan, a place of madness and decadence... A mysterious Bio-roid life form has appeared. Its true nature and purpose are unknown. Is it some country's secret weapon, or an alien from another world? They slay their victims and take their place, earning them the nickname "SNATCHERS." A new police division - J.U.N.K.E.R.s - has been formed. They are trained specifically to combat the SNATCHERS. The fate of mankind hangs in the balance. The war between the SNATCHERS and J.U.N.K.E.R.s has begun!</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Snatcher (U)-image.png</image>
    <releasedate>19941130T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Konami</developer>
    <publisher>Konami</publisher>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Sol-Feace (U).cue</path>
    <name>Sol-Feace</name>
    <desc>Sol-Feace is a typical 2D shooter with weapon powerups. The game features six levels: Sirius, Enemy Arsenal, ArtifiStar, Pluto Base, Almathea, and Final Battle.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Sol-Feace (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19911212T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Wolf Team</developer>
    <publisher>Wolf Team</publisher>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Sonic CD (U).cue</path>
    <name>Sonic CD</name>
    <desc>Sonic's gameplay remains similar to that of Sonic the Hedgehog but with the addition of the Spin Dash and the Super Peel Out, which lets him zoom into a quick speed from a standing point.The main innovation of this chapter in the Sonic series is the manner in which the player can travel to four different versions of each zone, each a different time period of the same location: Present, Past, Good Future and Bad Future. This is accomplished by speed posts scattered around the level, bearing the labels "Past", and "Future". After running through one of these posts, the player has to run at top speed for a few seconds without stopping, to travel into the respective time period. Because these teleports are relative, there are no "Past" signs in the Past, and no "Future" signs in the Future; that is, warping to the past in the future returns the player to the "present" time and vice versa.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Sonic CD (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19930923T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Sega</developer>
    <publisher>Sega</publisher>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Soulstar (U).cue</path>
    <name>SoulStar</name>
    <desc>Soulstar for the Sega CD/Mega CD is a 3D shoot-'em up that combines several different types of gameplay into one game. Some levels in this game are on a fixed path, similar to Space Harrier or Star Fox. Other levels allow your space craft to hover freely around a 3D environment, and in other levels your craft transforms into a walker robot for close-up attacks.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Soulstar (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19941221T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Core Design Ltd.</developer>
    <publisher>Core Design Ltd.</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Space Ace (U).cue</path>
    <name>Space Ace</name>
    <desc>You're playing Dexter, a guy fighting the evil madman Borf who has kidnapped your girlfriend Kimberly and is now threatening the world with his dreaded weapon, the "Infanto Ray" which turns adults into small children.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Space Ace (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19940101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>ReadySoft Incorporated</developer>
    <publisher>ReadySoft Incorporated</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Space Adventure, The (U).cue</path>
    <name>The Space Adventure</name>
    <desc>While waiting in a bar for his partner, Cobra encounters a beautiful bounty hunter named Jane. Very soon he realizes that the bounty Jane has been hunting for is his own head, for which the Galaxy Patrol has put quite a reward. But everything changes when Crystal Boy, the head of the Pirate Guild and Cobra's archenemy, appears on the scene. Jane's father had apparently hidden a great treasure, encoding its location in tattoos on the backs of his triplet daughters. Crystal Boy wants this treasure, and is going after Jane and her sisters. Cobra and Jane decide to join forces in order to find Jane's sisters and to undermine Crystal Boy's plans.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Space Adventure, The (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19940101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Hudson Entertainment, Inc.</developer>
    <publisher>Hudson Entertainment, Inc.</publisher>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Star Strike (U).cue</path>
    <name>Star Strike</name>
    <desc>Star Strike is an Action game, developed and published by Good Deal Games, which was released in 2000.

Launching from repair bay 28 of the Galatea, you guide your Blue Fighter Wing through the Launch Ring at lightspeed, entering enemy territory, sector Delta Five Niner! Your mission: Rescue the Orange Wing Center which was captured alive, before the enemy ingests his brain -- A brain which they consider to not only be an excellent source of protein, but also, once consumed, transfers all knowledge to the species - Including military secrets, vital to the survival of all mankind! 
Can you rescue your comrad &amp; Destroy the opposing Protoid Forces?</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Star Strike (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>20000101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Good Deal Games</developer>
    <publisher>Good Deal Games</publisher>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Star Wars - Rebel Assault (U).cue</path>
    <name>Star Wars: Rebel Assault</name>
    <desc>The game follows the adventures of a young pilot known as Rookie One, a farmer from Tatooine in the style of Luke Skywalker. The game largely takes place during the events of Episode IV: A New Hope, however the sequences on Hoth from The Empire Strikes Back are included.
The game begins with Rookie One's training (you), followed by an attack on the Star Destroyer Devastator, after its capture of the Tantive IV in the events of the film. The story then leads the player to sequences to defend the Rebel Base on Hoth from the attack shown in the Empire Strikes Back, and finally ends in the assault on the Death Star of the film, with the player taking the place of Luke Skywalker in destroying the battle station.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Star Wars - Rebel Assault (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19930101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>LucasArts Entertainment Company LLC</developer>
    <publisher>LucasArts Entertainment Company LLC</publisher>
    <genre>Action, Shooter</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Star Wars Chess (U).cue</path>
    <name>Star Wars Chess</name>
    <desc>Star Wars Chess is a chess game where the pieces are characters from the Star Wars universe. When pieces are taken, an animated battle is shown, much like in Battle Chess.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Star Wars Chess (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19930101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>The Software Toolworks</developer>
    <publisher>Mindscape, Inc.</publisher>
    <genre>Strategy</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Starblade (U).cue</path>
    <name>StarBlade</name>
    <desc>Sitting in the gunner position of a "GeoSword" fightercraft, you must shoot your way through the enemy armada and bring the fight to their base planet, Redeye. Altogether you'll have around 10 missions to get through before the galaxy is safe and your wingmen will help you along the way. And during those missions, you'll be expected to shoot out the sides of huge enemy battlecruisers, travel inside of enemy carriers and travel through the canyons of Redeye to deliver your payload.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Starblade (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19940101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Namco</developer>
    <publisher>Namco</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Stellar-Fire (U).cue</path>
    <name>Stellar-Fire</name>
    <desc>The dreaded Draxon race has been at it again, pushing the human race around, working to either enslave all 10 billion humans or wipe them out completely. As the last surviving pilot sent on a mission to thwart the Draxons' plans, all hope rests on you. Invade each of the fortified moons orbiting the Draxons' homeworld of Arctaurus and then aim for the mother planet itself.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Stellar-Fire (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19930101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Infinite Laser Dog</developer>
    <publisher>Dynamix, Inc.</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Super Strike Trilogy (U).cue</path>
    <name>Super Strike Trilogy</name>
    <desc>Super Strike Trilogy is an unreleased game compilation for the Sega Mega-CD. Super Strike Trilogy was shown at E3 1995 and was intended to incorporate upgraded versions of Electronic Arts' initial three Strike games, Desert Strike, Jungle Strike and Urban Strike.So now for the first time you can play the game that never was.Please remember that this game was never officially finished and will contain bugs.Many thanks to HeadCrab for making this happen.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Super Strike Trilogy (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>20170713T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>EA</developer>
    <publisher>EA Games</publisher>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Surgical Strike (U).cue</path>
    <name>Surgical Strike</name>
    <desc>The elite Special Forces unit, The Surgical Strike Team, have been called into action. High-tech urban guerrillas are attacking innocent people but once they're done with their carnage they fade back into the landscape. In a very delicate way, the Team must find these hidden enemies and get rid of them without harming innocent citizens. Inside your hovercraft, you can charge at the violent creatures, turn 180 degrees to watch your own back and explore new uncharted areas. You have a choice of weaponry choose the 30MM Gatling gun or the laser-guided rockets. AWACs C-130's hover above and give you pointers, plus on-board mapping allows you to zero in on hidden emplacements.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Surgical Strike (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19931116T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>The Code Monkeys Ltd.</developer>
    <publisher>Sega</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Syndicate (E).cue</path>
    <name>Syndicate</name>
    <desc>Syndicate is an isometric strategy game developed by Bullfrog Productions. It was released among other systems for the Sega Mega Drive and Sega Mega-CD. Its sequel, Syndicate Wars, was due to be released on the Sega Saturn but was cancelled.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Syndicate (E)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19950112T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Bullfrog Productions</developer>
    <publisher>Electronic Arts, Domark Software</publisher>
    <genre>Role-Playing, Life Simulation</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Terminator, The (U).cue</path>
    <name>The Terminator</name>
    <desc>Just like the movie, you assume the role of Kyle Reese, a traveller from the future who returns to modern-day L.A. to protect the life of Sarah Conner - the beautiful woman who holds the key to the survival of the human race. Your mission: Outwit and outmaneuver a brutal killing machine known as the Terminator. He's big, he's bad and he's virtually unstoppable - let's hope you're smarter! Featuring 10 huge main levels pumped up with hardcore weaponry and heavy-hitting adversaries.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Terminator, The (U)-image.png</image>
    <releasedate>19930308T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Virgin Interactive Entertainment</developer>
    <publisher>Virgin Games, Ltd.</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Theme Park (E).cue</path>
    <name>Theme Park</name>
    <desc>Theme Park (&amp;#x30C6;&amp;#x30FC;&amp;#x30DE;&amp;#x30D1;&amp;#x30FC;&amp;#x30AF;) is a management simulator developed by Bullfrog Productions and published by Electronic Arts in 1994. It was released for a variety of systems, including the Sega Mega Drive, Sega Mega-CD, Sega Saturn in the following year.

Theme Park was the first successful theme park simulator, and would go on to inspire other Theme games and the RollerCoaster Tycoon series. Players are given a plot of land and are tasked with buying (and creating) rides, as well as organising the general layout of the park, staff and attempting to keep visitors happy without going bankrupt.

From a Sega perspective the game is fairly interesting - the game was technically released twice in Japan, first as regular Theme Park seen here, and again as Shin Theme Park, a localised variant. The game was originally designed with a mouse in mind, but none of the Sega ports are compatible with their respective mouse add ons, whether that be the Sega Mouse or Shuttle Mouse.

Theme Park would later see a true sequel in the form of the fully 3D Theme Park World (known as Sim Theme Park in North America) in 1999.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Theme Park (E)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19950502T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Bullfrog Productions</developer>
    <publisher>Electronic Arts, Domark Software</publisher>
    <genre>Strategy, Life Simulation</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Third World War (U).cue</path>
    <name>Third World War</name>
    <desc>Third World War is a "hypothetical/what if" wargame with a twist. Set sometime in the late 20th century, when conflicts all over the world have erupted, and world peace is but a thing of the past.

As the leader of one of 16 nations, your ultimate goal is none other than world domination. To accomplish this you have a multitude of options ranging from raw military might, diplomacy, foreign or domestic investment policy, aiding terrorists or revolutionaries, to media manipulation. In other words, it's just like the real world.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Third World War (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19940101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Micronet Co. Ltd.</developer>
    <publisher>Micronet Co. Ltd.</publisher>
    <genre>Strategy</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Time Cop (E) (Unreleased).cue</path>
    <name>Time Cop</name>
    <desc>Timecop is a side-scrolling action video game produced by Cryo Interactive for the Super Nintendo Entertainment System in 1995.[1] It is based on the 1994 film of the same title and takes place after the events of the film. Despite the use of digitized actors to portray the characters in the game, an actor other than Jean-Claude Van Damme was used to pose as protagonist Max Walker. Levels range from locales in the past (e.g., New York City during the 1920s, the European front of World War II), the present day, and a dystopian Los Angeles of the distant future.

Although the game was only released for the Super NES, a version was also developed for the Sega CD, with a short demo being distributed in May 1995 alongside the European Sega Pro magazine.[5] Despite being fully completed by the developer, JVC pulled off the Sega CD version publishing and it remained unreleased. In 2007, a complete version of the game was eventually released on the Internet by the Sega CD version coder.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Time Cop (E) (Unreleased)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19950802T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>JVC</developer>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Time Gal (U).cue</path>
    <name>Time Gal</name>
    <desc>The year is 4001. The evil Luna has stolen a time machine and plans to use it to take over the world. You are the Time Gal, a skillful and pretty scientist, and your mission is to chase Luna through different time periods, to get the time machine back, and to save the world.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Time Gal (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19930101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Taito Corporation</developer>
    <publisher>Renovation Products, Inc.</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Tomcat Alley (U).cue</path>
    <name>Tomcat Alley</name>
    <desc>Tomcat Alley is one of the last of Sega's TruVideo games for the SegaCD, featuring you and your F-14 Tomcat doing what you do best - dogfighting Russian Migs!

This time, a renegade Soviet commander is threatening the United States with chemical weapons from his base in the Mexican desert, and its up to you and your wingmen to fine-tune your air-to-air combat strategies to make the entire western hemisphere safe again!

Tomcat Alley was one of Sega's last TruVideo games, featuring what is called "Active Matrix" software, which allows for many different outcomes to any given situation. This means only one thing - much more interaction and variation than previous FMV (Full Motion Video) games!</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Tomcat Alley (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19940101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>The Code Monkeys Ltd.</developer>
    <publisher>Sega</publisher>
    <genre>Action, Flight Simulator</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Trivial Pursuit (U).cue</path>
    <name>Trivial Pursuit</name>
    <desc>This is the first multimedia version of the classic Parker Brothers board game. It uses photos, animations, videos &amp; voice clips to pose over 2000 questions and answers to Trivial Pursuit questions.

In the Classic Game, up to 6 players roll an on-screen die and move their 'pie-dish' marker around the spoke-and-wheel game board, just like the board game. The square you land on is color coded to one of six trivia categories: People &amp; Places, Sports &amp; Leisure, History, Arts &amp; Entertainment, Science &amp; Nature, and Wild Card. Answering the trivia question correctly lets you take another turn.

Further, if you are on the 'prize' square at the end of each spoke (1 spoke end for each category color), the correct answer grants you a colored pie piece in your pie-dish marker for that category. Once you have all 6 pie pieces in your dish, you need to head back to the hub for a final random question to win the game.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Trivial Pursuit (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19930101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Western Technologies Inc.</developer>
    <publisher>Parker Brothers</publisher>
    <genre>Puzzle</genre>
    <players>4</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Ultraverse Prime (U).cue</path>
    <name>Ultraverse Prime</name>
    <desc>Players control the superhero Prime, a thirteen year-old boy called Kevin Green that has the power to transform into a superhero adult version of himself. Prime can punch, kick and jump, and combine these into some new moves and combos. The player as well as the enemies can also occasionally find weapons or objects to pick up and throw. Some stages are much faster as Prime flies at a fast speed and needs to punch obstacles and enemies out of the air.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Ultraverse Prime (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19940101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Psygnosis Limited</developer>
    <publisher>Sony</publisher>
    <genre>Action, Adventure</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Vay (U).cue</path>
    <name>Vay</name>
    <desc>It came from space more than a millenium before. Two-tons of advanced technology, programmed only for destruction. The five mightiest wizards of the land joined forces and drew away the power of the battle machine, dividing the power into 5 orbs and sealing the armor away from humanity. Now, the Danek Empire has partially duplicated the fearsome mechanized technology, creating a deadly army of metal warriors programmed for world domination. The only hope for salvation is to find the legendary orbs and restore power to the armor that nearly destroyed the planet more than 1000 years before. Join Sandor as he begins a quest that will take him from the depths of Magmal Isle to the terrifying heights of Draktyr. 

Fight over 100 types of monsters, explore towns, and enjoy exciting CD animation scenes as you pursue the orbs that will activate the legendary armor of Vay. But, will the armor save your world, or destroy it forever?</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Vay (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19940414T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>SIMS Co., Ltd.</developer>
    <publisher>Working Designs</publisher>
    <genre>Role-Playing</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Wheel of Fortune (U).cue</path>
    <name>Wheel of Fortune</name>
    <desc>One of the many Wheel of Fortunes versions released, the SEGA CD version has 6,000 different puzzles with full motion video of Vanna White herself, however Pat Sajak does make an appearance in the game. The gameplay was as same as other games, using a power meter to spin the wheel, pick letters to fill in puzzles and solve them in order to make it to the bonus round for a chance to win either big money.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Wheel of Fortune (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19940101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Sony Imagesoft</developer>
    <publisher>Sony Imagesoft</publisher>
    <genre>Puzzle</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Who Shot Johnny Rock (U).cue</path>
    <name>Who Shot Johnny Rock?</name>
    <desc>Another live-actor arcade shooter by American Laser Games (makers of Mad Dog McCree and Crime Patrol), Who Shot Johnny Rock is set in the classic 1920's style gangster era.

As the title suggests, you're supposed to find out who shot singer Johnny Rock (or at least who hired the guys who shot him) and put them behind bars.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Who Shot Johnny Rock (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19940101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>American Laser Games, Inc.</developer>
    <publisher>American Laser Games, Inc.</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Wild Woody (U).cue</path>
    <name>Wild Woody</name>
    <desc>An adventurer named Dusty returns home with an enchanted Totem Pole. Due to an assortment of rare events, the spirits of the Totem have been freed and they have created a bizarre parallel universe that can devour the world. Lowman, the "head" of the Totem, needs some "muscle" as he calls it, to bring them back. He finds a pencil on the desk and makes it come to life. The pencil tells Lowman to call him Woody, WILLLLLLLLD Woody. Lowman explains what has happened with his Totem brothers and now Woody goes into the parallel universe, dimension by dimension, and rounds up Lowman's Totem brothers.

In this game, you destroy your enemies by jumping on top of them and Woody can also wipe them out with his eraser. You can erase certain walls to get through them and you can also erase boxes that most of the time teleport if you press down. Other boxes contain items. You also can sketch things and they will come to life, but you can only do this twice because Woody shrinks very quickly from doing this. There are also power-ups that make you grow again.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Wild Woody (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19950101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Sega</developer>
    <publisher>Sega</publisher>
    <genre>Action, Puzzle</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Wing Commander (U).cue</path>
    <name>Wing Commander</name>
    <desc>Wing Commander is a space combat simulator interspersed with shipboard dialogs. Onboard the ship, you can save/load game, visit the bar to get the latest gossip, or go on to the next mission briefing, and the 3D space combat part.

The 3D space combat has you sitting in the cockpit, where you control the craft like roll, turn, up/down, afterburner, as well as fire guns and launch missiles. There are four different crafts on the Confed side, each with different flight characteristics and armament. You will have a wingman on each mission, and you should keep the wingman alive as the wingman will help you if you issue the right orders. You can also taunt the enemy. You'll be fighting several different types of enemy fighters and capital ships, and even combat a few Kilrathi aces.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Wing Commander (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19940101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Origin Systems</developer>
    <publisher>Origin Systems</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Wirehead (U).cue</path>
    <name>Wirehead</name>
    <desc>Wirehead has the player controlling Ned Hubbard, a man with a wireless controller implanted in his brain, via the joypad.

The bad guys are chasing after Ned for his "mind implant", and of course, the only way to get it is to open his head. Reminiscent of Dragon's Lair, a path opens up, and the player has to choose the right direction, otherwise Ned will be killed.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Wirehead (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19950101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>The Code Monkeys Ltd.</developer>
    <publisher>Sega</publisher>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Wolfchild (U).cue</path>
    <name>Wolfchild</name>
    <desc>The world's most renowned biogenetic scientist has been kidnapped and brainwashed into creating an army of bloodthirsty mutant warriors.

Suddenly the fate of all mankind rests in the hands of his youngest son... and a top-secret mutating experiment known as "Project Wolfchild."

-10 freaky levels filled with mind-blowing mazes, brain twisting puzzles and against all-odds combat action.

-CD-quality graphics and a rockin' stereo soundtrack

-Grusome cast of unrelenting schitzoid mutants, each with the power to destroy

-Fully animated introduction sequence</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Wolfchild (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19930101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Core Design Ltd.</developer>
    <publisher>JVC Musical Industries, Inc.</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Wonder Dog (U).cue</path>
    <name>Wonder Dog</name>
    <desc>Cartoon-quality animation brings to life Wonder Dog's narrow escape from the invading Pitbully Space Armada on his home planet of K-9. In Bunny Hop Meadow you'll take of mangy mutts, rascally rabbits and dizzy ducks as your long journey back to free K-9 begins.

Climb in the ring with boxers in Dogsville and wailing alley cats in the Scrapyard-or maybe you'll even find a hidden zone or two...or three.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Wonder Dog (U)-image.png</image>
    <releasedate>19920101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Core Design Ltd.</developer>
    <publisher>JVC Musical Industries, Inc.</publisher>
    <genre>Platform</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./WonderMega Collection (J).cue</path>
    <name>Wondermega Collection</name>
    <desc>Wondermega Collection (&amp;#x30EF;&amp;#x30F3;&amp;#x30C0;&amp;#x30FC;&amp;#x30E1;&amp;#x30AC;&amp;#x3000;&amp;#x30B3;&amp;#x30EC;&amp;#x30AF;&amp;#x30B7;&amp;#x30E7;&amp;#x30F3;) is a sample disc bundled with Japanese Wondermega consoles. It contains four CD+G karaoke songs and Battle Fighter, Flicky, Pyramid Magic and Quiz Scramble as playable games.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/WonderMega Collection (J)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19920104T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>JVC</developer>
    <publisher>Victor Interactive Software, Inc.</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./World Cup USA '94 (U).cue</path>
    <name>World Cup USA 94</name>
    <desc>World Cup USA 94 is a top-down football (soccer) game recreating the namesake tournament. Beside the 24 teams who qualified for the actual World Cup, other significant footballing nations like England, France and Denmark can be drafted in. Tackling is difficult and passing is easy, making for a flowing end-to-end style of play. The presentation of the menus is largely icon-based, with the official mascot featured prominently.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/World Cup USA '94 (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19930101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Tiertex Design Studios</developer>
    <publisher>U.S. Gold Ltd.</publisher>
    <genre>Sports</genre>
    <players>4</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./WWF Rage in the Cage (U).cue</path>
    <name>WWF Rage in the Cage</name>
    <desc>Brace yourself! A supercharged lineup of Superstars collide in the ultimate World Wrestling Federation slugfest! From punishing powerslams to cranium-crunching piledrivers... it doesn't get any better than this!

-20 SUPERSTARS -- EACH WITH HIS OWN TRADEMARK MOVE!
-SPECTACULAR STEREO SOUND -- OUTRAGEOUS ASSAULTS FROM EACH WRESTLER!
-BRUTAL STEEL CAGE MATCHUPS!
-BALLISTIC TOURNAMENT BATTLES, "NO-HOLDS-BARRED" BRAWLS, IN AND OUT OF THE RING ACTION... AND MORE!

Do you have what it takes to escape this ring of steel? It's time to unleash the Rage in the Cage!

-ONLY ONE WILL SURVIVE THE RAGE IN THE CAGE
-NEVER "WRITE OFF" MR. PERFECT
-LIVE ACTION VIDEO
-DEVASTATING AERIAL ATTACKS
-BEWARE THE BANZAI DROP</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/WWF Rage in the Cage (U)-image.png</image>
    <releasedate>19931221T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Sculptured Software</developer>
    <publisher>Arena Entertainment</publisher>
    <genre>Fighting, Sports</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Dracula Unleashed (U) [Disc 1 of 2].cue</path>
    <name>Dracula Unleashed (Disc 1/2)</name>
    <desc>In Dracula Unleashed it is the year 1899, ten years after the destruction of count Dracula chronicled in Bram Stoker's novel. You take the role of Alexander Morris, the younger brother of Texan Quincey Morris who died defeating Dracula. Alexander has come to London to investigate the circumstances of his brother's death, but became sidetracked when he fell in love with and proposed to a local girl named Annisette.

Now, the dawn of a new millennium approaches and an evil force is stalking the streets of London, draining victims of their blood and transforming innocent women into bloodthirsty vampiresses. With the aide of your brother's old friends, the survivors of Dracula's evil, you must uncover the identity of this new vampire and prevent him from transforming Annisette into his queen of the night. Do not fail her, or she will personally rip your throat out.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Dracula Unleashed (U) [Disc 1 of 2]-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <releasedate>19930101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>ICOM Simulations, Inc.</developer>
    <publisher>Sega</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Dracula Unleashed (U) [Disc 2 of 2].cue</path>
    <name>Dracula Unleashed (Disc 2/2)</name>
    <desc>In Dracula Unleashed it is the year 1899, ten years after the destruction of count Dracula chronicled in Bram Stoker's novel. You take the role of Alexander Morris, the younger brother of Texan Quincey Morris who died defeating Dracula. Alexander has come to London to investigate the circumstances of his brother's death, but became sidetracked when he fell in love with and proposed to a local girl named Annisette.

Now, the dawn of a new millennium approaches and an evil force is stalking the streets of London, draining victims of their blood and transforming innocent women into bloodthirsty vampiresses. With the aide of your brother's old friends, the survivors of Dracula's evil, you must uncover the identity of this new vampire and prevent him from transforming Annisette into his queen of the night. Do not fail her, or she will personally rip your throat out.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Dracula Unleashed (U) [Disc 2 of 2]-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <releasedate>19930101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>ICOM Simulations, Inc.</developer>
    <publisher>Sega</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Game no Kandume - Sega Games Can Vol. 1 (J).cue</path>
    <name>Game no Kandume - Sega Games Can Vol. 1</name>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <releasedate>19691231T160000</releasedate>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Game no Kandume - Sega Games Can Vol. 2 (J).cue</path>
    <name>Game no Kandume - Sega Games Can Vol. 2</name>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <releasedate>19691231T160000</releasedate>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Ground Zero Texas (U) [Disc 1 of 2].cue</path>
    <name>Ground Zero: Texas (Disc 1/2)</name>
    <desc>Space aliens are infiltrating the U.S. from a sleepy little town on the Texas/Mexico border, snatching bodies and paving the way for a greater invasion. Those they abduct return as Pod People-like drones, normal in appearance until they reveal themselves. The government's response is you - a technician driving custom-built gun cameras mounted around the town. Similar to Night Trap or Double Switch, you must monitor the town for alien activity, and respond to protect the lives of the citizens and your agents.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Ground Zero Texas (U) [Disc 1 of 2]-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <releasedate>19930101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Digital Pictures</developer>
    <publisher>Sega</publisher>
    <genre>Action, Shooter</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Ground Zero Texas (U) [Disc 2 of 2].cue</path>
    <name>Ground Zero: Texas (Disc 2/2)</name>
    <desc>Space aliens are infiltrating the U.S. from a sleepy little town on the Texas/Mexico border, snatching bodies and paving the way for a greater invasion. Those they abduct return as Pod People-like drones, normal in appearance until they reveal themselves. The government's response is you - a technician driving custom-built gun cameras mounted around the town. Similar to Night Trap or Double Switch, you must monitor the town for alien activity, and respond to protect the lives of the citizens and your agents.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Ground Zero Texas (U) [Disc 2 of 2]-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <releasedate>19930101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Digital Pictures</developer>
    <publisher>Sega</publisher>
    <genre>Action, Shooter</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Johnny Mnemonic (U) (Unreleased) [Disc 1 of 2].cue</path>
    <name>Johnny Mnemonic (Unreleased) (Disc 1/2)</name>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <releasedate>19691231T160000</releasedate>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Johnny Mnemonic (U) (Unreleased) [Disc 2 of 2].cue</path>
    <name>Johnny Mnemonic (Unreleased) (Disc 2/2)</name>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <releasedate>19691231T160000</releasedate>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Night Trap (U) [Disc 1 of 2].cue</path>
    <name>Night Trap (Disc 1/2)</name>
    <desc>Five girls go to a party to a nice house on a lakeside. Five girls disappear without a trace... Now another five girls go there, in order to spend the vacation with the Martins, the owners of the house, in particular with the lovely Ms. Martin. This time, you should not let them die a gruesome death! Because "nice people" can sometimes turn out to be... yes, that's right - vampires. The whole house is full of traps, that are intended to catch the poor innocent girls, so that the vampires can suck their blood... ugh. Luckily, the brave adventurer is there in order to cease to be hunted and to become a hunter instead! Set the traps so that they will capture the villains themselves, using precise timing and good organization.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Night Trap (U) [Disc 1 of 2]-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <releasedate>19920701T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Digital Pictures</developer>
    <publisher>Sega</publisher>
    <genre>Action, Horror</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Night Trap (U) [Disc 2 of 2].cue</path>
    <name>Night Trap (Disc 2/2)</name>
    <desc>Five girls go to a party to a nice house on a lakeside. Five girls disappear without a trace... Now another five girls go there, in order to spend the vacation with the Martins, the owners of the house, in particular with the lovely Ms. Martin. This time, you should not let them die a gruesome death! Because "nice people" can sometimes turn out to be... yes, that's right - vampires. The whole house is full of traps, that are intended to catch the poor innocent girls, so that the vampires can suck their blood... ugh. Luckily, the brave adventurer is there in order to cease to be hunted and to become a hunter instead! Set the traps so that they will capture the villains themselves, using precise timing and good organization.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Night Trap (U) [Disc 2 of 2]-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <releasedate>19920701T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Digital Pictures</developer>
    <publisher>Sega</publisher>
    <genre>Action, Horror</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Penn &amp; Teller's Smoke and Mirrors (U) [Disc 1 of 2].cue</path>
    <name>Penn &amp; Teller's Smoke and Mirrors (Disc 1/2)</name>
    <desc>Penn &amp; Teller's Smoke and Mirrors is a Simulation game, developed and published by Absolute Entertainment, which was cancelled before it was released.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Penn &amp; Teller's Smoke and Mirrors (U) [Disc 1 of 2]-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <releasedate>19950401T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Absolute Entertainment</developer>
    <publisher>Absolute Entertainment</publisher>
    <genre>Puzzle</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Penn &amp; Teller's Smoke and Mirrors (U) [Disc 2 of 2].cue</path>
    <name>Penn &amp; Teller's Smoke and Mirrors (Disc 2/2)</name>
    <desc>Penn &amp; Teller's Smoke and Mirrors is a Simulation game, developed and published by Absolute Entertainment, which was cancelled before it was released.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Penn &amp; Teller's Smoke and Mirrors (U) [Disc 2 of 2]-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <releasedate>19950401T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Absolute Entertainment</developer>
    <publisher>Absolute Entertainment</publisher>
    <genre>Puzzle</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Prize Fighter (U) [Disc 1 of 2].cue</path>
    <name>Prize Fighter (Disc 1/2)</name>
    <desc>Prize Fighter is a FMV boxing game which puts the player in the body of a boxer known as "The Kid" and must face off against four opponents: Honeyboy Fernandez, Mega Joe Falco, Rex Hawkins, and, the ultimate challenge, Nuke "The Duke" Johnson, over the course of two CDs.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Prize Fighter (U) [Disc 1 of 2]-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <releasedate>19940101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Digital Pictures</developer>
    <publisher>Sega</publisher>
    <genre>Fighting</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Prize Fighter (U) [Disc 2 of 2].cue</path>
    <name>Prize Fighter (Disc 2/2)</name>
    <desc>Prize Fighter is a FMV boxing game which puts the player in the body of a boxer known as "The Kid" and must face off against four opponents: Honeyboy Fernandez, Mega Joe Falco, Rex Hawkins, and, the ultimate challenge, Nuke "The Duke" Johnson, over the course of two CDs.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Prize Fighter (U) [Disc 2 of 2]-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <releasedate>19940101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Digital Pictures</developer>
    <publisher>Sega</publisher>
    <genre>Fighting</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Sherlock Holmes - Consulting Detective Vol. II (U) [Disc 1 of 2].cue</path>
    <name>Sherlock Holmes: Consulting Detective Vol. II (Disc 1/2)</name>
    <desc>The same structure brings a familiar look, inviting to channel all attention to the task of solving mysteries: your intelligence, skills and patience are required to find clues by listening to people, observing details, or even reading the London Times - but don't let yourself be misguided by a wrong hint.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Sherlock Holmes - Consulting Detective Vol. II (U) [Disc 1 of 2]-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <releasedate>19930101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>ICOM Simulations, Inc.</developer>
    <publisher>ICOM Simulations, Inc.</publisher>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Sherlock Holmes - Consulting Detective Vol. II (U) [Disc 2 of 2].cue</path>
    <name>Sherlock Holmes: Consulting Detective Vol. II (Disc 2/2)</name>
    <desc>The same structure brings a familiar look, inviting to channel all attention to the task of solving mysteries: your intelligence, skills and patience are required to find clues by listening to people, observing details, or even reading the London Times - but don't let yourself be misguided by a wrong hint.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Sherlock Holmes - Consulting Detective Vol. II (U) [Disc 2 of 2]-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <releasedate>19930101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>ICOM Simulations, Inc.</developer>
    <publisher>ICOM Simulations, Inc.</publisher>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Slam City with Scottie Pippen (U) [Disc 1 of 4].cue</path>
    <name>Slam City with Scottie Pippen (Disc 1/4)</name>
    <desc>Slam City with Scottie Pippen is a Full-Motion-Video basketball game. It uses proprietary technology to allow switching from one scene to another without lag, which allows for smoother interactive video.
The game features a total of 13 characters, 5 of which the player has an option to play against, all of which are played by real actors.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Slam City with Scottie Pippen (U) [Disc 1 of 4]-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <releasedate>19940801T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Digital Pictures</developer>
    <publisher>Digital Pictures, Inc.</publisher>
    <genre>Action, Sports</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Slam City with Scottie Pippen (U) [Disc 2 of 4].cue</path>
    <name>Slam City with Scottie Pippen (Disc 2/4)</name>
    <desc>Slam City with Scottie Pippen is a Full-Motion-Video basketball game. It uses proprietary technology to allow switching from one scene to another without lag, which allows for smoother interactive video.
The game features a total of 13 characters, 5 of which the player has an option to play against, all of which are played by real actors.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Slam City with Scottie Pippen (U) [Disc 2 of 4]-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <releasedate>19940801T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Digital Pictures</developer>
    <publisher>Digital Pictures, Inc.</publisher>
    <genre>Action, Sports</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Slam City with Scottie Pippen (U) [Disc 3 of 4].cue</path>
    <name>Slam City with Scottie Pippen (Disc 3/4)</name>
    <desc>Slam City with Scottie Pippen is a Full-Motion-Video basketball game. It uses proprietary technology to allow switching from one scene to another without lag, which allows for smoother interactive video.
The game features a total of 13 characters, 5 of which the player has an option to play against, all of which are played by real actors.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Slam City with Scottie Pippen (U) [Disc 3 of 4]-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <releasedate>19940801T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Digital Pictures</developer>
    <publisher>Digital Pictures, Inc.</publisher>
    <genre>Action, Sports</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Slam City with Scottie Pippen (U) [Disc 4 of 4].cue</path>
    <name>Slam City with Scottie Pippen (Disc 4/4)</name>
    <desc>Slam City with Scottie Pippen is a Full-Motion-Video basketball game. It uses proprietary technology to allow switching from one scene to another without lag, which allows for smoother interactive video.
The game features a total of 13 characters, 5 of which the player has an option to play against, all of which are played by real actors.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Slam City with Scottie Pippen (U) [Disc 4 of 4]-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <releasedate>19940801T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Digital Pictures</developer>
    <publisher>Digital Pictures, Inc.</publisher>
    <genre>Action, Sports</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Supreme Warrior (U) [Disc 1 of 2].cue</path>
    <name>Supreme Warrior (Disc 1/2)</name>
    <desc>Supreme Warrior is a full-motion video fighting game. The game, or interactive movie, is set in China hundreds of years ago. You are tasked with protecting half of a magical mask. The wearer of the mask will be granted untold power. Unfortunately, the villanous Wang Tu has the other half of the mask, and wants your half badly. So, you must fight off Wang Tu's minions, and eventually Fang Tu himself.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Supreme Warrior (U) [Disc 1 of 2]-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <releasedate>19940101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Digital Pictures</developer>
    <publisher>Digital Pictures, Inc.</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Supreme Warrior (U) [Disc 2 of 2].cue</path>
    <name>Supreme Warrior (Disc 2/2)</name>
    <desc>Supreme Warrior is a full-motion video fighting game. The game, or interactive movie, is set in China hundreds of years ago. You are tasked with protecting half of a magical mask. The wearer of the mask will be granted untold power. Unfortunately, the villanous Wang Tu has the other half of the mask, and wants your half badly. So, you must fight off Wang Tu's minions, and eventually Fang Tu himself.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Supreme Warrior (U) [Disc 2 of 2]-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <releasedate>19940101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Digital Pictures</developer>
    <publisher>Digital Pictures, Inc.</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./BATTLETECH - Gray Death Legion (U).cue</path>
    <name>Battletech: Gray Death Legion</name>
    <desc>Battletech: Gray Death Legion is an unreleased mech shooter game for the Sega Mega-CD and Sega Saturn set to be published by Absolute Entertainment, and based on FASA's Battletech universe. The game uses a first-person perspective for the action, and is similar to Absolute's RDF: Global Conflict, also on Mega-CD. Nothing is known about the Saturn version other than being mentioned on some magazines of the time, but it's likely it would've played similarly.

The game was put on indefinite hold in late 1995 due to the poor state of Absolute's finances.

Sometime in the 2000s, a prototype of the Mega-CD version was found, which was later given a commercial unlicensed release by Good Deal Games.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/BATTLETECH - Gray Death Legion (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <publisher>Absolute Entertainment</publisher>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20200507T231031</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Bloodshot (E).cue</path>
    <name>Bloodshot</name>
    <desc>Bloodshot, known as Battle Frenzy in Germany, is a Sega Mega Drive and Sega Mega-CD game developed by Domark. It is notable for being a 3D first person shooter - one of the few available for the Sega Mega Drive and the only game of this genre for the Sega Mega-CD.

The game takes up most of the screen, with much smaller borders than similar games such as Zero Tolerance, a very impressive technical achievement. A two player splitscreen mode is also available. However, the game also suffers from slowdown and some of the texture data of the Mega Drive version looks corrupted but this was fixed with the Mega-CD version.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Bloodshot (E)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19940101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Acclaim</developer>
    <publisher>Sega</publisher>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <playcount>2</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20200507T231709</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Annett Futatabi (J).cue</path>
    <name>Anett Futatabi</name>
    <desc>After being rescued from certain sacrifice by Earnest Evans, Annet travels across Europe and encounters a group that wants a pendant in her possession. After being ambushed by them she escapes and begins a quest to protect the world from destruction.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/Annett Futatabi (J)-image.png</image>
    <releasedate>19930330T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Wolf Team</developer>
    <publisher>Wolf Team</publisher>
    <genre>Action, Fighting</genre>
    <playcount>7</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20200508T021137</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./After Burner III (U).cue</path>
    <name>After Burner III</name>
    <desc>You're strapped into the Navy's fiercest jet fighter-the F-14 Tomcat. Kick in the afterburner to outrun deadly cannon fire "hot on your six." Pull up hard...lock and launch! Roll 360 degrees to blow desert tank patrols, radio towers, and missile sites into oblivion.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/After Burner III (U)-image.png</image>
    <releasedate>19920417T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>CRI</developer>
    <publisher>Sega</publisher>
    <genre>Shooter, Vehicle Simulation</genre>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20200515T223711</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./3 Ninjas Kick Back (U).cue</path>
    <name>3 Ninjas Kick Back</name>
    <desc>You must help an old samurai to retrieve a dagger he once got as an award for his achievements in martial arts. The dagger was stolen by somebody who envied the old warrior - now he cannot give this prize to the warriors of the next generation. Choose one of the three young ninjas to help the old man!

This is a traditional platform game based on the movie 3 Ninjas Kick Back. Each one of the three ninjas has unique weapons and abilities. All three of them can run, duck, crawl, climb, jump, and hang on trees, ropes, etc. You'll encounter many obstacles and enemies, both regular and boss-like, which you'll have to overcome and defeat.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/segacd/3 Ninjas Kick Back (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19940601T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Malibu Interactive</developer>
    <publisher>Sony</publisher>
    <genre>Platform</genre>
    <players>2</players>
    <playcount>3</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20200516T011909</lastplayed>
  </game>
</gameList>
