<?xml version="1.0"?>
<gameList>
  <game>
    <path>./Descent Rebirth.sh</path>
    <name>Descent</name>
    <desc>The game requires the player to navigate labyrinthine mines while fighting virus-infected robots. The player is given the clear objective to find and destroy each mine's reactor core and escape before the mine is destroyed by the meltdown. To obtain access to the reactor, the player must collect the blue, yellow, and red access keys for each location. As an optional objective, the player can also choose to rescue PTMC workers that were taken hostage by the infected robots.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/ports/Descent Rebirth-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <releasedate>19950228T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Parallax Software</developer>
    <publisher>Interplay Entertainment Corp.</publisher>
    <genre>Action, Shooter, Flight Simulator</genre>
    <playcount>2</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20190706T162035</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Descent 2 Rebirth.sh</path>
    <name>Descent II</name>
    <desc>Descent II is a 1996 first-person shooter video game developed by Parallax Software and published by Interplay Productions. It is the second game in the Descent video game series and a sequel to the original Descent. Unlike standard first-person shooters, the player must control a flying ship that has a six degrees of freedom movement scheme, allowing the player to move in any 3D direction. The game received very positive reviews from video game critics. A sequel, Descent 3, was released in 1999.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/ports/Descent 2 Rebirth-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <releasedate>19960209T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Parallax Software</developer>
    <publisher>Interplay Entertainment Corp.</publisher>
    <genre>Action, Shooter, Flight Simulator</genre>
    <players>4</players>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20190706T164514</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./DOOM - Freedoom Phase 2.sh</path>
    <name>DOOM - Freedoom Phase 2</name>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20190706T163804</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./DOOM - 2 - Hell on Earth.sh</path>
    <name>Doom II</name>
    <desc>Immediately following the events in Doom, the player once again takes the role of the anonymous space marine who has proven too tough to be contained. After being teleported from Phobos, and subsequently fighting on Deimos which is suspended above Hell, the Marine finds himself back home on Earth, only to find that it too has fallen victim to the hellish invasion, leaving billions of people dead.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/ports/DOOM - 2 - Hell on Earth-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <releasedate>19940930T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>id Software</developer>
    <publisher>GT Interactive Software Corp.</publisher>
    <genre>Action, Shooter</genre>
    <players>4</players>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20190706T155528</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./DOOM - Freedoom Phase 1.sh</path>
    <name>Doom: Freedom Phase 1</name>
    <desc>In Doom, a nameless space marine, gets punitively posted to Mars after assaulting a commanding officer, who ordered his unit to fire upon civilians. The Martian marine base acts as security for the Union Aerospace Corporation UAC, a multi-planetary conglomerate, which is performing secret experiments with teleportation by creating gateways between the two moons of Mars, Phobos and Deimos. Suddenly, one of these UAC experiments goes horribly wrong; computer systems on Phobos malfunction, Deimos disappears entirely and "something fragging evil" starts pouring out of the gateways, killing or possessing all UAC personnel! 
Responding to a frantic distress call from the overrun scientists, the Martian marine unit is quickly sent to Phobos to investigate, where you, the space marine, are left to guard the hangar with only a pistol while the rest of the group proceeds inside to discover their worst nightmare. As you advance further, terrifying screams echo through the vast halls, followed by a disturbing silence ... it seems, all your buddies are dead and you're all on your own now - fight back, exterminate every evil creature and get your ticket back home to earth!</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/ports/DOOM - Freedoom Phase 1-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <releasedate>19931210T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>id Software</developer>
    <publisher>id Software</publisher>
    <genre>Action, Shooter</genre>
    <players>4</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Abuse.sh</path>
    <name>Abuse</name>
    <desc>It is the unimaginably distant year 2009. You are Nick Vrenna, falsely locked inside a high security prison. The genetic experiments conducted in the prison, combined with a full-scale riot that took place recently, caused all guards and inmates to be transformed into insane, aggressive mutants. Your job is to escape while stopping the genetic plague from transforming the whole world. 

Abuse is a side-scrolling platformer with a lot of shooting. It's a nonlinear game, as the levels often have a few exits that lead to different areas. Your character is a cyborg equipped with various weapons; initially, you only have a weak laser rifle with unlimited ammo, but you can find more powerful guns later on, such as grenade launchers, flamethrowers or lightsabers. You move through a building complex, fighting any enemies you might encounter on the way. The enemies are mostly the mutants, but also the defense systems (such as stationary missile launchers). 

While you move with the keyboard, you can aim with your mouse, so you can shoot at any angle no matter what direction you are running. On your way, you'll find elevators, teleporters, cracked walls that can be destroyed and more. 

Apart from ammo and health, you can also find upgrades which have a number of beneficial effect - increasing your running speed, for example.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/ports/Abuse-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <releasedate>19960101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Crack dot Com</developer>
    <publisher>Crack dot Com</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <playcount>2</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20190714T013622</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./C-Dogs SDL.sh</path>
    <name>C-Dogs SDL</name>
    <desc>C-Dogs SDL is a classic overhead run-and-gun game, supporting up to 4 players in co-op and deathmatch modes. Customize your player, choose from many weapons, and blast, slide and slash your way through over 100 user-created campaigns. Have fun!</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/ports/C-Dogs SDL-image.png</image>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <releasedate>20130723T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Jeremy Chin, Lucas Martin-King, Cong Xu</developer>
    <publisher>Cong Xu</publisher>
    <genre>Shooter, Stealth</genre>
    <players>4</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Dinothawr.sh</path>
    <name>Dinothawr</name>
    <desc>Dinothawr is a simple puzzle game made by Agnes Heyer and Hans-Kristian Arntzen (AKA Themaister, original creator of the RetroArch/libretro project).
The goal of the game is to save your frozen friends by pushing them onto lava so they can thaw. It mixes gameplay mechanics from Kickle Cubicle and Sokoban with some lovely ambient homegrown music.

Features:
* 50+ levels
* Level editor
* Shaders for enhanced graphics, and/or plain retro graphics for pixel purists

This game comes with a customized standalone version of RetroArch serving as the frontend. This is the first game based solely around the libretro API.

Like libretro/RetroArch, the game is open source and its source can be obtained on Github.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/ports/Dinothawr-image.png</image>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <releasedate>20130921T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Hans-Kristian Arntzen "Themaister"</developer>
    <publisher>Libretro</publisher>
    <genre>Puzzle</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Duke Nukem 3D.sh</path>
    <name>Duke Nukem 3D</name>
    <desc>As a first-person shooter, the gameplay of Duke Nukem 3D involves moving through levels presented from the protagonist's point of view, shooting enemies on the way. The environment of Duke Nukem 3D is highly destructible and interactive; most props can be destroyed by the player.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/ports/Duke Nukem 3D-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <releasedate>19960129T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>3D Realms Entertainment</developer>
    <publisher>GT Interactive Software Corp.</publisher>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <players>4</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Giana's Return.sh</path>
    <name>Giana's Return</name>
    <desc>Evil Swampy and his followers have stolen the magic ruby, which made it once possible for Giana and Maria to return from their dream. Many creatures are after this ruby, but does it really has power, or was it just a coincidence?As this is not bad enough, Swampy fell in love at first sight with Giana&amp;#x2019;s sister Maria and shamelessly kidnapped her. She simply has been at the wrong place at the wrong time.You will now have to take on the role of Giana and get back the magic ruby. And most important of all, save your beloved sister Maria and get home save! Good Luck!</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/ports/Giana's Return-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <releasedate>20090815T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Retroguru</developer>
    <publisher>Giana's Return Team</publisher>
    <genre>Platform</genre>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20190512T031939</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Minecraft.sh</path>
    <name>Minecraft: Pi Edition</name>
    <desc>Minecraft: Pi Edition is a version of Minecraft developed for the Raspberry Pi. It is based on an old version Alpha 0.6.1 of Pocket Edition but is slightly cut down, containing a revised feature set and support for multiple programming languages. The Pi Edition is intended as an educational tool for novice programmers. Although officially discontinued, it is still available to download for free, from the official downloads page, and users are encouraged to interact with the game using an API.

It was developed by Aron Nieminen, one of the developers of the Pocket Edition, as well as Daniel Frisk. It is no longer officially supported, but the download still exists on the Pi Edition website.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/ports/Minecraft-image.png</image>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <releasedate>20130211T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Aron Nieminen, Daniel Frisk</developer>
    <publisher>Mojang AB</publisher>
    <genre>Sandbox</genre>
    <players>4</players>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20190714T014224</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Mr.Boom.sh</path>
    <name>Mr. Boom</name>
    <desc>Mr.Boom is a Bomberman clone for the RetroArch platform and was converted from DOS assembly using asm2c.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/ports/Mr.Boom-image.png</image>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <releasedate>19691231T160000</releasedate>
    <genre>Action, Strategy</genre>
    <players>4</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Prince of Persia.sh</path>
    <name>Prince of Persia</name>
    <desc>Prince of Persia was originally released in 1989 for the Apple II by Jordan Mechner. Mechner used film of his younger brother David running, jumping, and performing many of the Prince's actions. Mechner then rotoscoped the film to create the animations that give the Prince his fluid movement.

Part of the game's appeal was its then unique focus on environmental puzzle-solving, as well as its one-on-one sword duels. Mechner has stated that the game was inspired by the first ten minutes of Raiders of the Lost Ark, for the character's acrobatics in a dangerous environment.

Prince of Persia has since been ported to a number of different platforms, including the Amiga, Apple Macintosh, DOS, NES, Game Boy, Sega Genesis, Game Gear, SNES, Sharp X68000, Atari ST, and SAM Coup&amp;#xE9;.

The music was written by Jordan Mechner's father, Francis Mechner.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/ports/Prince of Persia-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <releasedate>19891003T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Atari Games</developer>
    <genre>Platform</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Quake.sh</path>
    <name>Quake</name>
    <desc>The player takes the role of an un-named protagonist sent into a portal in order to stop an enemy code-named "Quake". Previously, the government had been experimenting with teleportation technology, and upon development of a working prototype called a "Slipgate", this enemy has compromised the human connection with their own teleportation system, using it to insert death squads into the "human" dimension, supposedly in order to test the martial capabilities of humanity.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/ports/Quake-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <releasedate>19960622T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>id Software</developer>
    <publisher>GT Interactive Software Corp.</publisher>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <players>4</players>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20190510T002520</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Wolfenstein 3D - Spear of Destiny Demo.sh</path>
    <name>Spear of Destiny</name>
    <desc>The game consists of a single 21-level episode, 19 of which need to be completed in order to win the game. The remaining two levels are secret levels that can be accessed from within the first 18 levels. The gameplay is identical to that of Wolfenstein 3D, which uses the same game engine. The levels can be divided into four blocks ("Tunnels", "Dungeons", "Castle", and "Ramparts"), each ending with the player having to defeat a "boss".</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/ports/Wolfenstein 3D - Spear of Destiny Demo-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <releasedate>19920918T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>id Software</developer>
    <publisher>FormGen, Inc.</publisher>
    <genre>Action, Shooter</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Steam Link.sh</path>
    <name>Steam Link (Raspberry Pi)</name>
    <desc>Steam Link is a free application made to stream Steam games from a host computer, the Raspberry Pi version was released in Beta on December 3 2018, then released in full on December 13 2018. This app was designed to mimic the functionality of it's hardware namesake. Unlike most PC ports to the "Pi," this version was specifically designed by Valve themselves to run on the Raspberry Pi's flagship OS, Raspbian.

The following information has been compiled from the official Steam Link "About" Page:
(https://store.steampowered.com/steamlink/about/)

The Steam Link app is available free of charge, streaming your Steam games to phones, tablets, and TV. No download or service fees apply. The Steam Link app supports the Steam Controller over Bluetooth, as well as other popular Bluetooth controllers, mice, and keyboards. Simply download the app and connect to your host computer running Steam to expand the range of your Steam gaming experience.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/ports/Steam Link-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <releasedate>20181213T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Valve Corporation</developer>
    <publisher>Valve Corporation</publisher>
    <genre>Action, Adventure, Construction and Management Simulation, Role-Playing, Puzzle, Strategy, Racing, Shooter, Life Simulation, Fighting, Sports, Sandbox, Flight Simulator, MMO, Platform, Stealth, Music, Horror, Vehicle Simulation</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Super Mario War.sh</path>
    <name>Super Mario War</name>
    <desc>Super Mario War is an open source, cross-platform, platform-adventure video game and level editor. It is unofficially based upon gameplay elements and audiovisual media that are cloned from Nintendo's Super Mario series. The game centers on players fighting each other by one player jumping on the other player's head, or by making use of items which can be picked up during gameplay.

The gameplay is somewhat simple. In various game modes, players may jump on each other's heads to defeat each other or they may use items found in the power-up boxes. The game has a variety of such configurable settings to determine when certain items spawn in the power-up boxes, the way players spawn onscreen, and more.

The game includes a campaign mode based upon an overworld similar to that of Super Mario Bros. 3. However, instead of levels, the player simply fights more of the characters featured in the game although controlled by the CPU player. The player moves onto the next level when the enemy is defeated.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/ports/Super Mario War-image.png</image>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <releasedate>20061216T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Michael Schaffer, Florian Hufsky</developer>
    <genre>Fighting, Platform</genre>
    <players>4</players>
    <playcount>2</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20190629T230833</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./The Plutonia Experiment.sh</path>
    <name>The Plutonia Experiment</name>
    <desc>After Hell's catastrophic invasion of Earth, the global governments decide to take measures against any possible future invasion, knowing that the powers of Hell still remain strong. The UAC corporation is refounded under completely new management (the old trustees and stockholders are all dead in any case) and aims to develop tools that would prevent demonic invasions. It is said that the new UAC base is on one of Jupiter's moons, Io. UAC's scientists thought that this distance from Earth might prevent another catastrophic invasion, but as the events of TNT: Evilution showed, this was not the case. Something else would be needed.

UAC's scientists start working on quantum accelerator devices intended to close interdimensional gates and stop possible invasions. The experiments are carried out in a secret research complex, with a stationed detachment of marines. The work seems to be going well, but...

The creatures from Outside have their dire attention drawn towards the new research. A gate opens in the heart of the complex and unnatural horrors pour out. The quantum accelerator performs superbly &amp;#x2014; the gate is quickly closed and the invasion stopped. Research continues more boldly.

On the next day, a ring of seven gates opens and an even greater invasion commences. For a single hour the quantum accelerators manage to close six of the seven gates... but the hellish army has become too numerous and too strong. The complex is overrun. Everyone present is slain, or zombified. The last gate of Hell remains open, manned and guarded by a demon Gatekeeper.

The government, frantic that the quantum accelerator will be destroyed or used in some evil alien fashion against humanity, orders all marines to the site at once. Doomguy is the closest one to the site and gets there first. There he concludes that by the time reinforcements arrive that the demons will be too numerous and powerful.

The marine decides to enter the complex and stop the Gatekeeper alone.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/ports/The Plutonia Experiment-image.png</image>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <releasedate>19960617T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Casali Brothers</developer>
    <publisher>id Software</publisher>
    <genre>Action, Shooter</genre>
    <players>4</players>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20190714T014703</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Ur-quan Masters.sh</path>
    <name>The Ur Quan Masters</name>
    <desc>In the last phase of the war between the Alliance of Free Stars and the Hierarchy of Battle Thralls, the Tobermoon, an Earthling ship, discovered an ancient Precursor subterranean installation in a cave on the surface of an uninhabited planet in the Vela star system. The Alliance hastily sent a secret scientific mission to study the relics, but a massive Hierarchy offensive forced the Alliance fleets to retreat beyond Vela; the mission commander, Captain Burton, decided to go into hiding on the planet and sent back the Tobermoon, her only starship, asking for help. Though the Ur-Quan forces didn't find the Earthlings during their sweep of the system, relief never arrived. Years later, with the help of a genius child born on the planet, the colonists activated the Precursor machinery and found out that it was programmed to build a starship. Using the limited store of raw materials available in the planet, in ten years the Precursor factory built a (barely) functional ship, which could be piloted only by the now grown genius child, who alone could interact with the Precursor central computer. In the first test flight, it was discovered that the ship Burton had sent for help had been severely damaged by the Ur-Quan and was orbiting unpowered in the outer solar system: the Alliance had never known of the mission's discoveries. The colonists decided to fix the recovered ship, train new crew members for both the Precursor ship and the Tobermoon and send a mission back to Earth, eager to know how the war had ended. Shortly before reaching Sol the little fleet was attacked by an unknown ship; Captain Burton, commanding the Earthling ship, intercepted the alien ship before it could damage the defenseless Precursor starship, but was killed in the short fight, leaving the genius young man in command</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/ports/Ur-quan Masters-image.png</image>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <releasedate>19921101T000000</releasedate>
    <genre>Adventure, Shooter</genre>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20190512T155338</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./TNT - Evilution.sh</path>
    <name>TNT: Evilution</name>
    <desc>In TNT: Evilution the UAC once again are intent on developing and experimenting with dimensional gateway technology. They set up a base on Io, one of the moons of Jupiter, with a solid detachment of space marines for protection. The marines do their job well: when the first experimental gateway is opened they annihilate the forces of Hell. Anything that came through the gateway was immediately destroyed by the marines, and so research on the gateways continued.

Later, the yearly supply ship came earlier than expected, and looks strange and unusually large on the radar. The personnel of the base go out to behold the terrible truth: it is a spaceship from Hell, built of steel, stone, flesh, bone and corruption. The ship's enormous gates open to unleash a rain of demons on the base. Quickly, the whole base is overrun, and everyone is slain or zombified.

The Doomguy, now in command of the marine deployment, has been away on a walk, and has thus escaped death or zombification. After being attacked by an imp he rushes back to the base, where he sees the demonic spaceship still hovering above it and realizes what has happened. Then he swears that he will seek vengeance for his slain troops, and sets out to kill as many evil creatures as possible.

In the end, the marine defeats the Demon-Spitter, and the game describes Something rumbles in the distance. A blue light begins to glow inside the ruined skull of the Demon-Spitter.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/ports/TNT - Evilution-image.png</image>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <releasedate>19960617T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Casali Brothers, TeamTNT</developer>
    <publisher>id Software</publisher>
    <genre>Action, Shooter</genre>
    <players>4</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Wolfenstein 3D demo.sh</path>
    <name>Wolfenstein 3D</name>
    <desc>The first three episodes of the game focus on William "B.J." Blazkowicz's attempts to escape from Castle Wolfenstein and overthrow the Nazi regime.

In the first episode, Escape from Castle Wolfenstein, B.J., an Allied spy, has been captured while trying to find the plans for Operation Eisenfaust, and was imprisoned in Castle Wolfenstein. Initially armed only with a knife and a Walther P38 (obtained by overpowering the guard in his cell), B.J. tries to escape the castle prison. Taking on SS guards, he eventually finds himself face to face with head prison guard Hans Grosse.

In the second episode, Operation: Eisenfaust, B.J. finds out that the operation is real, and that Nazis are creating an army of undead mutants in Castle Hollehammer. B.J. enters the castle and confronts the mad scientist Dr. Schabbs, creator of the mutants. His defeat signals the end of this biological war.

Die, F&amp;#xFC;hrer, Die! is, chronologically, the final episode. Fighting through Nazi soldiers, and attacking the bunker under the Reichstag, he finds himself up against Adolf Hitler himself (equipped with a robotic suit and 4 Gatling guns).</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/ports/Wolfenstein 3D demo-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <releasedate>19920101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>id Software</developer>
    <publisher>Apogee Software, Ltd.</publisher>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./OpenBlok.sh</path>
    <name>Openblok</name>
    <desc>Openblok is an open source Tetris clone.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/ports/OpenBlok-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <releasedate>19691231T160000</releasedate>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20190714T020238</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./OpenTyrian.sh</path>
    <name>OpenTyrian</name>
    <desc>Tyrian is an arcade-style vertical scrolling shooter. The story is set in 20,031 where you play as Trent Hawkins, a skilled fighter-pilot employed to fight Microsol and save the galaxy.

OpenTyrian is a port of the DOS shoot-em-up Tyrian. Jason Emery generously gave the OpenTyrian developers a copy of the Tyrian 2.1 source code, which has since been ported from Turbo Pascal to C. The port uses SDL, making it easily cross-platform.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/ports/OpenTyrian-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <releasedate>19691231T160000</releasedate>
    <playcount>5</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20190714T020724</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Sonic Robo Blast 2.sh</path>
    <name>Sonic Robo Blast 2</name>
    <desc>Sonic Robo Blast 2 is a 3D sonic fan game made on the Doom engine.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/ports/Sonic Robo Blast 2-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <releasedate>19691231T160000</releasedate>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20190714T021639</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./DOOM - 1.sh</path>
    <name>Doom</name>
    <desc>In Doom, a nameless space marine, gets punitively posted to Mars after assaulting a commanding officer, who ordered his unit to fire upon civilians. The Martian marine base acts as security for the Union Aerospace Corporation UAC, a multi-planetary conglomerate, which is performing secret experiments with teleportation by creating gateways between the two moons of Mars, Phobos and Deimos. Suddenly, one of these UAC experiments goes horribly wrong; computer systems on Phobos malfunction, Deimos disappears entirely and "something fragging evil" starts pouring out of the gateways, killing or possessing all UAC personnel! 
Responding to a frantic distress call from the overrun scientists, the Martian marine unit is quickly sent to Phobos to investigate, where you, the space marine, are left to guard the hangar with only a pistol while the rest of the group proceeds inside to discover their worst nightmare. As you advance further, terrifying screams echo through the vast halls, followed by a disturbing silence ... it seems, all your buddies are dead and you're all on your own now - fight back, exterminate every evil creature and get your ticket back home to earth!</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/ports/DOOM - 1-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <releasedate>19931210T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>id Software</developer>
    <publisher>id Software</publisher>
    <genre>Action, Shooter</genre>
    <players>4</players>
    <playcount>4</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20190820T111023</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Doom.sh</path>
    <name>Doom</name>
    <desc>In Doom, a nameless space marine, gets punitively posted to Mars after assaulting a commanding officer, who ordered his unit to fire upon civilians. The Martian marine base acts as security for the Union Aerospace Corporation UAC, a multi-planetary conglomerate, which is performing secret experiments with teleportation by creating gateways between the two moons of Mars, Phobos and Deimos. Suddenly, one of these UAC experiments goes horribly wrong; computer systems on Phobos malfunction, Deimos disappears entirely and "something fragging evil" starts pouring out of the gateways, killing or possessing all UAC personnel! 
Responding to a frantic distress call from the overrun scientists, the Martian marine unit is quickly sent to Phobos to investigate, where you, the space marine, are left to guard the hangar with only a pistol while the rest of the group proceeds inside to discover their worst nightmare. As you advance further, terrifying screams echo through the vast halls, followed by a disturbing silence ... it seems, all your buddies are dead and you're all on your own now - fight back, exterminate every evil creature and get your ticket back home to earth!</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/ports/Doom-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <releasedate>19931210T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>id Software</developer>
    <publisher>id Software</publisher>
    <genre>Action, Shooter</genre>
    <players>4</players>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20190511T040421</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Doom II.sh</path>
    <name>Doom II</name>
    <desc>Immediately following the events in Doom, the player once again takes the role of the anonymous space marine who has proven too tough to be contained. After being teleported from Phobos, and subsequently fighting on Deimos which is suspended above Hell, the Marine finds himself back home on Earth, only to find that it too has fallen victim to the hellish invasion, leaving billions of people dead.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/ports/Doom II-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <releasedate>19940930T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>id Software</developer>
    <publisher>GT Interactive Software Corp.</publisher>
    <genre>Action, Shooter</genre>
    <players>4</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./VVVVVV.sh</path>
    <name>VVVVVV</name>
    <desc>VVVVVV is a retro styled 2D platformer by Terry Cavanagh, creator of dozens of free games. You play as the fearless leader of a team of dimension exploring scientists who inadvertently crash, and are separated. The game involves exploring the strange world you've found yourself in, and reuniting your friends.

VVVVVV explores one simple game mechanic: you cannot jump - instead, you reverse your own gravity at the press of a button. The game focuses on playing with this mechanic in a variety of interesting ways.

The game is designed not to artificially gate your progress. In VVVVVV there are no locks, no power-ups, no switches, nothing to stop you progressing except the challenges themselves.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/ports/VVVVVV-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <releasedate>20100111T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Terry Cavanagh</developer>
    <publisher>Terry Cavanagh</publisher>
    <genre>Action, Puzzle, Platform</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Bombermaaan.sh</path>
    <name>Bombermaaan (Bomberman clone)</name>
    <desc>A native clone of the classic game, Bomberman.</desc>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <releasedate>19691231T160000</releasedate>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20190714T013903</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Cannonball - OutRun Engine.sh</path>
    <name>CannonBall (OutRun engine)</name>
    <desc>A native engine for the classic game, OutRun.

The player must race to the end of each stage as fast as possible against a time limit while avoiding traffic. At the end of each stage, the player is presented with a fork in the road where the player must choose one of two stages. The left route presents an easier stage, while the right offers a greater challenge. Passing through checkpoints awards the player with extra time. Once the timer reaches zero or the player completes the race, the game ends. In addition to the nonlinear gameplay, Out Run also offered the choice of music to listen to while driving, represented as radio stations.[</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/ports/Cannonball - OutRun Engine-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <releasedate>20121112T000000</releasedate>
    <genre>Racing</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Commander Genius.sh</path>
    <name>Commander Genius (Commander Keen engine)</name>
    <desc>Commander Genius is a software piece that interprets the Commander Keen Invasion of the Vorticons and Galaxy series. As fans and developers we try to implement new features, improve the gameplay and give players an experience that feels like playing the original game but a bit more refreshing.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/ports/Commander Genius-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <releasedate>20091119T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>gerstrong</developer>
    <publisher>gerstrong</publisher>
    <genre>Action, Adventure, Platform</genre>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20200508T171428</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Digger Remastered.sh</path>
    <name>Digger</name>
    <desc>Take control of a mechanical digging machine as you tunnel your way through the earth, searching for valuable gems and the even more valuable bags of gold! But watch out for Nobbins and Hobbins, and don't be careless enough to let the bags of gold crush you!

Digger is an arcade game combining elements of the popular arcade games Dig Dug and Mr. Do!. Players control the titular 'Digger' that can tunnel through dirt with ease. The goal of each level is to gather up each of the gems, which allows you to progress to the next stage. However, Nobbins and Hobbins are also lurking within the levels - Nobbins are fairly slow, but transform into Hobbins which are much quicker. The enemies can only chase Digger through the tunnels he creates - they cannot dig through the dirt themselves.

Digger's defenses consist of being able to shoot a single, rechargeable shot in the direction he is facing with F1 (which recharges after about thirty seconds), crushing his foes by digging underneath a gold bag and letting it plummet down, crushing anything in its path, or by collecting the bonus cherry that sometimes appears, causing Digger to become temporarily invincible.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/ports/Digger Remastered-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19830101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Windmill Software</developer>
    <publisher>Windmill Software</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Jump 'n Bump.sh</path>
    <name>Jump 'n Bump</name>
    <genre/>
    <players/>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Super Flappy Birds.sh</path>
    <name>Super Flappy Birds</name>
    <desc>A multiplayer clone of the game, Flappy Bird.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/ports/Super Flappy Birds-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>20190127T000000</releasedate>
    <publisher>Self-Published</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <players>8</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./XRick.sh</path>
    <name>XRick</name>
    <desc>Port of the classic game, Rick Dangerous.

The plot of Rick Dangerous is largely based on the Indiana Jones movie Raiders of the Lost Ark. Set in 1945, British agent Rick Dangerous travels to the Amazon jungle to search for the lost Goolu tribe. His plane crashes in the jungle, and Rick must escape from the enraged Goolu. When the game starts Rick finds himself in a cave running from a rolling boulder, a famous scene from the Indiana Jones movie.

Armed with a pistol and dynamite, Rick must fight hostiles and evade traps in three more levels. The second level of the game is set inside a pyramid located in Egypt. In the third level, Rick must venture to the Nazi stronghold of Schwarzendumpf castle to rescue captured Allied soldiers. The rescued soldiers tell him that the Nazis are planning a missile attack on London. Therefore, in the last level, Rick must infiltrate their secret missile base.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/ports/XRick-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <releasedate>19890101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Core Design Ltd.</developer>
    <publisher>Rainbird Software</publisher>
    <genre>Platform</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Desktop.sh</path>
    <name>Desktop</name>
    <desc>'Pixel Desktop', a light-weight Linux desktop environment.  It provides some useful GUI tools and the Chromium web browser.

Select "Shutdown &amp;gt;&amp;gt; Exit to command line" to return to RetroPie.</desc>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <releasedate>19691231T160000</releasedate>
    <playcount>4</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20200515T182200</lastplayed>
  </game>
</gameList>
