<?xml version="1.0"?>
<gameList>
  <game>
    <path>/home/pi/RetroPie/roms/tg-cd/Black Hole Assault (NTSC-J) [MNCD3001].cue</path>
    <name>Black Hole Assault</name>
    <cover/>
    <image/>
    <marquee/>
    <rating/>
    <desc/>
    <releasedate/>
    <developer/>
    <publisher/>
    <genre/>
    <players/>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>/home/pi/RetroPie/roms/tg-cd/Davis Cup Tennis, The (Japan).cue</path>
    <name>Davis Cup Tennis, The (Japan)</name>
    <cover/>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_media/tg-cd/screenshots/Davis Cup Tennis, The (Japan).png</image>
    <marquee/>
    <rating/>
    <desc/>
    <releasedate/>
    <developer/>
    <publisher/>
    <genre>Sports / Tennis, Sports</genre>
    <players/>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>/home/pi/RetroPie/roms/tg-cd/Faceball (NTSC-J) [RHCD-3007].cue</path>
    <name>Faceball</name>
    <cover/>
    <image/>
    <marquee/>
    <rating/>
    <desc/>
    <releasedate/>
    <developer/>
    <publisher/>
    <genre/>
    <players/>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>/home/pi/RetroPie/roms/tg-cd/Kick Boxing (NTSC-J) [MWCD2001].cue</path>
    <name>Kick Boxing</name>
    <cover/>
    <image/>
    <marquee/>
    <rating/>
    <desc/>
    <releasedate/>
    <developer/>
    <publisher/>
    <genre/>
    <players/>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>/home/pi/RetroPie/roms/tg-cd/Legion (NTSC-J) [TJCD0010].cue</path>
    <name>Legion</name>
    <cover/>
    <image/>
    <marquee/>
    <rating/>
    <desc/>
    <releasedate/>
    <developer/>
    <publisher/>
    <genre/>
    <players/>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>/home/pi/RetroPie/roms/tg-cd/Pro Yakyuu, The (1990) (Intec) (J).cue</path>
    <name>The Pro Yakyuu</name>
    <cover/>
    <image/>
    <marquee/>
    <rating/>
    <desc/>
    <releasedate/>
    <developer/>
    <publisher/>
    <genre/>
    <players/>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Asuka 120% Maxima Burning Fest (NTSC-J) [NAPR-1049].cue</path>
    <name>Asuka 120% Maxima BURNING Fest</name>
    <desc>Welcome to the "Ryouran Private School for Women" which educates the daughters of the upper echelons of society. Here, the high class clubs annually hold a martial arts tournament: the "Club Rivalry Budget Contest Mega Fight." Each character employs a different fighting style; techniques are unique to each club.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Asuka 120% Maxima Burning Fest (NTSC-J) [NAPR-1049]-image.png</image>
    <releasedate>19950728T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>NEC AVENUE, FILL IN CAFE</developer>
    <publisher>Kodansha</publisher>
    <genre>Fighting</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Avenger (NTSC-J) [TJCD0011].cue</path>
    <name>Avenger</name>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Avenger (NTSC-J) [TJCD0011]-image.jpg</image>
    <developer/>
    <publisher/>
    <genre/>
    <players/>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Baby Jo the Super Hero (NTSC-J) [MWCD2004].cue</path>
    <name>Baby Jo The Superhero</name>
    <rating>0.7</rating>
    <releasedate>19940520T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Hudson</developer>
    <publisher>Hudson</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Bakushou Yoshimoto Shinkigeki (NTSC-J) [HCD4045].cue</path>
    <name>Bakushou Yoshimoto ShinkiGeki</name>
    <desc>A Japanese comedy platformer</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Bakushou Yoshimoto Shinkigeki (NTSC-J) [HCD4045]-image.jpg</image>
    <developer/>
    <publisher>Hudson Soft</publisher>
    <genre>Platform</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Beyond Shadowgate [U][SCD][TGXCD1048][ICOM Simulations][1993][PCE][thx-1138-darkwater].cue</path>
    <name>Beyond Shadowgate</name>
    <desc>As the last descendant in the "Line of Kings", Prince Erik is summoned home to regain his rightful place on his father's throne. But alas, Prince Erik is accused of his father's murder by the evil Royal Advisor Belezaar, and is thrown into the dungeon to be executed at dawn. Your mission and destiny are intertwined. Escape the dungeon and start your long journey toward the land deep within Castle Shadowgate. Your quest is to free the kingdom from the evil grips of the Warlock Lord. You will need to make good use of all the resources you can find throughout your journey. Evil abounds, and creatures great and small will try to defeat you! Use the good that comes of it because the Legend of Shadowgate rests in your hands!</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Beyond Shadowgate [U][SCD][TGXCD1048][ICOM Simulations][1993][PCE][thx-1138-darkwater]-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0.6</rating>
    <releasedate>19930423T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>ICOM</developer>
    <publisher>Turbo Technologies</publisher>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Bomberman '94 Taikenban (J).cue</path>
    <name>Bomberman '94 Taikenban</name>
    <desc>Bomberman '94 Special Version (Japanese: &amp;#x30DC;&amp;#x30F3;&amp;#x30D0;&amp;#x30FC;&amp;#x30DE;&amp;#x30F3;'94&amp;#x4F53;&amp;#x9A13;&amp;#x7248;, Bonb&amp;#x101;man '94 taikenhan) is a limited edition demo of Bomberman '94 released on the TurboGrafx-16 game console only in Japan in 1993.
Only 10,000 copies of this pre-release title were produced, and were given away exclusively through Hudson Soft's newsletter and at one of the Hudson Soft Summer Caravan events.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Bomberman '94 Taikenban (J)-image.png</image>
    <developer>Hudson</developer>
    <publisher>Hudson</publisher>
    <genre>Puzzle</genre>
    <players>4+</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Bomberman - Panic Bomber (NTSC-J) [HCD4069].cue</path>
    <name>Bomberman: Panic Bomber</name>
    <desc>It is a "falling blocks" puzzle game based on the Bomberman franchise. The goal of the game is essentially to cause your opponent to lose by causing their gameplay field to fill to the top with objects. You do this by causing chains of bombs to explode, sending useless rubble over to your opponent's field, which they must then remove themselves. Bombs are earned by causing chains of three identical blocks to disappear. Bombs can only be blown up with an explosion from a lit bomb, which falls from the top of the screen every so often. If the player causes enough damage, they can eventually earn a giant bomb, which will remove a large amount of debris from the playing field, and cause their opponent a good deal of trouble.

The game's regular story mode revolves around Bomberman's hunt for the Golden Bomber statue. During his trek, he fights against several different odd characters, like Drifty the balloon, or Cecil the tiger. However, all that can really be earned from playing through this mode is a harder difficulty level, earned by finishing the entire story at the "hard" difficulty level. The player's progress is saved by a password system.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Bomberman - Panic Bomber (NTSC-J) [HCD4069]-image.png</image>
    <releasedate>19941222T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Hudson Soft</developer>
    <publisher>Hudson Soft</publisher>
    <genre>Puzzle</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Bonanza Bros. (Japan).cue</path>
    <name>Bonanza Bros</name>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Bonanza Bros. (Japan)-image.jpg</image>
    <developer>Sega</developer>
    <publisher>NEC Avenue</publisher>
    <genre/>
    <players/>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Browning (NTSC-J) [TJCD1020].cue</path>
    <name>Browning</name>
    <desc>Browning is a side-scrolling action game developed by Telenet Japan and published by Riot. A mysterious army is threatening to take over the world and, from their secret hideout, they are building a supreme weapon capable of wiping out the entire planet. Breed Schuyler and his heavy mechanical armor, codenamed "X-BR Browning" (The "BROWN INnovation Gunner"), are deployed to counter the impending threat. The operation "Running Saber" is a go - the machine and its pilot must both infiltrate the Sea-Square island, a man-made fortress that sits somewhere in the Atlantic Ocean, and destroy the enemy's secret weapon. The game consists of five long stages which have to be completed within a time limit, from the island surface to the enemy's underground military and research facility. The Browning comes equipped with a Vulcan gun and the mecha-suit can hover for a short period of time. A force field also protects the armor against enemy attacks and the device automatically recharges itself whenever the energy balance is low and as long as it hasn't reach zero. The game features infinite continues and the player is sent back to the beginning of a stage when the Browning receives a deadly blow. Browning is as English friendly as it gets and even features full English cutscenes.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Browning (NTSC-J) [TJCD1020]-image.png</image>
    <developer/>
    <publisher/>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <players/>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Buster Bros (U).cue</path>
    <name>Buster Bros.</name>
    <desc>Your goal is to destroy the balloons which bounce around the playfield. To accomplish this, you can shoot hooks which travel upwards, and blow up any balloon they touch. Depending on their size, they either split on two smaller ones, or evaporate if they're at their minimum size. Apart from balloons, some levels also have barriers that have to be destroyed with your hooks, since they often block your access to balloons. There are also some barriers which cannot ever be destroyed. Your character has the ability to climb ladders, but cannot jump.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Buster Bros (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19930101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Hudson</developer>
    <publisher>Hudson</publisher>
    <genre/>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Camp California (US).cue</path>
    <name>Camp California</name>
    <desc>Byron the surfing bear must rescue his lil' bro and their three friends and stop a crew of rats from destroying their beach and preventing a big rock n' roll concert. Featuring music from the Beach Boys, this radical adventure is cleans up the streets and hits the beach!</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Camp California (US)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19930101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>ICOM Simulations</developer>
    <publisher>Turbo Technologies</publisher>
    <genre>Platform</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Cardangels (Japan).cue</path>
    <name>Cardangels</name>
    <desc>It&amp;#xB4;s a card game from Fujicom named Cardangels. In this PC-ENGINE game, you can choose among 4 different kinds of card games: Poker, Black Jack, Babanuki and Speed.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Cardangels (Japan)-image.jpg</image>
    <developer>Fujicom</developer>
    <publisher>Fujicom</publisher>
    <genre/>
    <players/>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Chou Aniki (NTSC-J) [NSCD2013].cue</path>
    <name>Cho Aniki</name>
    <desc>Bo Emperor Bill, the man who achieved ten consecutive victories in the Great Galaxy Bodybuilding contest, faces an ever decreasing supply of protein. He unilaterally invades neighboring star systems, in order to establish protein factories to replenish his supply. Feeling threatened, the heaven realm sent Idaten and Benten to vanquish Bo Emperor Bill. Thus the sweaty hot battle between the muscle brothers and Builders Army begins.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Chou Aniki (NTSC-J) [NSCD2013]-image.png</image>
    <rating>0.7</rating>
    <releasedate>19951225T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Masaya</developer>
    <publisher>Nippon Computer Systems Corp.</publisher>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Color Wars (NTSC-J) [CJCD2002].cue</path>
    <name>Color Wars</name>
    <desc>Color Wars is a puzzle game in which up to four players try to win by putting colored balls on poles, converting adjacent balls to their color. Each stage consists of a rotatable 3D screen containing a number of poles of the same height. Players take turns in placing balls onto these poles. Adjacent balls (horizontally, vertically, or diagonally) can be "captured" and hence change their color. Points are awarded per ball of each color. The round ends when there is no more place on the poles to put balls onto, and the player with the most points wins.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Color Wars (NTSC-J) [CJCD2002]-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19921007T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Tomcat System</developer>
    <publisher>Japan Entertainment Co., Ltd.</publisher>
    <genre/>
    <players/>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Cosmic Fantasy II [U][CD][WTG990301][Telenet Japan][1992][PCE][thx-1138-darkwater].cue</path>
    <name>Cosmic Fantasy 2</name>
    <desc>Turn your imagination over to a Cosmic Fantasy of epic proportions! Laura has been kidnapped, and you must reach her before it's too late! Cut a swath of destruction through the throng of monsters blocking the path to Galam's hideout to save her. Along the way, make friends, solve puzzles, and learn magic while incing your way toward a confrontation that will shake the cosmos! Interactive fantasy role playing takes on a whole new dimension with the addition of animated intermissions that will get you involved in the story! And what's more, the true RPG-style combat interface will put you right in the action. What are you waiting for?</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Cosmic Fantasy II [U][CD][WTG990301][Telenet Japan][1992][PCE][thx-1138-darkwater]-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>1</rating>
    <releasedate>19920901T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Telnet Japan Co. LTD</developer>
    <publisher>Working Designs</publisher>
    <genre>Role-Playing</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Cotton - Fantastic Night Dreams [U][SCD][TGXCD1038][Success][1993][PCE][thx-1138-darkwater].cue</path>
    <name>Cotton: Fantastic Night Dreams</name>
    <desc>The young witch Cotton sets out on her magical broom on a quest to get her favorite candy. Fortunately for us her obsession gets her in the way of several world-threatening terrors that she must destroy in standard shooter fare.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Cotton - Fantastic Night Dreams [U][SCD][TGXCD1038][Success][1993][PCE][thx-1138-darkwater]-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>1</rating>
    <releasedate>19930101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Hudson Soft</developer>
    <publisher>Success</publisher>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Daisenpuu Custom (NTSC-J) [NAPR-1019].cue</path>
    <name>Daisenpu Custom</name>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Daisenpuu Custom (NTSC-J) [NAPR-1019]-image.png</image>
    <developer/>
    <publisher/>
    <genre/>
    <players/>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Dekoboko Densetsu - Hashiru Wagamanma (NTSC-J) [TJCD0013].cue</path>
    <name>Dekoboko Densetsu - Hashiru Wagamanma</name>
    <desc>This cute overhead racing game allows you to play with up to 5 players all at once (using the multi-tap). The object is to race up the varied, auto-scrolling courses, avoiding all manner of weird objects like dung beetles, naked bathing girlies, giant robots, Rambo clones...you get the idea. At the end of each race points are awarded for your finishing position and these can be spent on upgrading your car with a choice of weapons to use against your opponents.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Dekoboko Densetsu - Hashiru Wagamanma (NTSC-J) [TJCD0013]-image.png</image>
    <developer/>
    <publisher/>
    <genre/>
    <players/>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Doraemon - Nobita no Dorabian Night (NTSC-J) [HCD2030].cue</path>
    <name>Doraemon: Nobita no Dorabian Nights</name>
    <desc>Doraemon and Nobita were using special shoes that allows them to jump into the worlds of the books that they want. Nobita let Shizuka use those shoes to enter the world of the book that she wants. Shizuka got lost in one Nobita's Sinbad Legend of the Seven Seas book. After Nobita's mother burned all of his books, Doraemon and the others must find another way to save Shizuka.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Doraemon - Nobita no Dorabian Night (NTSC-J) [HCD2030]-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19911206T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Hudson</developer>
    <publisher>Hudson</publisher>
    <genre>Platform</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Double Dragon II - The Revenge (Japan).cue</path>
    <name>Double Dragon II: The Revenge</name>
    <desc>In the year 2000,  A nuclear strike has left New York City in disaster and law and order have taken a backseat to crime and violence.  One of the most powerful crime syndicate in New York is called the Gen-Satsu-Ken, a mysterious organization led by a mysterious warrior who is a master in a wicked style of Kung Fu.  However two young men named Billy and Jimmy, masters of a martial art called the Sou-Setsu-Ken, were brave enough to challenge them.  One day, during a Gen-Satsu-Ken attack, Billy's girlfriend, Marian, is murdered by the Gen-Satsu-Ken. Billy and Jimmy swore revenge by taking down the Gen-Satsu-Ken once and for all.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Double Dragon II - The Revenge (Japan)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19930312T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Naxat Soft</developer>
    <publisher>Naxat Soft</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Download 2 (NTSC-J) [NAPR-1018].cue</path>
    <name>DOWNLOAD 2</name>
    <desc>Shoot 'em up sequel that takes place over a series of very different and sometimes surreal landscapes.

Cheats/tips: CONFIG MODE: On the title screen push SELECT, I, II, I, II, I, II, I, II, I, II, SELECT
ALTERNATE GRAPHICS: From config mode, go to the DEMO section and watch the ending (9?). When the NEC Avenue logo appears, press UP, SELECT, II then RUN. When the game starts you should see the enemy and some background object replaced by slightly silly things (look out for Ultraman).</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Download 2 (NTSC-J) [NAPR-1018]-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0.5</rating>
    <releasedate>19910329T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>nec adventure</developer>
    <publisher/>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <players/>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./DragonBall Z - Idainaru Son Gokuu Densetsu (NTSC-J) [BNCD4001].cue</path>
    <name>Dragon Ball Z: Idainaru Son Goku Densetsu</name>
    <desc>Join Gohan as he shares with Goten the battles of their deceased father, Goku, along with other characters. Dragon Ball Z: Idainaru Son Goku Densetsu illustrates Goku's seven greatest battles: fighting Mercenary Tao, challenging Tien Shinhan at the World Martial Arts Tournament, destroying King Piccolo, fighting Piccolo at the 23rd World Martial Arts Tournament, protecting Earth from Vegeta, saving Namek from Frieza, and sacrificing his life to save the world from Perfect Cell.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/DragonBall Z - Idainaru Son Gokuu Densetsu (NTSC-J) [BNCD4001]-image.png</image>
    <rating>0.3</rating>
    <releasedate>19941111T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Bec</developer>
    <publisher>Bandai</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Dragon Slayer - The Legend of Heroes [U][SCD][TGXCD1029][Falcom][1992][PCE][thx-1138-darkwater].cue</path>
    <name>Dragon Slayer: The Legend of Heroes</name>
    <desc>In this epic role-playing game, you must guide Prince Logan all accross the beautiful and dngerious world of Isrenasa in the quest to regain his throne. This game features a huge world to explore and many companions to join you on your journey. This game features one of the largest quests and most advanced interface of any role-playing game for the TurboDuo system.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Dragon Slayer - The Legend of Heroes [U][SCD][TGXCD1029][Falcom][1992][PCE][thx-1138-darkwater]-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19911201T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Nihon Falcom</developer>
    <publisher>Turbo Technologies, Inc.</publisher>
    <genre>Role-Playing</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Dungeon Explorer II [U][SCD][TGXCD1034][Hudson Soft][1993][PCE][thx-1138-darkwater].cue</path>
    <name>Dungeon Explorer II</name>
    <desc>This CD sequel to Dungeon Explorer plays exactly the same as the first game. You chose your character from a variety of fantasy stereotypes and set forth in a Gauntlet-esque adventure. The CD format allows a greater quantity and variety of levels to compliment the storyline, with new areas and characters becoming open to you as you progress.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Dungeon Explorer II [U][SCD][TGXCD1034][Hudson Soft][1993][PCE][thx-1138-darkwater]-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19930326T000000</releasedate>
    <developer/>
    <publisher/>
    <genre/>
    <players>4+</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Dungeon Master - Theron's Quest [U][SCD][TGXCD1041][FTL Games][1993][PCE][xeno-nec archives].cue</path>
    <name>Dungeon Master: Theron's Quest</name>
    <desc>Terrifyingly brutal beasts! Monstrous mazes! Treacherous pits of evil! The adventure of a lifetime is here....Theron's Quest!!

The Monastery at Ya-Brodin has fallen to the Cult of Deaths and the Brotherhood of Enlightenment, the true keepers of Magic, have been slaughtered. The Seven Great Treasures now lie in the hands of foul beings who will stop at nothing to hold onto their massive powers. But Theron, with a courage beyond belief, has decided to seek out the Cult of Deaths and win back the Treasures. If he succeeds, he will become a High Lord. If not, the land will see eternal darkness.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Dungeon Master - Theron's Quest [U][SCD][TGXCD1041][FTL Games][1993][PCE][xeno-nec archives]-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19930101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Victor Entertainment, Inc.</developer>
    <publisher>Turbo Technologies, Inc.</publisher>
    <genre>Role-Playing</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Dynastic Hero [U][SCD][TGXCD1053][Westone][1993][PCE][rigg].cue</path>
    <name>Dynastic Hero</name>
    <desc>The land of Tarron is under siege and you must save it from the wicked Drillkor Empire. A beautiful guide will help you along the way as only you, The Dynastic Hero, can deliver the goods!</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Dynastic Hero [U][SCD][TGXCD1053][Westone][1993][PCE][rigg]-image.png</image>
    <rating>0.7</rating>
    <releasedate>19940520T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Hudson</developer>
    <publisher>Hudson</publisher>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Exile [U][CD][WTG990101][Telenet Japan][1992][PCE][thx-1138-darkwater].cue</path>
    <name>Exile</name>
    <desc>Become Sadler the desert warrior as he travels the known world in search of the precious Holimax!  Join forces with Rumi, Kindi, and Fakhyle to piece together the puzzle that will allow you to find the Holimax and use it to overthrow the ruthless Klispin Crusaders!  But keep your cool!  In this quest, you&amp;#x2019;ll have to jump through haunted forests, plan a jailbreak, slink thought creepy towers, and defeat terrifying monsters if you&amp;#x2019;re going to get anywhere!  Hurry!  There is only one Holimax, and the enemy forces are closing in!</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Exile [U][CD][WTG990101][Telenet Japan][1992][PCE][thx-1138-darkwater]-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0.9</rating>
    <releasedate>19910329T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Telenet Japan</developer>
    <publisher>Working Designs</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Exile II - Wicked Phenomenon [U][SCD][WTG990102][Telenet Japan][1993][PCE][xeno-nec archives].cue</path>
    <name>Exile: Wicked Phenomenon</name>
    <desc>The Age of Chaos is upon the Chaltar world! The source of this chaos is rumored to be at the heart of an ancient tower. Join Sadler, Rumi, Kindi, and Fakhyle as they begin a new quest: To learn the secret of the ancient tower and stop the madness spreading over the land. Choose from five different characters as you hack, slash, and bash your way through foreign lands, putrid pyramids, and deadly dungeons while enjoying intense cinema sequences along the way. Will Sadler be able to unlock the secret of the ancient tower and stop the insanity that is spreading throughout the land? Only you can decide that as you guide Sadler through this heart-stopping Action/RPG!</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Exile II - Wicked Phenomenon [U][SCD][WTG990102][Telenet Japan][1993][PCE][xeno-nec archives]-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19930101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Alfa System / Telnet Japan</developer>
    <publisher>Working Designs</publisher>
    <genre>Role-Playing</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./F1 Circus Special - Pole to Win (Japan) (FAAT, FACT).cue</path>
    <name>F1 Circus Special - Pole To Win</name>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <developer/>
    <publisher/>
    <genre/>
    <players/>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Garou Densetsu 2 - Aratanaru Tatakai (Japan) (FABT, FAET, FAFT).cue</path>
    <name>Fatal Fury 2</name>
    <desc>Ambitious conversion of the famed Neo Geo fighting game.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Garou Densetsu 2 - Aratanaru Tatakai (Japan) (FABT, FAET, FAFT)-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <releasedate>19940312T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>HUDSON SOFT / SNK</developer>
    <publisher/>
    <genre>Fighting</genre>
    <players>2</players>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181128T221507</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Garou Densetsu Special (Japan) (FABT).cue</path>
    <name>Fatal Fury Special</name>
    <desc>Fatal Fury Special is an improved version of SNK's 2D one-on-one fighter Fatal Fury 2. The objective is to win the tournament by defeating all other fighters including end boss Wolfgang Krauser. Fatal Fury Special features a fairly large selection of fighters that includes: 
The eight regular fighters from Fatal Fury 2: Terry Bogard, Andy Bogard, Joe Higashi, Kim Kaphwan, Jubei Yamada, Cheng Sinzan, Mai Shiranui and Big Bear. 
The four bosses from Fatal Fury 2: Billy Kane, Axel Hawk, Lawrence Blood and Wolfgang Krauser (this time they're all immediately playable). 
Three characters returning from the first Fatal Fury: Duck King, Tung Fu Rue and Geese Howard (the end boss from Fatal Fury).</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Garou Densetsu Special (Japan) (FABT)-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <developer/>
    <publisher/>
    <genre/>
    <players/>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181128T221523</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Faussete Amour (NTSC-J) [NXCD2017].cue</path>
    <name>Fausett&amp;#xE9; amour</name>
    <desc>This is the adventures of Koruku Ransu, a young blue-haired warrior. The evil lord Goat Bone has kidnaped her beloved sister and also controls the minds of most of her best friends. Koruku wears a strong pink armor  Through seven long stages, one of Kokuru's friend awaits at the end of each one of them - however, she will have to defeat their dark side first and free their controlled minds.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Faussete Amour (NTSC-J) [NXCD2017]-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19930326T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>AIM</developer>
    <publisher>Naxat Soft</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Final Zone II [U][CD][TGXCD1008][Telenet Japan][1990][PCE].cue</path>
    <name>Final Zone II</name>
    <desc>You swore bloody vengence when ZOD blew your satellite crew to shreds. Now it's payback time! Your New Age Power Suits turn each member of your elite force into a walking arsenal of destruction, each with it's own awesome fighting power. But you're just five against a renegade weapons society responsible for killing billions! Choose the fighter best armed to face ZOD's devastating forces in each level of combat as you fight battle after furious battle for the final zone!</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Final Zone II [U][CD][TGXCD1008][Telenet Japan][1990][PCE]-image.png</image>
    <releasedate>19900323T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Telenet Japan</developer>
    <publisher>NEC</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Flash Hiders (NTSC-J) [RSCD3004].cue</path>
    <name>Flash Hiders</name>
    <desc>A martial artist from the Wallace tribe named Bang Bipot and a temperamental sorceress named Tiria Rossette are on a trek across the world. The duo runs across and all but adopts Erue, an emotionally fragile young man somehow connected to an assortment of thugs, bounty hunters, and stranger things.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Flash Hiders (NTSC-J) [RSCD3004]-image.png</image>
    <releasedate>19931219T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>RIGHT STUFF</developer>
    <publisher>RIGHT STUFF</publisher>
    <genre>Fighting</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Forgotten Worlds [U][SCD][TGXCD1030][Capcom][1992][PCE][aguichor].cue</path>
    <name>Forgotten Worlds</name>
    <desc>The Turbografx-16 version of the arcade smash.

It was released as a Super CD-ROM&amp;#xB2; title which supported a specialized 3-button controller that NEC released only in Japan. An American version for the TurboGrafx 16 was released by Turbo Technologies Inc. as well. With the 3-button controller, the player can control their character as they would in the Mega Drive version, with two buttons to rotate the character and one to shoot. 

With the standard TurboGrafx-16 controller, the Run button is used in the place of the third button to rotate the character to the left. The TurboGrafx-16 is one-player only, but allows the player to select between either of the two Unknown Soldiers at the start of the game (with their respective abilities from the arcade version retained).</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Forgotten Worlds [U][SCD][TGXCD1030][Capcom][1992][PCE][aguichor]-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19920327T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>NEC</developer>
    <publisher>NEC</publisher>
    <genre/>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Formation Soccer '95 - Della Serie A (1995) (Human Entertainment) (J).cue</path>
    <name>Formation Soccer '95</name>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <releasedate>19941223T000000</releasedate>
    <developer/>
    <publisher/>
    <genre>Sports</genre>
    <players/>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./In Magical Adventure - Fray CD - Xak Gaiden (Japan).cue</path>
    <name>Fray CD: Xak Gaiden</name>
    <desc>Fray is a young girl whom Latok has saved during the events of Xak. Fray falls in love with Latok and decides to prove him that she can be more than just a damsel in distress. She studies magic in a university for three years and afterwards begins a long journey to find Latok and to help him in his battle against evil.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/In Magical Adventure - Fray CD - Xak Gaiden (Japan)-image.png</image>
    <releasedate>19940330T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Micro Cabin</developer>
    <publisher>Micro Cabin</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Gain Ground SX (NTSC-J) [NAPR-1032].cue</path>
    <name>Gain Ground SX</name>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Gain Ground SX (NTSC-J) [NAPR-1032]-image.jpg</image>
    <developer/>
    <publisher/>
    <genre/>
    <players/>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Galaxy Keiji Gayvan (NTSC-J) [IGCD3005].cue</path>
    <name>Galaxy Keiji Gayvan</name>
    <desc>A side-scrolling beat'em up, supports 2-players. There the main game and also a versus mode where you can also select the bad guys to fight with. The main game is a beat'em up with only one layer, meaning you can't walk up and down like other games of the genre. That makes the game surprisingly very challenging. You have special moves you can execute with combination of the D-pad+buttons and even let armor appear around you, which slowly drains its own energy away. The sprites are very well animated, a must get.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Galaxy Keiji Gayvan (NTSC-J) [IGCD3005]-image.png</image>
    <developer/>
    <publisher/>
    <genre/>
    <players/>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181128T224755</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Genocide (NTSC-J) [BRCD2003].cue</path>
    <name>Genocide</name>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Genocide (NTSC-J) [BRCD2003]-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19920625T000000</releasedate>
    <developer/>
    <publisher/>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <players/>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Ginga Fukei Densetsu - Sapphire (NTSC-J) [HCD5080].cue</path>
    <name>Ginga Fukei Densetsu Sapphire</name>
    <desc>Join the four girls pilots part of a futuristic police unit called the Burning Rabbits. Their duty is to go after bandits, to explore the far corners of the universe and to even venture back in time, whatever the risks, to prosecute the worst criminals. Because humanity is now advanced enough to travel through time, this special police force was created to protect society from these new "time criminals". You have four spaceships, to choose from. Each one balances out the next and usually trades off fire power for maneuverability and speed.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Ginga Fukei Densetsu - Sapphire (NTSC-J) [HCD5080]-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0.5</rating>
    <releasedate>19951124T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>CAProduction</developer>
    <publisher>Hudson Soft</publisher>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Godzilla [U][SCD][TGXCD1051][Toho][1993][PCE].cue</path>
    <name>Godzilla</name>
    <desc>The great Godzilla battles his famous arch-enemies in this one-on-one fight to the finish. It's a 16-beast brawl in Japan, and the master of mayhem himself is the main fighting force -- Godzilla is back, he's bad, and he's mad!</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Godzilla [U][SCD][TGXCD1051][Toho][1993][PCE]-image.png</image>
    <rating>0.7</rating>
    <releasedate>19930226T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Alfa System</developer>
    <publisher>Hudson</publisher>
    <genre>Fighting</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Golden Axe (Japan).cue</path>
    <name>Golden Axe</name>
    <desc>One of Sega's classic arcade titles, Golden Axe features three fantasy characters on their quest to destroy the evil Death Adder. At the beginning of the game you get to choose from the dwarf Gilius Thunderhead, the woman Tyris Flare and the man Ax Battler. The game itself is a scrolling beat 'em up with the player having to defeat waves of enemies as you progress. There are also a few creatures you can mount, such as dragons and the chicken-leg from Altered Beast which has a nice tail-whip attack to keep the bad guys at bay. At various points (and between each level) you will encounter tiny little humanoids dressed in blue or green - the green ones drop food to increase your health bars, the blue ones drop magic potions (although you have to put the boot in to get anything from them). Each character is able to cast magic spells, and the more potions you have, the more impressive and powerful the spells are. Gilius casts lightning spells, which are the weakest, Ax casts earthquake spells and Tyris casts powerful fire spells which can be powered up to give you a giant dragon that breathes flames all over the landscape.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Golden Axe (Japan)-image.png</image>
    <developer/>
    <publisher/>
    <genre>Fighting</genre>
    <players/>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./GoTzenDiener (NTSC-J) [HECD4014].cue</path>
    <name>Gotzendiener</name>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/GoTzenDiener (NTSC-J) [HECD4014]-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19941125T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Gainax</developer>
    <publisher>NEC</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Gradius II - Gofer no Yabou (Japan).cue</path>
    <name>Gradius II: Gofer no Yabou</name>
    <desc>Two years after its last epic battle, the GRADIUS army recommissions the VIC VIPER superdimensional warplane to combat the invasion of a new nemesis known as GOFER. Piloting the latest model of the VIC VIPER, players can select between multiple WEAPON MODULES and SHIELDS to tackle the varying stages and enemy attack patterns they come up against. With a total of nine stages, this perfect port of the original boasts one of the longest adventures in the series and features more of its trademark fast-paced background music to accompany the intense action!</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Gradius II - Gofer no Yabou (Japan)-image.png</image>
    <rating>0.5</rating>
    <releasedate>19921218T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Konami</developer>
    <publisher>Konami</publisher>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Gulclight TDF 2 (Japan) (Rev 2).cue</path>
    <name>GulcLight TDF 2</name>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_media/tg-cd/screenshots/Gulclight TDF 2 (Japan) (Rev 2).png</image>
    <marquee>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_media/tg-cd/marquees/Gulclight TDF 2 (Japan) (Rev 2).png</marquee>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <developer/>
    <publisher/>
    <genre/>
    <players/>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Hawk F-123 (NTSC-J) [PVCD-0007].cue</path>
    <name>Hawk F-123</name>
    <desc>Horizontal shoot 'em up similar in style to Power Gate, although technically more advanced.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Hawk F-123 (NTSC-J) [PVCD-0007]-image.jpg</image>
    <developer/>
    <publisher/>
    <genre/>
    <players/>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Hellfire S - The Another Story (NTSC-J) [NAPR-1017].cue</path>
    <name>Hellfire S</name>
    <desc>Hellfire S is a Shoot-'Em-Up game, developed by Bits Laboratory and published by NEC International, which was released in Japan in 1991.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Hellfire S - The Another Story (NTSC-J) [NAPR-1017]-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19910412T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Bits Laboratory</developer>
    <publisher>NEC International</publisher>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Horror Story (NTSC-J) [NAPR-1027].cue</path>
    <name>Horror Story</name>
    <desc>Demon's World, released in Japan as Horror Story (&amp;#x30DB;&amp;#x30E9;&amp;#x30FC;&amp;#x30B9;&amp;#x30C8;&amp;#x30FC;&amp;#x30EA;&amp;#x30FC;?), is a platformer arcade game that was developed by Toaplan and published by Taito in 1989. This game is multi-regional, meaning that it can be configured for different regions via the DIP switches. These settings change the legal warnings, can display the Taito licensing message and can change the title between the English version (Demon's World) and the Japanese version (Horror Story).</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Horror Story (NTSC-J) [NAPR-1027]-image.jpg</image>
    <developer>Taoplan</developer>
    <publisher>Taito</publisher>
    <genre>Platform</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Hu PGA Tour - PowerGolf 2 - Golfer (Japan).cue</path>
    <name>Hu PGA Tour - Powergolf 2 - Golfer</name>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <releasedate>19900824T000000</releasedate>
    <developer/>
    <publisher/>
    <genre/>
    <players/>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181128T221935</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Human Sports Festival (Japan) (Rev 3).cue</path>
    <name>Human Sports Festival</name>
    <desc>Sports compilation featuring Formation Soccer, Final Match Tennis and Fine Shot Golf.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Human Sports Festival (Japan) (Rev 3)-image.jpg</image>
    <developer>Human</developer>
    <publisher>Human</publisher>
    <genre/>
    <players/>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Hyper Dyne SideArms Special (NTSC-J) [HACD9002].cue</path>
    <name>Hyper Dyne: SideArms Special</name>
    <desc>Hyper Dyne Side Arms Special is an Action game, developed by Capcom and published by NEC Interchannel, which was released in Japan in 1989.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Hyper Dyne SideArms Special (NTSC-J) [HACD9002]-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19891215T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Capcom</developer>
    <publisher>NEC Interchannel</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <players/>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Iga Ninden Gaiou (NTSC-J) [NBCD3003].cue</path>
    <name>Iga Ninden Gaiou</name>
    <desc>A Ninja Gaiden-esque action adventure</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Iga Ninden Gaiou (NTSC-J) [NBCD3003]-image.png</image>
    <developer/>
    <publisher>Nichibutsu</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./ImageFight II - Operation Deepstriker (Japan).cue</path>
    <name>Image Fight II - Operation Deepstriker</name>
    <desc>Image Fight II Operation Deepstriker is a vertical shooter by Irem and sequel of the arcade game Image Fight originally released in 1988 (and ported to the PC Engine in 1990). Humanity tries to rebuild itself from the aftermath of the first Image Fight - the computer on the moon was destroyed and peace had finally returned. But three years after the attack, a space probe detects unknown objects hurtling towards planet Earth. The signs are clear - a massive alien invasion is underway. After a first encounter around Saturn, Image Fight requires the player to progress through four "simulation stages" - the last six "real stages" can only be accessed if the "simulation" achievement rating is greater enough. Failing this requirements leads to a short but intense Penalty Area. All the primary weapons from the original game are also here for the taking. Up to three colored orbs can be attached to the ship and either fire forwards (blue) or in the opposite way the ship is moving (Red). Secondary devices are also available and can be equipped at the front of the ship - they include all kind of lasers and missiles. However the only way to switch to a different device is to receive a direct hit.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/ImageFight II - Operation Deepstriker (Japan)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19921218T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Irem</developer>
    <publisher>Irem</publisher>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <players/>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Implode (NTSC-U) [BTCD0201].cue</path>
    <name>Implode</name>
    <desc>Implode is a homebrew puzzle game. It plays like a falling block puzzle in all respects, with the exception of the fact that the blocks appear from below instead of falling. All the blocks have the same shape and are only distinguished by their color. The player must selects groups of three or more identically colored blocks in order to make them disappear. The goal is to not let the blocks stack up and pass the upper border of the screen. Bombs would sometimes appear and clear out adjacent blocks if the player selects them. The game gradually advances to higher difficulty levels, with more colors and faster speed.

Also included on the CD are two games previously only released in downloadable emulation format: Crash and Humpball. The first is a single-screen overhead arcade racing game. Two cars race automatically on a maze-like screen in circular movement. Players must press directional buttons to switch between the tracks. The goal is to move over all the dots scattered in the stage while avoiding crashing into the other car.

Humpball can be described as a cross between Pong and a volleyball game. Two hump-like creatures are positioning on either side of a pole, tossing a ball towards the opponent's side by moving to the sides and jumping. The goal is to make the ball touch the opponent's floor, which results in scoring a point. Power-ups that move the pole to left or right, change the speed of the ball, gravity rules, etc., appear randomly and are activated when touched by the ball.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Implode (NTSC-U) [BTCD0201]-image.jpg</image>
    <developer>MindRec</developer>
    <publisher>MindRec</publisher>
    <genre>Puzzle</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./It Came from the Desert [U][CD][TGXCD1010][Cinemaware][1992][PCE].cue</path>
    <name>It Came From The Desert</name>
    <desc>It Came from the Desert is a remake of the the original 1989 Amiga game of the same name, but with a vast amount of changes and improvements. The basic setting was kept identical. It is a mix of action and adventure elements, largely inspired from cult-horror B-Movies of the 50's and 60's, and the 1954 film Them in particular. The player plays the part of Dr. Greg Bradley, a geologist and the newest resident in town. Eager to satisfy his scientific mind, Bradley sets out to examine the crash-site of a mysterious meteor, but what he finds is not at all what he had been looking for.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/It Came from the Desert [U][CD][TGXCD1010][Cinemaware][1992][PCE]-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19910101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Cinemaware</developer>
    <publisher>Cinemaware</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./J. League Tremendous Soccer '94 (Japan).cue</path>
    <name>J. League Tremendous Soccer '94</name>
    <desc>Tremendous Soccer '94 is a soccer (football) game with licensed players and teams of the Japanese soccer league (J.League). There are five modes in the game: Pre-Season (a single game between two teams in the league), Championship (a season mode), Cup (the Japanese football cup with elimination rounds), All-Star (West and East teams compete in a match), and PK Battle (penalty kicks between teams). The player can regulate the strength of the computer AI and the length of a game, as well as substitute players and change tactical formations. The gameplay is similar to other top-down football games of the time, with simple controls and automatic moves performed by players depending on the situation.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/J. League Tremendous Soccer '94 (Japan)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19941223T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>HuneX Co., Ltd.</developer>
    <publisher>NEC Home Electronics, Ltd.</publisher>
    <genre>Sports</genre>
    <players/>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./J. B. Harold Murder Club [U][CD][TGXCD1012][Riverhill Soft][1991][PCE].cue</path>
    <name>J.B. Harold Murder Club</name>
    <desc>A horrible murder has taken place in the sleepy little town of Liberty. Bill Robbins, a wealthy man known for his wild womanizing ways is the victim and, list of possible suspects keeps growing. As J.B. Harold you must figure out the who, what, where and why of the case. To solve the mystery you will need to travel to various locations, interview people and search for clues.

The game is laid out over a grid map that displays various locations, though other than that, the game is mainly presented in the form of still photos.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/J. B. Harold Murder Club [U][CD][TGXCD1012][Riverhill Soft][1991][PCE]-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19910101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Riverhillsoft</developer>
    <publisher>Hudson</publisher>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Jack Nicklaus Turbo Golf (1990) (Victor Music Entertainment) (US).cue</path>
    <name>Jack Nicklaus Turbo Golf</name>
    <desc>"I designed my golf game with one goal in mind-to create the most realistic simulation of championship golf in the world. Tee to green, it offers the most breathtaking scenery available. And I've made sure that there's variety and challenge built into every hole. It's my kind of golf-uncompromising. And I know you'll enjoy it as much as I do."</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Jack Nicklaus Turbo Golf (1990) (Victor Music Entertainment) (US)-image.jpg</image>
    <developer/>
    <publisher/>
    <genre/>
    <players/>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./John Madden Duo CD Football (1993) (NEC Solutions) (U).cue</path>
    <name>John Madden Duo CD Football</name>
    <desc>Huddle up sports fans. John Madden comes alive with Duo CD Football.

TTI gives you the latest in full-motion video technology, so real you won't need to watch the pros again. Get right into the action with shoe-string catches, side stepping jukes and high-flying tackles. All your favorite Madden action is included plus so much more with the miracle media of CD.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/John Madden Duo CD Football (1993) (NEC Solutions) (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19930101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer/>
    <publisher>Hudson</publisher>
    <genre>Sports</genre>
    <players/>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Kaizou Choujin Shubibinman 3 - Ikai no Princess (NTSC-J) [NSCD2010].cue</path>
    <name>Kaizou Choujin Shubibinman 3: Ikai no Princess</name>
    <desc>Tasuke and Kyapiko are spending a nice relaxing day at the beach, when suddenly a huge spaceship appears overhead! This can only mean one thing... another invasion! Tasuke and Kyapiko suit up and set out to stop it... or is it all just a gross misunderstanding?</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Kaizou Choujin Shubibinman 3 - Ikai no Princess (NTSC-J) [NSCD2010]-image.png</image>
    <rating>0.5</rating>
    <releasedate>19920228T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Masaya</developer>
    <publisher>NCS</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Kakutou Haou Densetsu Algunos (NTSC-J) [IGCD3007].cue</path>
    <name>Kakutou Haou Densetsu Algunos</name>
    <desc>The world's greatest warriors, Jenius, Asasin, Arcer, Samohan, Greeze, Orga, Lobo, Blocken, Jyobei and Daibuster. Every single one of them has different attacks and set of techniques the player has to learn and master. Most of the fighters in Algunos use their bare hands but some also use weapons. Choose your fighter and take on the challenge.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Kakutou Haou Densetsu Algunos (NTSC-J) [IGCD3007]-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19940128T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>INTEC</developer>
    <publisher>FILL IN CAFE</publisher>
    <genre>Fighting</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Kaze Kiri - Ninja Action (NTSC-J) [NXCD3025].cue</path>
    <name>Kaze Kiri: Ninja Action</name>
    <desc>Kaze Kiri takes place in Feudal Japan where the kingdom princess Shizuhime is abducted by a group of mysterious ninjas. A feared swordsman called Kaze Kiri, hero of the game, is given the task to rescue the poor girl and restore order. Our ninja can can use a broad variety of fightings skills - he can run, jump, dash and slash without mercy anyone who gets in his way.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Kaze Kiri - Ninja Action (NTSC-J) [NXCD3025]-image.png</image>
    <releasedate>19940428T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Naxat Soft</developer>
    <publisher>Naxat Soft</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Kiaidan 00 (NTSC-J) [TJCD2031].cue</path>
    <name>Kiaidan 00</name>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Kiaidan 00 (NTSC-J) [TJCD2031]-image.png</image>
    <developer/>
    <publisher/>
    <genre/>
    <players/>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./L-Dis (NTSC-J) [NSCD0005].cue</path>
    <name>L-Dis</name>
    <desc>L-Dis is an Action game, developed by Dual and published by NCS, which was released in Japan in 1991.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/L-Dis (NTSC-J) [NSCD0005]-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19910405T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Dual</developer>
    <publisher>NCS</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <players/>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Last Alert [U][CD][TGXCD1007][Telenet Japan][1990][PCE].cue</path>
    <name>Last Alert</name>
    <desc>Only a relentless commando assault can stop this international arms syndicate's threat to humanity. That's why we picked you. You'll need rocket launchers. hyper pineapples, and super napalm to blast through their high tech fortress... past tank brigades, bazookas, and then far into space. Confront the renegade military lunatic sworn to your destruction. Listen up for your orders, Commando. You'll be facing one suicide mission after another along the way. It'll make a great story... if you live to tell it!</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Last Alert [U][CD][TGXCD1007][Telenet Japan][1990][PCE]-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19900101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Telenet Japan</developer>
    <publisher>NEC Interchannel</publisher>
    <genre/>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Hihou Densetsu - Chris no Bouken (NTSC-J) [PVCD-1004].cue</path>
    <name>Legendary Treasure: Chris's Adventure</name>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <releasedate>19900330T000000</releasedate>
    <developer/>
    <publisher/>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <players/>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Loom [U][SCD][TGXCD1017][LucasArts][1992][PCE].cue</path>
    <name>Loom</name>
    <desc>Loom is based on a serious and complex fantasy story. With its experimental interface, it eschewed the traditional paradigm of graphical adventures, where puzzles usually involve interactions between the game character, the environment, and multiple items the character can take into their possession. Loom's game-play centers instead around magical four-note tunes (drafts) that the protagonist, Bobbin Threadbare, can play on his distaff. Each draft is a spell that has an effect of a certain type, such as "Opening" or "Night Vision". Drafts can be learned by observing an object that possess the qualities of the relevant draft; for example, examining a blade while it is being sharpened gives the player the "Sharpening" draft.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Loom [U][SCD][TGXCD1017][LucasArts][1992][PCE]-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19920412T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Realtime Associates</developer>
    <publisher>Lucasfilm Games</publisher>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Lords of the Rising Sun (1992) (NEC Solutions) (U).cue</path>
    <name>Lords of the Rising Sun</name>
    <desc>Combat the epic Gempei war of ancient Japan in a game that offers a unique blend of military strategy, engaging action sequences and role-playing games. In a heroic quest to become a Shogun and redeem the honor of the family, players must command vast armies of samurai warriors, defend against ninja assassins, besiege powerful strongholds, negotiate alliances and face enemies in personal combat.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Lords of the Rising Sun (1992) (NEC Solutions) (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19890101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Cinemaware</developer>
    <publisher>Cinemaware</publisher>
    <genre>Strategy</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Lords of Thunder [U][SCD][TGXCD1033][Red][1993][PCE][thx-1138-darkwater].cue</path>
    <name>Lords of Thunder</name>
    <desc>Lords of Thunder is a side-scrolling shooter that has you take on the role of a legendary warrior, blasting enemies to heavy-metal tunes. Your enemies are plotting to revive Zaggart, "The Dark One," who was sealed beneath the six continents of Mistral. It's up to Landis, descendant of the heroic Dyu, to stop them.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Lords of Thunder [U][SCD][TGXCD1033][Red][1993][PCE][thx-1138-darkwater]-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19930101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>RED Entertainment</developer>
    <publisher>Turbo Technologies, Inc.</publisher>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Mad Stalker (J).cue</path>
    <name>Mad Stalker: Full Metal Force</name>
    <desc>2142 A.D. Artemis City. People were about to forget all those disasters. A war ship probably built during the late war time was discovered by the military. There were a few hundred SlaveGears aboard the war ship, and were to be put under the control. Under the intention of the ruling government in power. Two SlaveGears were put under the management of the police for the purpose of experimental use. These two models were named "Hound Dog" and "Rising Dog". The manned test of Hound Dog. The main computer "Omega" of the war ship stored within the premises of military facilities suddenly began operations. "Omega" conducted network access through military channels. Omega froze all functions of Artemis City, and gave a command to the SlaveGear to put the entire city under control. "Exterminate the enemy!" Rising Dog which had not yet been modified for manned use, also had started operations under the command of Omega. The research facilities were destroyed, and one SlaveGear disappeared into the city. The police had recognized the emergency of Artemis, and had begun operations for settlement. "Code name Hound Dog. Alert! Terminate all tests immediately, and join with the forces in the city. Repeating..."</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Mad Stalker (J)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19940915T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Kogado Studio</developer>
    <publisher>NEC Home Electronics</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Metamor Jupiter (J).cue</path>
    <name>Metamor Jupiter</name>
    <desc>Sci-fi shoot 'em up.
The following information was kindly provided by Brandon Sheffield of www.insertcredit.com: Metamor Jupiter represents the first (major, he had one previous collaboration) foray into games by musician/designer Masaya Matsuura, of Parappa the Rapper fame. Matsuura, hot off the disbanding of his pop group PSY'S, wrote a vocal song and some incidental music for the game. As for the game itself, it's a rather standard shooter, but is also notable as an early creation of Flight Plan, the developer that went on to create such notable titles as Summon Night, Black/Matrix, Poison Pink, et al. Definitely worth a go if you're a fan of either Matsuura or Flight Plan, and a decent enough, if merely workmanlike effort otherwise. Try it. 
I actually bought a copy of this game when last I was in Tokyo, and presented it to Matsuura at his office during an informal interview. He was incredibly surprised to see the game, as he'd lost the original copy of the track, and ripped the disc on the spot in order to get it back! Pretty nifty. Honestly though, I only played it for about 30 minutes. It's really quite ok, but is way more interesting for its history than anything else.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Metamor Jupiter (J)-image.jpg</image>
    <developer/>
    <publisher/>
    <genre/>
    <players/>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Meteor Blaster DX (NTSC-U) [BTCD0402].cue</path>
    <name>Meteor Blaster DX</name>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <developer/>
    <publisher/>
    <genre/>
    <players/>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Mugen Senshi Valis - Legend of a Fantasm Soldier (NTSC-J) [TJCD2023].cue</path>
    <name>Mugen Senshi Valis: The Legend of A Fantasm Soldier</name>
    <desc>What would you think if your best friend went on a date with the King of the Dark World - because she thought he was cute?! You'd think she'd been duped - and you'd be right. The fiendish King Rogles stands poised to conquer the other worlds of the universe: the Dream World of Queen Valia, and the Human World. Rogles and his five Dark Lords have taken the force of Yang from Queen Valia and sealed it into a Fantasm Jewel. Only a warrior with a heart perfectly balanced between Yin and Yang can wield the Sword of Valis against the encroaching darkness! 

Yuko, a young student from the Human World, is the chosen one - and you will control her. She is to become the greatest warrior in the universe, never suspecting that her most fearsome battle will not be against a Dark Lord, but against her closest friend from the Human World - the one she warned, "Don't go out with him, he's the Dark..." But before she could finish, her friend ran off into The Darkness.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Mugen Senshi Valis - Legend of a Fantasm Soldier (NTSC-J) [TJCD2023]-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19920319T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Telenet</developer>
    <publisher>Riot</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Nekketsu Koukou Dodgeball Bu - Soccer Hen (NTSC-J) [NXCD1005].cue</path>
    <name>Nekketsu Koukou Dodgeball Bu: CD Soccer Hen</name>
    <desc>While Kunio and Shinichi were practicing dodge ball, soccer manager Misako approached the two on the court. "Please! Instead of dodgeball, join me and play soccer in the national convention!"

Nekketsu High Soccer Club has come down with food poisoning, and Kunio must lead his dodgeball team into the soccer competition and go for the goal! Only through winning the championship can Kunio convince his whole team to join him.

Nekketsu Koukou Dodgeball Bu: CD Soccer Hen presents the classic soccer game with crystal clear sound and high resolution graphics like never before seen in the series!</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Nekketsu Koukou Dodgeball Bu - Soccer Hen (NTSC-J) [NXCD1005]-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19911220T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>KID</developer>
    <publisher>Naxat Soft</publisher>
    <genre>Sports</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Neo Nectaris (J).cue</path>
    <name>Neo Nectaris</name>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Neo Nectaris (J)-image.jpg</image>
    <developer/>
    <publisher/>
    <genre/>
    <players/>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Nexzr (NTSC-J) [NXCD2014].cue</path>
    <name>Nexzr</name>
    <desc>Space based vertically scrolling shoot &amp;#x2018;em up, similar in style to Super Star Solider, but far more challenging.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Nexzr (NTSC-J) [NXCD2014]-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19921211T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Naxat soft</developer>
    <publisher>Naxat Soft</publisher>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Pop'n Magic (NTSC-J) [TJCD2027].cue</path>
    <name>Pop 'n Magic</name>
    <desc>A static screen action game in the style of Bubble Bobble or Don Doko Don, Pop 'n Magic allows you to trap enemies by firing your wand at them, then pick them up and throw them across the screen to destroy them. The bubbles they are trapped in are specific colours and care must be taken not to throw two of the same colour together as this will release the (now quite upset) creatures inside.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Pop'n Magic (NTSC-J) [TJCD2027]-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19920727T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Riot</developer>
    <publisher>Telenet</publisher>
    <genre/>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Prince of Persia [U][SCD][TGXCD1027][Broderbund][1992][PCE][thx-1138-darkwater].cue</path>
    <name>Prince of Persia</name>
    <desc>The Final Count Down of Love and Justice.

Awaiting enemies and constant attacks. Getting through traps here and here and more. The list of tasks continues. Will you be able to find your beloved princess within 60 minutes? Inshaallah-only God knows...</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Prince of Persia [U][SCD][TGXCD1027][Broderbund][1992][PCE][thx-1138-darkwater]-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19911106T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Riverhill Soft</developer>
    <publisher>Hudson</publisher>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./R-Type Complete CD (J).cue</path>
    <name>R-Type Complete CD</name>
    <desc>This CD combines both HuCards into the complete game, as it originally should have been. There are some added visual scenes to justify the CD format, as well as re-arranged music tracks for each level.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/R-Type Complete CD (J)-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0.5</rating>
    <releasedate>19911220T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Irem</developer>
    <publisher/>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Riot Zone (U).cue</path>
    <name>Riot Zone</name>
    <desc>Riot Zone is a side-scrolling fighting game that follows two heroes as they fight to take down an evil organization. The crime syndicate Dragon Zone has kidnapped Hawk's girlfriend and it's up to him and his partner detective, Tony, to get her back. Join them as they jump "fists first" into the grim Kowloon district.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Riot Zone (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19920101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Agenda / Hudson Soft</developer>
    <publisher>Turbo Technologies, Inc.</publisher>
    <genre/>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Road Spirits (J).cue</path>
    <name>Road Spirits</name>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Road Spirits (J)-image.png</image>
    <releasedate>19910322T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>PACK IN VIDEO</developer>
    <publisher/>
    <genre>Racing</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Seirei Senshi Spriggan (NTSC-J) [NXCD1004].cue</path>
    <name>SEIREI SENSHI SPRIGGAN</name>
    <desc>Take on the alien hordes in this vertically scrolling shoot 'em up from the people behind Aleste. The power-up system in Spriggan relies on different coloured globes - you can have three of these in stock at any one time and the order they are in will vary what style of weapon you have. This allows for a certain degree of mix-and-match until you find your preferred combination. You can also eject these orbs, which act as a smart bomb in times of need.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Seirei Senshi Spriggan (NTSC-J) [NXCD1004]-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19910712T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Compile</developer>
    <publisher>Naxat Soft</publisher>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181128T223319</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Shadow of the Beast [U][SCD][TGXCD1018][Psygnosis][1992][PCE][thx-1138-darkwater].cue</path>
    <name>Shadow of the Beast</name>
    <desc>Kidnapped as a child by the evil Beast-Mages, you have been transformed into a creature of fearsome power, agility and strength. In this guise you faithfully serve the Beast and its cohorts for many years as their warrior-messenger. Until one day you discover an awful secret - the truth about your past... a truth that drives you wild with anger and sends you on a trail of bloody revenge against your master. Now the time has come to enter the Shadow of the Beast!

Your task is to fight your way through several different regions in order to reach the heart of the enemy's stronghold, where you will face your ultimate adversary. Along the way you will encounter an awesome array of monsters and traps. Be ruthless, be quick...for only the strongest and toughest can hope to survive.

Prepare to live by your wits, relying on split-second reactions and ingenuity. Combat the diabolical creatures. Dodge the deadly plantlife. Overcome the devious traps. Find and use the long-lost artifacts. Feel the adrenalin pumping as the tension becomes almost unbearable...Prepare to enter the Shadow of the Beast!</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Shadow of the Beast [U][SCD][TGXCD1018][Psygnosis][1992][PCE][thx-1138-darkwater]-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19920101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Psygnosis</developer>
    <publisher>NEC Home Electronics</publisher>
    <genre>Platform</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Shape Shifter [U][SCD][TGXCD1021][ICOM Simulations][1992][PCE][japman].cue</path>
    <name>Shape Shifter</name>
    <desc>Far below the three moons that hang in the midnight sky lies the land of Krelion. And the people of this land live in an age of perfect peace and prosperity known as the Age of Light, a time by a band of powerful wizards known as the Ring of Five. 

But, on the 11th moon of the Age of Light, a dark wave of evil has begun to sweep across the land, leaving a wide path of destructing in its wake. And the Ring of Five, which has protected Krelion for centuries untold has suddenly vanished from the land. Their fate is left in the unholy hands of three evil beings from the shadow realm known as the Dark Ones. 

Now the mid-summer equinox is almost at hand. And with this event, the Dark Ones will shatter the barrier that lies between Krelion and the shadow realm. But there is a single light in the darkness. His name is Lykas and he has the power to change his shape at will. Hopefully, he can save Krelion before it is too late ... before the land is plunged into a dark, eternal nightmare... never to awaken...</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Shape Shifter [U][SCD][TGXCD1021][ICOM Simulations][1992][PCE][japman]-image.png</image>
    <releasedate>19920925T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>ICOM Simulations</developer>
    <publisher>Turbo Technologies, Inc.</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Shin Nihon Pro Wrestling - '94 Battlefield in Tokyo Dome (Japan).cue</path>
    <name>Shin Nihon Pro Wrestling '94: Battlefield in Tokyo Dome</name>
    <desc>A port of the Super Famicom hit, featuring higher quality music, G1 tournament, and bloodshed.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Shin Nihon Pro Wrestling - '94 Battlefield in Tokyo Dome (Japan)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19941125T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Fujicom</developer>
    <publisher>Varie</publisher>
    <genre>Fighting</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Sim Earth - The Living Planet (1993) (NEC Solutions) (U).cue</path>
    <name>Sim Earth - The Living Planet</name>
    <desc>Talk about power! You control a whole planet right from its birth to its last day. That means nursing single-celled life-forms into high-tech civilizations which can blast off to the stars. **Based on James Lovelock's GAIA theory, SimEarth simulates the Earth as one living organism.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Sim Earth - The Living Planet (1993) (NEC Solutions) (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19930502T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Maxis</developer>
    <publisher>Hudson</publisher>
    <genre>Strategy</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Slime World (NTSC-J) [MWCD2005].cue</path>
    <name>Slime World</name>
    <desc>Slime World is a side-scrolling platform game by Epyx and published by Micro World. Captain Todd is on a mission to explore the green and inhospitable underground world of a mysterious Slime Planet and retrieve all the precious Slime Gems hidden in its depths. Our hero has to visit endless caverns and catacombs filled with green and gooey slime. Six stages are available from the start and each one of them is based around upon a particular scheme - from straight arcade action where Todd has to blast as many enemies as possible, to logic action when the player has to use his brain rather than his fire-power. Todd can run, jump, climb walls or use his water-gun to defeat all the various hordes of slimy enemies the game throws at him. More weapons and special items are available, such as bombs, jet pack or shields. When hit, Todd doesn't lose any life but instead turns greener and greener until he dies - unless he can find a water pond and clean himself up.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Slime World (NTSC-J) [MWCD2005]-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19921009T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Epyx</developer>
    <publisher/>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <players/>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Splash Lake (NTSC-U) [TGXCD1025].cue</path>
    <name>Splash Lake</name>
    <desc>Splash Lake is an action-puzzle game for the TurboGrafx-CD and PC Engine CD-ROM. The player is an ostrich named Ozzie and must walk around a grid, pecking at certain lynchpin areas of the ground in order to collapse parts of the level into the ocean. The goal is to remove all enemies by dropping the ground they're walking on. It is structurally similar to Dig Dug 2.

The game has a multiplayer mode, which allows two players to try to outmaneuver and out-think each other.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Splash Lake (NTSC-U) [TGXCD1025]-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0.5</rating>
    <releasedate>19910628T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Bits Laboratory</developer>
    <publisher>Turbo Technologies, Inc.</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Spriggan 2 (J).cue</path>
    <name>Spriggan Mark 2: Re-Terraform Project</name>
    <desc>Spriggan Mark 2: Re-Terraform Project is an Action game, developed by Compile and published by Naxat Soft, which was released in Japan in 1992.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Spriggan 2 (J)-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <releasedate>19920501T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Compile</developer>
    <publisher>Naxat Soft</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <players/>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Super Air Zonk (U).cue</path>
    <name>Super Air Zonk</name>
    <desc>Zonk is back in Super Air Zonk!!

Now moving to a rockabilly beat and able to transform into nine different characters, Zonk lets loose through seven action-packed stages in another battle against his arch nemesis, Sandro Vitch. Power up Zonk with the classic Meat item, eventually turning him into the champion of justice, Ultra Zonk, or the fearsome Tyrano Zonk in the latter stages of the game.
Read More&amp;gt;&amp;gt;

After rescuing his friends from enemies, Zonk can also morph with them to combine powers. Fight enemies with killer tunes belted out from a trusty microphone. Hurl freshly made sushi at them. With its variety of wacky attacks, Super Air Zonk has a sense of humor all its own.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Super Air Zonk (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19930730T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Dual</developer>
    <publisher>Hudson</publisher>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <players/>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Super Darius (J).cue</path>
    <name>Super Darius</name>
    <desc>Super Darius is a 1990 port of Darius for the PC Engine CD-ROM&amp;#xB2;, and the only attempt at an accurate port of the game for many years; it even uses recordings of music and sound effects straight from the PCB! Its other claim to fame is the introduction of all 26 bosses from the original draft for Darius, some of which were earlier seen on promotional material and some of which were used in Darius II instead.

A "light" version for normal PC Engines, Darius Plus, was released later in the year. At the time that was released, owning both versions allowed you to get Darius Alpha.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Super Darius (J)-image.png</image>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <releasedate>19900316T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Taito</developer>
    <publisher>NEC Avenue</publisher>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <players/>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Super Darius 2 (J).cue</path>
    <name>Super Darius II</name>
    <desc>Super Darius II takes place sometime after the first Darius game. The colonized planet Darius is recuperating from its invasion from the alien Belser Army thanks to that game's heroes Proco and Tiat. Darius' inhabitants have since situated themselves on the planet Olga while Darius' societies, architecture and attacked areas were being repaired. The space flight Headquarters established on Olga picks up an SOS signal coming from Earth, where the first colonists originated before colonizing Darius. The signal included the description of alien ships similar to those of the Belser Army. Suspecting that these might be their remaining Earthling ancestors, the people of Darius sends both Proco Jr. and Tiat Young to help them.

The Super CD-ROM version features an entirely new set of bosses, major changes to levels, and a fully arranged soundtrack including new songs.

The game is set in the inner half of the solar system, and has the same branching level structure as Darius.

The red/green/blue powerups from the first game return, and have the same function: respectively, upgrades to the "missile" main weapon and "bomb" subweapon, and a shield to absorb some damage. Two new power-ups were added: a yellow powerup that adds a new "laser" main weapon that functions somewhat similarly to the bombs, and a rainbow powerup that grants one upgrade to all the players weapons.

Actually acquiring these powerups and the upgrade path is completely different from Darius: a formation of a specific enemy must be completely destroyed (and a given formation may not have a powerup), and every single powerup now grants some kind of upgrade. Further, the various weapons upgrade differently, though the shield upgrade the same as before.

Another new feature in Darius II is the appearance of minibosses known as "captains"; large enemies that appear somewhere in the level before the main boss. In Darius II, these are all smaller versions of bosses from the first game, with similar abilities.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Super Darius 2 (J)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>20090217T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Taito</developer>
    <publisher>NEC</publisher>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Super Raiden (J).cue</path>
    <name>Super Raiden</name>
    <desc>A conversion of the classic arcade shoot 'em up, Raiden follows the conventions of the genre with coloured power up pods that give different weapons when collected. 

Raiden is one of the all-time greats in the annals of shoot 'em up history. It&amp;#x2019;s not just the excellent graphics and sounds, but the engaging gameplay that keeps you addicted for ages. It&amp;#x2019;s also capable of throwing up some hair-raising moments, and bullet dodging skills are pushed to the extreme</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Super Raiden (J)-image.jpg</image>
    <developer/>
    <publisher/>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <players/>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Sword Master (J).cue</path>
    <name>Sword Master</name>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <releasedate>19950811T000000</releasedate>
    <developer/>
    <publisher/>
    <genre/>
    <players/>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181128T222423</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./The Addams Family [U][CD][TGXCD1019][ICOM Simulations][1991][PCE][rigg].cue</path>
    <name>The Addams Family</name>
    <desc>The Addams Family Ocean games were preceded by a TurboGrafx-CD gamedeveloped by ICOM Simulations and published by NEC in 1991,[6] though in this version the protagonist is the Addams's lawyer, Tully Alford, despite being an antagonist in the movie. The game also follows the plot of the movie but plays from the perspective of Tully Alford. The player controls Alford through several side-scrolling stages on a quest to locate, and steal, the Addams' vast wealth. Alford's main weapon is his umbrella, which can shoot fireballs, or he can transform into a wolf man.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/The Addams Family [U][CD][TGXCD1019][ICOM Simulations][1991][PCE][rigg]-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19910101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>ICOM Simulations</developer>
    <publisher>NEC</publisher>
    <genre/>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Pro Yakyuu Super, The (Japan) (FABT).cue</path>
    <name>The Pro Yakyuu Super</name>
    <rating>0.7</rating>
    <releasedate>19921010T000000</releasedate>
    <developer/>
    <publisher/>
    <genre/>
    <players/>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Pro Yakyuu Super '94, The (1994) (Intec) (J).cue</path>
    <name>The Pro Yakyuu Super '94</name>
    <rating>0.7</rating>
    <releasedate>19921010T000000</releasedate>
    <developer/>
    <publisher/>
    <genre/>
    <players/>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Valis 3 (NTSC-U) [TGXCD1024].cue</path>
    <name>Valis III</name>
    <desc>King Glames leads denizens of the Dark World to destroy both Earth and Vecanti. Against this common foe, Yuko Asou finds help in her new girlfriend, a Vecanti warrior-maiden named Cham, who was born in the Dark World and uses a deadly whip, and her own sister Valna Asou, who grew up within Vecanti and became strong in the ways of magic. Furthermore, the Valis sword is shown to be capable of more than what Yuko has accomplished with it thus far.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Valis 3 (NTSC-U) [TGXCD1024]-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <releasedate>19900907T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Laser Soft</developer>
    <publisher>Telnet Japan</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Valis IV (NTSC-J) [TJCD1017].cue</path>
    <name>Valis IV</name>
    <desc>Yuko has become the goddess of the world of Vecanti and has watched over the world in peace since the defeat of Glames. Trouble brews when the Dark World prince named Galgear begins to search for a magical ring. This ring increases his powers, but to the loss of control he could have maintained under its effects, and the gods of Vecanti recognize this and imprison Galgear inside a crystal sunk into the ocean.

Fifteen years pass, and Galgear manages to break out of his prison, kidnapping the former heroine Valna and being pursued by troops led by Cham as a result. A member of her band, named Lena Brande, requests permission to infiltrate Galgear's stronghold and free Valna.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Valis IV (NTSC-J) [TJCD1017]-image.png</image>
    <rating>0.6</rating>
    <releasedate>19910823T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Laser Soft</developer>
    <publisher>Telnet Japan</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Vasteel (NTSC-U) [WTG990801].cue</path>
    <name>Vasteel</name>
    <desc>The emperor is dead. Now begins the bloodiest chapter in the history of the Vasteel solar system! Jump right into the action as you choose to play either Faliall, the newly crowned emperor, or his brother Stefan, leader of the rebel army. In addition to a first-of-it's-kind on-line guide that actually speaks to aid you in your weapon's choice, there are over 70 types of armored robots and transports to lead you to victory. Set up the battles on the overhead strategy map, then go in and duke out the actual fight arcade style! Vasteel also offers the option of a 2 play VS mode where you can match wits and arcade skill with a friend (TurboTap required for this option). Regardless of how you play it, the complexity and arcade action in Vasteel will transfix you!</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Vasteel (NTSC-U) [WTG990801]-image.png</image>
    <releasedate>19930502T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Human</developer>
    <publisher>Working Designs</publisher>
    <genre>Strategy</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Fire Pro Jyoshi - Shoumu Choujyo Taisen - Zenjo vs JWP (NTSC-J) [HMCD4008].cue</path>
    <name>Wrestling Universe: Fire Pro Women: Dome Super Female Big Battle: All Japan Women VS J.W.P.</name>
    <desc>The continuation of the Fire Pro series, with the official license of All Japan Women Wrestling and JPW in an all female roster. New special moves and modes are available.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Fire Pro Jyoshi - Shoumu Choujyo Taisen - Zenjo vs JWP (NTSC-J) [HMCD4008]-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19950203T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>HUMAN</developer>
    <publisher>HUMAN</publisher>
    <genre>Fighting</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Kaze No Densetsu Xanadu II (J).cue</path>
    <name>Xanadu II</name>
    <desc>Falcom has pretty much established themselves as one of the finest RPG makers in the business, and Xanadu II - an offshoot of the Legend of Heroes series shows exactly why. The sequel to the first popular Xanadu game, Xanadu II is also an action RPG. This game retains the simple Ys inspired walk-into-the-enemy attack style which works very well and also the side-on action scenes used for boss battles. Being untranslated, the story is a little hard to plot out, but you play Arios and start out aboard a ship in search of your friend, whose own ship (as shown in the intro) was attacked by dragon riders. Eventually you get blown overboard in a vicious storm and end up on a beach near the city of Razan...</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Kaze No Densetsu Xanadu II (J)-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <releasedate>19950616T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Falcom</developer>
    <publisher>Falcom</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <players/>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Ys III - Wanderers from Ys [U][CD][TGXCD1015][Falcom][1991][PCE].cue</path>
    <name>Ys III: Wanderers from Ys</name>
    <desc>As Adol, hero of Ys Book I &amp; II, your most fearsome new adventure is about to begin! The curse of the monster Demanicus terrorizes your friend Dogi's homeland. Chaos rules as blood-thirsty creatures threaten innocent lives. Only you have the courage and strength to defeat them! Gather your fiercest swords and deadly amulet to battle these horrific creatures with a thrilling new action view. Survive the fiery depths of Alcaino. Conquer the terrifying Nekevil. But stay alert, brave Adol! The fury of Demanicus awaits your final epic struggle!</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Ys III - Wanderers from Ys [U][CD][TGXCD1015][Falcom][1991][PCE]-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19910101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Nihon Falcom</developer>
    <publisher>Hudson Soft</publisher>
    <genre>Role-Playing</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Ys IV - The Dawn of Ys [TRANSLATED][J][SCD].cue</path>
    <name>Ys IV: The Dawn of Ys</name>
    <desc>Two years after defeating Darm and bringing peace to Esteria, Adol returns to the town of Minea with his companion in adventure, Dogi. Everything seems fine as friends are reunited and the people hail their hero, but there&amp;#x2019;s an unseen evil looming in the air. As Adol goes to the seer Sara, she tells him of an even greater darkness in the land of Celceta and asks the red-haired swordsman to go there and seek the truth behind this mystery. Thus, Adol steals away unnoticed in the middle of the night to embark on his next adventure.

In Celceta, Adol will learn of the Romun Empire&amp;#x2019;s ambitions, fight the mysterious Clan of Darkness that seeks to ressurect their long dead leader, and discover the ancient history of Celceta itself as well as its connection to the land of Ys. The last survivor of a forgotten race of winged beings holds the power that may bring back darkness to the land, and only Adol will be able to stop it.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Ys IV - The Dawn of Ys [TRANSLATED][J][SCD]-image.png</image>
    <releasedate>19931222T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Falcom</developer>
    <publisher>Hudson</publisher>
    <genre>Role-Playing</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Yu Yu Hakusho (1993) (Banpresto) (J).cue</path>
    <name>Y&amp;#x16B; Y&amp;#x16B; Hakusho Yamish&amp;#x14D;bu!! Ankoku Bujutsu Kai</name>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Yu Yu Hakusho (1993) (Banpresto) (J)-image.jpg</image>
    <developer/>
    <publisher/>
    <genre/>
    <players/>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Zero Wing (NTSC-J) [NXCD1003].cue</path>
    <name>Zero Wing</name>
    <desc>Horizontal shoot 'em up where you can suck in enemy craft and either use them as a shield or fire them off for extra damage.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Zero Wing (NTSC-J) [NXCD1003]-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19920918T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Toaplan</developer>
    <publisher>Naxat Soft</publisher>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <players/>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Emerald Dragon (J).cue</path>
    <name>Emerald Dragon</name>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <developer/>
    <publisher/>
    <genre/>
    <players/>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Shanghai II (Japan) (Rev 2).cue</path>
    <name>Shanghai II</name>
    <desc>Shanghai II is a variant of the puzzle game also known as solitaire mahjong. 144 mahjong tiles are arranged in rows and stacked upon each other in various patterns; the player's goal is to remove pairs of matching tiles that do not have adjacent tiles from both sides until the whole board is clear. This variant features six patterns named after animals: tiger, scorpion, monkey, snake, panther, and dragon. The player can choose to display hints or reverse any amount of moves. A mode with a time limit is available as well.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_media/tg-cd/screenshots/Shanghai II (Japan) (Rev 2).png</image>
    <marquee>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_media/tg-cd/marquees/Shanghai II (Japan) (Rev 2).png</marquee>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <developer/>
    <publisher/>
    <genre/>
    <players/>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181128T225539</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Fantasy Star Soldier [U][SCD][Inter State][prototype][PCE][squaresoft74].cue</path>
    <name>Fantasy Star Soldier (Star Parodier)</name>
    <desc>Star Parodier is a vertical scrolling shooter, much like the Star Soldier games, and features many of the same conventions, such as collecting power-ups to upgrade the player's weapons, and facing several bosses and minibosses as they progress through the game. The game also features the 2 and 5 minute high score time attack modes seen in previous games.

However, in parodying the hard sci-fi atmosphere of the Star Soldier games, Star Parodier takes a light hearted approach by featuring cute, cartoonish graphics and toning down the violence (for example, defeated enemies wave white flags in surrender). The players choose from one of three craft to play as in the game: the Paro Ceaser from Star Soldier, a giant flying Bomberman or an anthropomorphic PC Engine console that shoots HuCards and CD-ROMs at enemies.

The game was originally only released in Japan, though it was also intended to be released in North America under the name Fantasy Star Soldier.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Fantasy Star Soldier [U][SCD][Inter State][prototype][PCE][squaresoft74]-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <releasedate>19920424T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Kaneko</developer>
    <publisher>Hudson</publisher>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <players/>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Lemmings (NTSC-J) [SSCD2003].cue</path>
    <name>LEMMINGS</name>
    <desc>Lemmings is a puzzle-platformer video game originally developed by DMA Design and first published by Psygnosis for the Amiga, Atari ST and PC in 1991. The game was programmed by Mike Dailly and David Jones, and was inspired by a simple animation that Dailly created while experimenting with Deluxe Paint.

The objective of the game is to guide a group of anthropomorphised lemmings through a number of obstacles to a designated exit. To save the required number of lemmings to win, one must determine how to assign a limited number of eight different skills to specific lemmings that allow the selected lemming to alter the landscape, to affect the behaviour of other lemmings, or to clear obstacles to create a safe passage for the rest of the lemmings.

Lemmings was one of the best-received video games of the early 1990s. It was the second highest rated game in the history of Amstrad Action, and was considered the eighth greatest game of all time by Next Generation in 1996. Lemmings is also one of the most widely ported video games, and is estimated to have sold over 15 million copies between its various ports. The popularity of the game also led to the creation of several sequels, remakes and spin-offs, and has also inspired similar games.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Lemmings (NTSC-J) [SSCD2003]-image.jpg</image>
    <developer/>
    <publisher/>
    <genre>Platform</genre>
    <players/>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181129T000717</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Populous - The Promised Lands (Japan) (Rev 3).cue</path>
    <name>Populous: The Promised Lands</name>
    <desc>This Data Disk for Populous adds five new landscape types: Wild West, Silly Land, Block Land, R&amp;#xC3;&amp;#xA9;volution Fran&amp;#xC3;&amp;#xA7;aise and Bit Plains. The types can be used to create new maps in Paint Map mode and the disk also has 500 new maps for Conquest mode.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_media/tg-cd/screenshots/Populous - The Promised Lands (Japan) (Rev 3).png</image>
    <marquee>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_media/tg-cd/marquees/Populous - The Promised Lands (Japan) (Rev 3).png</marquee>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <developer>Bullfrog</developer>
    <publisher>Electronic Arts</publisher>
    <genre>Strategy</genre>
    <players/>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Puyo Puyo CD Tsuu (NTSC-J) [NIPR-1001].cue</path>
    <name>Puyo Puyo Tsuu</name>
    <desc>Classic Tetris-style puzzle game where you compete against opponents by grouping together coloured blobs that drop down from the top of the screen.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Puyo Puyo CD Tsuu (NTSC-J) [NIPR-1001]-image.png</image>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <releasedate>19940422T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>NEC AVENUE / COMPILE</developer>
    <publisher/>
    <genre>Puzzle</genre>
    <players/>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181128T230033</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./RayXAnber II (J).cue</path>
    <name>Rayxanber II</name>
    <desc>Rayxanber II is an Action game, developed and published by DataWest, which was released in Japan in 1991.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/RayXAnber II (J)-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <releasedate>19910607T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>DataWest</developer>
    <publisher>DataWest</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <players/>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Monster Lair (U).cue</path>
    <name>Monster Lair</name>
    <desc>It's your wildest nightmare come true - times 10. Indescribable mutants will boggle your brain. Worse yet, you have 14 levels of mountains, oceans, incredible obstacles. But there's no turning back. You have found the Legendary Sword and Shield - and you must rid the land of these monstrocities. Power up, increase your lifeforce to survive. Go it alone or with a friend ... into the Dragon Jaw of Death!</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Monster Lair (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19890501T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Hudson</developer>
    <publisher>NEC Home Electronics</publisher>
    <genre/>
    <players>2</players>
    <playcount>4</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181201T174311</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Puyo Puyo CD (NTSC-J) [NAPR-1038].cue</path>
    <name>Puyo Puyo</name>
    <desc>Classic Tetris-style puzzle game where you compete against opponents by grouping together coloured blobs that drop down from the top of the screen.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Puyo Puyo CD (NTSC-J) [NAPR-1038]-image.png</image>
    <releasedate>19940422T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>NEC AVENUE / COMPILE</developer>
    <publisher/>
    <genre>Puzzle</genre>
    <players/>
    <playcount>2</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181201T174649</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Sherlock Holmes Consulting Detective Volume 2 (1992) (NEC Solutions) (U).cue</path>
    <name>Sherlock Holmes Consulting Detective Volume II</name>
    <desc>Sherlock Holmes: Consulting Detective Vol. II is the title of a full motion video computer game released for the Mega-CD, TurboGrafx-CD, and DOS. The game is a sequel to Sherlock Holmes: Consulting Detective and was released in 1992.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Sherlock Holmes Consulting Detective Volume 2 (1992) (NEC Solutions) (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19920101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>ICOM Simulations</developer>
    <publisher>ICOM Simulations</publisher>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181201T190533</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Strider Hiryu (J).cue</path>
    <name>Strider Hiryu</name>
    <desc>Strider, released in Japan as Strider Hiry&amp;#x16B; (&amp;#x30B9;&amp;#x30C8;&amp;#x30E9;&amp;#x30A4;&amp;#x30C0;&amp;#x30FC;&amp;#x98DB;&amp;#x7ADC;?) is a 1989 side-scrolling platform game released for the CP System arcade hardware by Capcom. It became one of Capcom's early hits before Street Fighter II, revered for its innovative gameplay and multilingual voice clips during cutscenes (presented in English, Japanese, Mandarin, Russian and Spanish). 

Strider is set in a dystopian future in the year 2048, where a mysterious dictator known as the "Grandmaster" rules over the world. Hiryu, the youngest ever Super A Ranked[2] member of a organization of high-tech ninja-like agents known as the "Striders", is alone tasked with the Grandmaster's assassination. Hiryu begins his mission by infiltrating the Grandmaster's capital at the Kazakh Soviet Socialist Republic. 

NEC Avenue produced a PC Engine version of Strider Hiryu, which was released exclusively in Japan on September 22, 1994. The PC Engine version was released as a CD-ROM&amp;#xB2; title which requires the Arcade Card expansion. The PC Engine port features an all-new desert stage that was not in the arcade version, as well as newly recorded cut-scenes, music and dialogue, with Japanese voice actor Kaneto Shiozawa as the voice of Hiryu and K&amp;#x14D;ji Totani as the Grand Master. The PC Engine version is notable for its long development process, having been planned in various formats, including the ill-fated SuperGrafx at one point</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Strider Hiryu (J)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19940922T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Capcom</developer>
    <publisher>NEC Avenue</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <players/>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181201T194841</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Valis 2 (NTSC-U) [TGXCD1006].cue</path>
    <name>Valis II</name>
    <desc>Time passes, and Vecanti is set to rule under its next emperor after Rogles, his brother Megas, who wishes to stamp out any trace of the former tyrant, to the point of murdering any supporters Rogles might have had. Furthermore, his bloodthirsty tendencies recognize Yuko and the Valis sword as viable threats to his claim of the throne, and he orders his minions to eliminate her first before she has the chance to thwart him.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Valis 2 (NTSC-U) [TGXCD1006]-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19890623T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Telnet Japan</developer>
    <publisher>NEC</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181201T191954</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Sherlock Holmes Consulting Detective (1991) (NEC Solutions) (U).cue</path>
    <name>Sherlock Holmes Consulting Detective</name>
    <desc>Match wits with Sherlock Holmes in the first live action video game ever! Now, the amazing technology of TurboGrafx-CD takes you to the streets of London to join Holmes, Watson, and a live cast of colorful characters in 3 live action video mysteries unlike anything you've ever seen! You don't merely observe the action, you direct it in your search for clues! Call on suspects, witnesses, and Homes' own street informants. Gather your facts and your wits about you and take the murderer to trial. Quickly, now...the game's afoot!

"Sherlock Holmes is a totally unique game...phenomenal...promises to be a big hit." - Electronic Gaming Monthly, April, 1991</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Sherlock Holmes Consulting Detective (1991) (NEC Solutions) (U)-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19910501T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>ICOM Simulations, Inc.</developer>
    <publisher>NEC Technologies, Inc.</publisher>
    <genre/>
    <playcount>16</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181208T062310</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Fighting Street (UJ) [REV05] [!].cue</path>
    <name>Fighting Street</name>
    <desc>Deep inside you there lurks a warrior. Let him loose! And test him against the martial arts champions of 5 nations. Grit your teeth, pump up and take after Retsu and Geki from Japan. Most worthy opponents! But watch out for the baddest - Adon and Sagat, a couple of Thai's. Mike and Joe (USA), Birdi and Eagle (UK), Lee and Gen (China) all have their own special "tricks." Be quick and strong, or be gone!</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Fighting Street (UJ) [REV05] [!]-image.png</image>
    <releasedate>19880101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Hudson</developer>
    <publisher>NEC</publisher>
    <genre>Fighting</genre>
    <players>2</players>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181208T231119</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Ys Book I &amp; II [U][CD][TGXCD1002][Falcom][1990][PCE].cue</path>
    <name>Ys Book I &amp; II</name>
    <desc>Journey through the Ancient Land of Ys, a once peaceful and prosperous country suddenly thrust deep into an empty abyss of isolation. The secret to restoring peace rests in the six books of the wise priests. 700 years have passed, and now you have a chance to unlock the mystery. Stunning graphics, intense stereo sound and profound gameplay make this a CD adventure you'll never forget ... and may never return from.</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Ys Book I &amp; II [U][CD][TGXCD1002][Falcom][1990][PCE]-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>1</rating>
    <releasedate>19890101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Nihon Falcom</developer>
    <publisher>Hudson Soft</publisher>
    <genre>Role-Playing</genre>
    <playcount>2</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181219T175236</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Castlevania Dracula X - Cycle of Blood (Akumajou Dracula X - Chi no Rondo) (NTSC-J) [KMCD3005] [T+Eng].cue</path>
    <name>Castlevania: Rondo of Blood</name>
    <desc>Count Dracula has returned and captured the young woman close to the famous vampire hunter, Richter Belmont. Will Richter be able to defeat Dracula and rescue his girlfriend in this new CD powered adventure?</desc>
    <image>/home/pi/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Castlevania Dracula X - Cycle of Blood (Akumajou Dracula X - Chi no Rondo) (NTSC-J) [KMCD3005] [T+Eng]-image.png</image>
    <rating>0.9</rating>
    <releasedate>19931029T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Konami</developer>
    <publisher>Konami</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <playcount>3</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20181228T223721</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Builder Land (NTSC-J) [MWCD2003].cue</path>
    <name>BuilderLand</name>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Builder Land (NTSC-J) [MWCD2003]-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <releasedate>19930101T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Loriciels</developer>
    <publisher>Hudson Entertainment, Inc.</publisher>
    <genre>Puzzle</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Chiki Chiki Boys (NTSC-J) [NAPR-1033].cue</path>
    <name>Chiki Chiki Boys</name>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Chiki Chiki Boys (NTSC-J) [NAPR-1033]-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <releasedate>19940715T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>NEC AVENUE</developer>
    <publisher>Capcom</publisher>
    <genre>Action, Platform</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Conan (J).cue</path>
    <name>Mirai Shounen Conan</name>
    <desc>Straightforward platform game based on famous anime director Hayao Miyazaki&amp;#x2019;s TV series.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Conan (J)-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <releasedate>19920228T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Telenet Japan</developer>
    <publisher>Telenet Japan Co., Ltd.</publisher>
    <genre>Platform</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Psychic Storm (NTSC-J) [TJCD2025].cue</path>
    <name>Psychic Storm</name>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Psychic Storm (NTSC-J) [TJCD2025]-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <releasedate>19920319T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Alfa System</developer>
    <publisher>Telenet Japan Co., Ltd., Lasersoft</publisher>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Shanghai III - Dragon's Eye (1992) (ASK Kodansha) (J).cue</path>
    <name>Shanghai III: Dragon's Eye</name>
    <desc>Standard "match tiles to remove them from the play field" mahjong game. </desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Shanghai III - Dragon's Eye (1992) (ASK Kodansha) (J)-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <releasedate>19921218T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Home Data</developer>
    <publisher>Ask Kodansha</publisher>
    <genre>Puzzle</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Where in the World Is Carmen Sandiego (Japan) (En,Ja) (Rev 3).cue</path>
    <name>Where in the World Is Carmen Sandiego?</name>
    <desc>You start out as a rookie detective whose job is to track down a crop of thieves stealing the world's most precious treasures. After each assignment briefing, you'll be given a deadline to capture the thief that stole the artifact using clues dealing with your knowledge of geography. </desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Where in the World Is Carmen Sandiego (Japan) (En,Ja) (Rev 3)-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <releasedate>19900330T000000</releasedate>
    <genre>Adventure</genre>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./World Heroes 2 (Japan) (FAAT, FABT).cue</path>
    <name>World Heroes 2</name>
    <desc>One year ago, Dr. Brown had created the World Heroes tournament in order to find out on who the strongest fighter of history is, but because of the unexpected arrival and interference of Geegus, Dr. Brown was unable to get his answer. Now Dr. Brown is prepared to hold the tournament once again, not only having to invite the eight original fighters back for a second round, but also having to bring forth six new fighters as well, each and every one of them seeking to prove themselves in being the strongest fighter of history. Dr. Brown hopes that this time around, a definite winner will truly come out of the World Heroes tournament and emerge as the strongest fighter of history, but will Geegus interfere in the tournament just like last time and if so, will he be the only threat that the fighters will have to contend with in due time?</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/World Heroes 2 (Japan) (FAAT, FABT)-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <releasedate>19940604T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>ADK</developer>
    <publisher>SNK</publisher>
    <genre>Fighting</genre>
    <players>2</players>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Xak 1 and 2 (J).cue</path>
    <name>Xak 1 &amp; 2</name>
    <rating>0</rating>
    <releasedate>19940218T000000</releasedate>
    <developer/>
    <publisher/>
    <genre/>
    <players/>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20190714T003809</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Advanced Variable Geo (NTSC-J) [GLCD4001].cue</path>
    <name>ADVANCED V.G.</name>
    <desc>The strongest young women in the country hold a tournament, which is sponsored by various restaurant chains, which in turn ask the competing girls to pose as waitresses working in said restaurants, for promotional purposes. The girls of the Jahana group who starred in the previous games return, with the new main protagonist being the young martial artist Yuka Takeuchi, who has been training in a secluded forest area before joining the competition.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Advanced Variable Geo (NTSC-J) [GLCD4001]-image.png</image>
    <releasedate>19940722T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>TGL</developer>
    <publisher>Giga</publisher>
    <genre>Fighting</genre>
    <players>2</players>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20200112T152140</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Ai Chou Aniki (NTSC-J) [NSCD5018].cue</path>
    <name>Ai Cho Aniki</name>
    <desc>Bo Emperor Conshyasu raise the Neo Builder Army to fight Idaten and Benten. However, the two fall in love and elope. This leaves Samson and Adon to fight the new threat, Su Emperor Roido!</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Ai Chou Aniki (NTSC-J) [NSCD5018]-image.png</image>
    <rating>0.5</rating>
    <releasedate>19950224T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Masaya</developer>
    <publisher>NCS</publisher>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <players>2</players>
    <playcount>1</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20200112T152546</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Bonk III - Bonk's Big Adventure [U][SCD][TGXCD1052][Red][1993][PCE][thx-1138-darkwater].cue</path>
    <name>Bonk 3: Bonk's Big Adventure</name>
    <desc>Aaagh! What's that Evil King drool doing back in the Dinosaur Kingdom?! Didn't Bonk get rid of him last time? Guess not, huh? Now it's up to our skull-splitting, head-butting, rock-smashing, monster-bashing prehistoric hero Bonk to put an end to Drool's dastardly deeds once and for all! Watch Bonk grown into huge fire-breathing Bonk or shrink into the Mini-Size Bonk and take on tons of cool new enemies like RocketMan, Robo Turtle and Crazy Lady. Or how about smashing up a few Booga Boogas or Snippies along the way. It's the ultimate bash-o-rama!</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Bonk III - Bonk's Big Adventure [U][SCD][TGXCD1052][Red][1993][PCE][thx-1138-darkwater]-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19941201T000000</releasedate>
    <developer/>
    <publisher/>
    <genre>Platform</genre>
    <players>2</players>
    <playcount>2</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20200112T154222</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Ane-San (NTSC-J) [NAPR-1045].cue</path>
    <name>Ane-san</name>
    <desc>The two sisters, Ai and Yuuko, have taken different paths in life. Yuuko has been taken away by a mysterious gang. Ai is determined to save her from the clutches of crime. In a seemingly all-female city overrun by insane workers, biker gangs, and assorted criminals, Ai and her friends Chika and Makoto decide to work together in order to restore the world to normality again.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Ane-San (NTSC-J) [NAPR-1045]-image.png</image>
    <releasedate>19950224T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>NEC AVENUE</developer>
    <publisher>NEC AVENUE</publisher>
    <genre>Action</genre>
    <playcount>2</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20200515T182406</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Altered Beast (Juuouki) (J) (HA10109).cue</path>
    <name>Altered Beast</name>
    <desc>Altered Beast is a side scrolling beat 'em up game with light platform elements. The player can punch, kick and jump. Up to two players can play at once. Each player controls a centurion, fighting undead creatures and monsters in a setting resembling Ancient Greece, with originally five levels, in a graveyard, the Underworld, a cavern, Neff's palace and base at the city of Dis. One of the enemies, a white two-headed wolf (blue in the Mega Drive version, and a blue ox in the DOS version) upon defeat releases a Spirit Ball, a power-up orb which increase the strength and size of the player character. Three orbs turn the centurion into a beast, which in the original version were a werewolf, a thunder weredragon, a werebear, a weretiger, and the more powerful golden werewolf. Each beast has its own abilities, such as the dragon's flight and lightning, and the bear's petrification.

After becoming the beast, the character can face the end-level boss, though the boss will also appear regardless of whether or not the character is transformed if the player takes too long to complete the level. Upon the boss's defeat, Neff appears and removes the transformation orbs.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Altered Beast (Juuouki) (J) (HA10109)-image.jpg</image>
    <rating>0.8</rating>
    <releasedate>19890928T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Sega</developer>
    <publisher/>
    <genre>Fighting</genre>
    <players>2</players>
    <playcount>11</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20200515T231638</lastplayed>
  </game>
  <game>
    <path>./Gate of Thunder 3-in-1 [U][SCD][TGXCD1026][Red][1992][PCE].cue</path>
    <name>Gate of Thunder</name>
    <desc>Aries was a peaceful and calm planet for millennia; however, it is now faced with its worst crisis. The deadly army of Obellon fighters led by General Don Jingi, the evil merchant known to do anything for personal gain, is out to steal the &amp;#x201C;Starlight,&amp;#x201D; a powerful source of energy that could destroy the universe if misused. You must properly guide the &amp;#x201C;Hunting Dog&amp;#x201D; fighter-plane along with Hawk and Esty (special undercover agents protecting the Galaxy) to destroy Obellon before they destroy the world. 

You are the last resort of our planet.</desc>
    <image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/tg-cd/Gate of Thunder 3-in-1 [U][SCD][TGXCD1026][Red][1992][PCE]-image.jpg</image>
    <releasedate>19920221T000000</releasedate>
    <developer>Hudson Soft, Red Entertainment</developer>
    <publisher>Hudson Soft</publisher>
    <genre>Shooter</genre>
    <playcount>9</playcount>
    <lastplayed>20200516T205331</lastplayed>
  </game>
</gameList>
